<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4w10372q/">carre219.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Carrel (Alexis) scrapbook</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Alexis Carrel Scrapbook <num>Biomed.0219</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by UCLA Biomedical Library staff, 2011.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2011.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-01 16:13:37 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English. </langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Alexis Carrel Scrapbook</unittitle>
    <unitid>Biomed.0219</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1908/1919" type="inclusive">1908-1919</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_199781014bdb562b1ed74e9c81cb2bce" label="Abstract">This collection relating to the French/American surgeon Alexis Carrel (1873-1944) contains materials which had been mounted or loosely inserted into a scrapbook. Most of the items are newspaper clippings, plus some manuscript letters and ephemera. Dr. Carrel, whose research in vascular suturing and the transplantation of blood vessels and organs in animals won him the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1912, also won him the enmity of anti-vivisectionists; a few of the letters and articles express their viewpoint vividly. As a French Army surgeon during the 1914-1919 war Dr. Carrel collaborated on important advances in the antisepsis of wound treatment. His work with tissue culture also contributed significantly to the understanding of viruses and the preparation of vaccines.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_7d0f6b41fbb17aa1110f2d04405627e0">Held at UCLA Library Special Collections. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_c117529227d2a3158776efd70372376b">Materials are in English and French.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_53ccc0b97afd0de3095a91fddf5c8263">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_bed0add5e67b91cb56b725b491e40990">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1096221d0e1d64f744782cabbce47a2d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Alexis Carrel Scrapbook (Collection 219). Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library History and Special Collections for the Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <odd id="aspace_693be036526713d109b08a53eb73d8c9">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9962672743606533">9962672743606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9c9660db635e12d4fb2ff909374e7082">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The scrapbook was purchased from Scientia, 2009.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_54add012d968930561861fa44d841f55">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Dr. Alexis Carrel (1873-1944) was a complicated, multi-faceted individual. Here are some descriptors retrieved on a Google search of his name: surgeon, biologist, sociologist, Nobel laureate, vivisectionist, eugenicist, Nazi sympathizer, genius, innovator, believer in miracles, ideologist.</p><p>Carrel was born and educated in Lyon, France, and received his medical degree from the University of Lyon in 1900. In 1904 he went to the University of Chicago, then moved to the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research in New York in 1906; he was affiliated with that institution until his retirement in 1939. His vacations were spent in France, and he maintained his French citizenship. During the 1914-1918 war he served as a military surgeon in the French Army. He died in Paris in 1944.</p><p>An exceptionally gifted surgeon, Carrel, from early in his career focused his research on devising innovative techniques for vascular suture and the transplantation of blood vessels and organs. It was this work which earned him the 1912 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine. During his years as an army surgeon he utilized a chlorine-based solution, originated by the English chemist Henry Drysdale Dakin, to minimize infection. For this major advance in the treatment of traumatic wounds Carrel was awarded the Légion d'honneur. His experiments also laid the groundwork for future developments in several related fields: his work with tissue culture contributed significantly to the understanding of viruses and the preparation of vaccines; and in the development of medical devices, the special sterilizing glass pump he and Charles A. Lindberg designed that could keep animal organs alive for several days or weeks was a significant trail blazer for the field.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_75e16a0babd4b1d5cc0c64ac6a07d607">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection includes ten leaves from a loose-leaf scrapbook which are covered with numerous clippings from English- and French-language newspapers, all dealing with the surgical work of Dr. Alexis Carrel. Also included are numerous items places loosely between the album pages: additional newspaper and magazine articles, six letters addressed to Dr. Carrel, and one unidentified snapshot of a young man. A copy of "Time" magazine (v. 26, no. 12, 16 Sep 1935), bearing a portrait of Carrel on its cover, has been added by the processing staff.</p><p>The letters divide four to two in attacking Dr. Carrel for vivisection, versus asking for help in medical problems through his newly perfected surgical methods. The newspaper articles invert that percentage, with approximately two thirds of the reports agog about the surgical marvels he was performing, and a third or less writing about individuals or groups decrying his work as cruel, against God's will, or unnecessary.</p><p>The majority of clippings are without identification of publication, place, or year.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_721cc69cc26362ae94077b310c073398">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>Processed by UCLA Biomedical Library staff.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_9qd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook leaves.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1908-1919</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2c8396d1dd7fd2b05ded5d20edbc9226" label="General Physical Description note">10 leaves</physdesc><container id="aspace_574ace3b93fa4914d66236b37fae6093" label="Mixed Materials" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e335a6406ec69bdde02b7b097452a880"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>numerous newspaper clippings glued to one or both sides of the leaves, taken from English- and French-language publications</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_74caef724135941364505b201da83feb"><head>General note</head><p>a minority of the reports deal with antivisection attacks and activities directed against Dr.Carrel and his work; the majority either consist of neutral reporting or are overtly admiring</p></odd></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_ghd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional newspaper and magazine stories.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1910-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_0bbfa70558ec018e4770bed11687eb1c" label="Mixed Materials" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_47b9b304eab504fa9f61f229478d5a76"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>more extensive newspaper stories in English and French, two of which focus partly on Mme. Carrel; an article from "The Oulook" by Earl Mayo, "Big battles against disease: the advance in surgery"</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_ve7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Autograph letters.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_78469e59d933346964be035d32e8a315" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf0530b77df50fce8bfccf20aeed0913"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>not all letters bear a time or place of origin; four are dated 1910, and come from Ohio, New York, Chicago, and Philadelphia</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_rtp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous items.</unittitle><container id="aspace_2f9ff840ce2d3313bcae8967d9e31760" label="Mixed Materials" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88d544884bfea1f5207f25792eeebcdf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>snapshot; Liberty Bonds flyer; envelope</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_5w6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Time: the weekly newsmagazine".</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1935 September 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_acb45c0aa6b1f0a8f4565a55a95ddc5a" label="Mixed Materials" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b62e6338f70d3836c0a247c1d808dbc2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>cover portrait of Dr. Alexis Carrel, and story in "Medicine" section</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
