<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1j49r627/">kanaar.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kanaar, M.D. (Adrian C.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Adrian C. Kanaar M.D. papers <num>Biomed.0106</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by UCLA Biomedical Library staff, 2011.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2011</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-06 10:49:24 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English. </langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Adrian C. Kanaar, M.D. papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Kanaar, Adrian Charles</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>Biomed.0106</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(2 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/2001" type="inclusive">1940-2001</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f611da77d187d51fc1d5b4b0580d0d32" label="Abstract">Dr. Kanaar was a British-born and -trained surgeon who served in the Royal Army Medical Corps during World War II, in France and Belgium up to the retreat at Dunkirk, in various battlefield locations after D-day, and in Berlin during the occupation. This collection focuses mostly on his non-medical writings, namely descriptions of his war experiences in Europe and of the conditions he observed there. Included are several typescripts of two unpublished books: 1. "War-time reflections by a British Army surgeon", which was based partly on a series of talks given by Capt. Kanaar during three months spent in the United States while on special leave; 2. "The Sign of the Hammer and Sickle " which is also partly based on wartime experiences; 3. typescripts of a number of published and unpublished essays, articles, and letters to newspapers. The bulk of the collection dates to 1940-1948.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b1e6e750faa52beaf85b0723acbc3317">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_5bec81b16e02b597c548e06ffa8fbd4a">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_098a63c7c4182e98e56c4432b25c58bf">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2cede2fd2595364989375598d737b9e5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_354ae527913e04e994b0233bd3eca31b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Adrian C. Kanaar, M.D. papers (Collection 106). Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library History and Special Collections for the Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_31f85aaab67df3f4015e7581336cb07c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by UCLA Biomedical Library staff.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_6053d1cc5a111e9ebb6e0417ba6141ca">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9966614103606533">9966614103606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c5a4a530a6d70b0ea039af2ddbe70273">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The collection was a gift from Dr. Margaret H. Jones-Kanaar to the UCLA Biomedical Library.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4b37c17d576c4e2f43b07859074dd42c">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Adrian C. Kanaar, MD, MRCP (London), FRCS (Edinburgh) (1911-1993) qualified M.B. at St. Bartholomew's Hospital, London, in 1934, received a B.S. from London University in 1936, had surgical training at Edinburgh University, and was awarded the M.D. from the British Postgraduate Medical School in 1939. That year he was called to active service with the Royal Army Medical Corps and was active in France and Belgium through the retreat at Dunkirk; he returned to the Continent after D-Day and served in various stations, including occupied Berlin. On special leave in 1942 in the U.S., Captain Kanaar began a series of talks about his war experiences, wanting to foster Anglo-American cooperation and to clear up what he felt were misconceptions about the war and about the British. These talks evolved into some of the manuscript chapters included in this collection. His experiences in Germany after the war's end, and especially his impressions of the administration in the Russian zone, are described in the second major manuscript in this collection, and in many of the shorter pieces.</p><p>In 1948 Dr. Kanaar had the honor of presenting a Hunterian lecture to the Royal College of Surgeons of England. Shortly thereafter he and his wife and son emigrated to Eastern Canada where he practiced orthopedic surgery and physical medicine. In 1959 he moved to Buffalo, NY, to become Director of Physical Medicine, Department of Public Health, and Associate Professor at the University of Buffalo Medical School. In 1964, the year he became a US citizen, the family moved to Poughkeepsie, NY, where he maintained a private practice in physical medicine and rehabilitation until his retirement in 1984. He was active in and cited for community leadership in physical fitness, and was a member of the American College of Sports Medicine. He published widely in the fields of rehabilitation and fitness, and practiced what he preached: as a young man he made two attempts to swim the English Channel, coming within a mile and a half of his goal; at age 74, he swam the 28.5 miles around New York City's Manhattan Island. He stated that the Channel swims were motivated by the wish to demonstrate that a dedicated Christian could also be an athlete and a strong individual.</p><p>After the death of his wife of 47 years, Dr. Kanaar retired and moved to Pacific Palisades, California. There he met and married Margaret H. [Holden] Jones, MD in 1989.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3a0cfe836938517a84fcd02d01ab99a5">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection focuses mainly on Dr. Kanaar's non-medical writings for 1940-1948, namely accounts of his experiences and observations in Europe during World War II and the subsequent occupation of Germany. There are various typescripts of two unpublished works, "United we stand: war-time reflections of a British Army surgeon", covering his service from the war's beginning through the evacuation from Dunkirk; and "The sign of the Hammer and Sickle", focusing more on the time of the occupation. Also included are a number of published and unpublished commentaries, letters to newspapers, and articles by Kanaar.</p><p>The collection is organized into the following series:<list><item>Series 1. Professional Activities. 3 folders</item><item>Series 2. Personal Beliefs and Accounts. 12 folders</item><item>Series 4. Personal Information. 4 folders</item></list> </p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="mesh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, English.</subject>
    <subject source="mesh">Physicians -- Personal narratives.</subject>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Jones, Margaret Holden</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Kanaar, Adrian Charles -- Manuscripts</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_cls" level="series"><did><unittitle>Professional Activities</unittitle><unitid>Series 1.</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent></physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c64d13268ca668a6437a025765907010"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>materials pertaining to a Hunterian Lecture delivered to the Royal College of Surgeons</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref13_gol" level="file"><did><unittitle>Application for Hunterian Professorship.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_b962f36622d11332465220f1ced728e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c2cda91769035b2f649dba90500c00b4" parent="aspace_b962f36622d11332465220f1ced728e8" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6bbace2c24b9b1b3c2e482fd720f538e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>original application letter and a follow-up note, both signed by Dr. Kanaar; photocopy of précis for lecture on "Pulmonary atelectasis in general surgery, with special reference to aetiology"</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref15_h1i" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Pulmonary atelectasis in postoperative and traumatic cases: some recent advances", Hunterian Lecture delivered to the Royal College of Surgeons of England by A. C. Kanaar.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1948</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2eb083ffc67015d244341794e23416b5" label="General Physical Description note">23 l. plus illustrations and tables</physdesc><container id="aspace_75ac426b14054d3226bad7093982c218" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4dc07c33a43ab9ceed0b1ee9220078ac" parent="aspace_75ac426b14054d3226bad7093982c218" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff2942a7656c005661ee9268b99580b9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>a short "Introduction/Abstract" to the paper by Margaret H. Jones-Kanaar, MD, written after her husband's death; text and illustrations of the lecture; letter from "The Annals of the Royal College of Surgeons of England" regretting inability to publish the lecture because of its length, and suggesting submission to a different journal</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref18_4pr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Early versions of the atelectasis study.</unittitle><container id="aspace_0a64a69a19867ba7cd41c5e776bddb56" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a7cf0c38d078151cf6dcbfcccbeb86e1" parent="aspace_0a64a69a19867ba7cd41c5e776bddb56" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b1c0cf0efd31a5f055e4d7606ca101a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>text and data drafts, lecture notes, case notes</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_2376c5dae65e94e41a9adb68ecc5364d"><head>General note</head><p>mostly undated; some case notes dated 1948</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref22_b21" level="series"><did><unittitle>Personal Beliefs and Accounts</unittitle><unitid>Series 2.</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 folders</extent></physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d7992d0e7d636670de700794a2e2ad28"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>writings and related materials on: World War II; Russian occupation in Germany and Poland; Communism; Religion</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref24_ady" level="file"><did><unittitle>"War-time reflections by a British Army surgeon", by Capt. A. C. Kanaar, MD, MRCP (London), FRCS (Edin).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1940</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2809d4b14c1c17d65c287040c3e47b57" label="General Physical Description note">92 l.</physdesc><container id="aspace_a284f4b3a9659a7f97059af857511976" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cc3fa794b45fe338f7439bdcf70b399c" parent="aspace_a284f4b3a9659a7f97059af857511976" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_860cfeba568abd9558c6bb1425143fc8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>quoting from the cover page: "This narrative of one man's early World War II experiences evolved from a series of talks given by Capt. Kanaar during three months spent in America while on special leave because of his wife' illness"; typed copy</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref27_7vr" level="file"><did><unittitle>"United we stand: war-time reflections of a British Army surgeon".</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1943</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0deb178ad2a11ff82b90b724e5a06389" label="General Physical Description note">ca. 73,600 words</physdesc><container id="aspace_036629aa45f35da33c2d67b277524009" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a21e37a63832232c397108cca5b62e80" parent="aspace_036629aa45f35da33c2d67b277524009" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_908e36f93e231364e0a15e03128b2755"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>typed draft of a projected book, incorporating Capt. Kanaar's experiences in France up to and through the evacuation of the British Army at Dunkirk (see Folder 4, above) as Part I; Britain during the war (Part II); Looking ahead (Part III)</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_476766206f4213dd94e6ff93a2a129fe"><head>General note</head><p>missing from this manuscript: Part II, chapters 2-4, 8; Part III, chapters 2, 3, 5-9</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref31_mmz" level="file"><did><unittitle>"United we stand: war-time reflections of a British Army surgeon".</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc02fd74599b63a64c0859bb140e2042" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a852ea525ef1c61e40df8c37a70e49e7" parent="aspace_cc02fd74599b63a64c0859bb140e2042" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fd6455b10123b8b366df53c1035fc172"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>photocopy of the typescript above</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref33_9tm" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Sign of the Hammer and Sickle", by A. C. Kanaar.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf2a6278e2617c4741c6613f911e6295" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6dcae8a362343f0780ccaf2af139e025" parent="aspace_cf2a6278e2617c4741c6613f911e6295" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7edeb0d66e55d1ed934b34e5729617f8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>partial typescript of an expanded version of "United we stand"; included are: Preface; Table of contents; Précis of chapters; Chapters 3-6, 8-19</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_ca16e60048b76111debcad113b609a2c"><head>General note</head><p>the paper is in fragile condition, with tears, worn edges, rust stains</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref36_aew" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Sign of the Hammer and Sickle", by A. C. Kanaar.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_21d6dfbd1fe9f8c347f54f33f78165ca" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_96813de7d0c43e9b28e1fd8272e5e967" parent="aspace_21d6dfbd1fe9f8c347f54f33f78165ca" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed6ecb871a4310807999a088b94d3ecf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>photocopy of the typescript above</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_c43fef8cf0ccc3cd3baffbc114d12c79"><head>General note</head><p>these pages are easier to handle and read</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref39_jhy" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Sign of the Hammer and Sickle", by A. C. Kanaar.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_68f6c605e1c08ef51a560b367d3b76b8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_90f369b917b12ec68528a78d85d7822b" parent="aspace_68f6c605e1c08ef51a560b367d3b76b8" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6b1abf951b751769b3a6bbc8d2284a7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>the most complete version of the projected book, missing only the Foreword promised by Lord Bertrand Russell; included are: Table of Contents; Illustrations, Maps and Cartoons; Preface; Précis of chapters; 19 chapters</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref41_l3v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alleged Russian misconduct in occupied Germany.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1945-1946</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_07de8ddfb50f1b7eaf411b0e84e4dc29" label="General Physical Description note">original and photocopy for each item</physdesc><container id="aspace_1deb5635b8a5bfa6f4f3674c8bbcbf23" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_cdf1f418df24b75b14c0887c21160526" parent="aspace_1deb5635b8a5bfa6f4f3674c8bbcbf23" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2403a8d09dc8d33ed5785643428a360e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>manuscript letter from Bertrand Russell to Kanaar; short typed letter from A. C. Russell, Ingham Infirmary, South Shields, to Kanaar; clipping from the weekly periodical "Forward", Glasgow, Dec. 15, 1945, titled "What is happening in Germany? A Scots soldier replies to Bertrand Russell", by Tim Christie; correspondence with the editor of "Forward", and Kanaar's rebuttal to Christie, titled "More about Germany"</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_22610e6af1814c0413b508444492c079"><head>General note</head><p>Christie questioned the assertions of Russian misconduct made by Russell in his article "The German Disaster", published in "Forward", Nov. 17, 1945, assertions which Kanaar believed to be true</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref45_3ro" level="file"><did><unittitle>List of articles by A. C. Kanaar published in 1945-1947.</unittitle><container id="aspace_bba611fb9a5d46a537e5e3d1ade8b33d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_1c72f40089d08822b22725a53b4536fe" parent="aspace_bba611fb9a5d46a537e5e3d1ade8b33d" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_87d83d2972868a983e8c7751f5f9ed40"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>the list provides dates and names of newspapers/magazines, and the following titles: "Report on Germany"; "The trail of the beast in Holland"; "What I saw in Germany"; "Land reform in Germany"; "The spectre behind the Iron Curtain"; "Why doctors said 'no' to Mr. Bevan"; "What the doctors want"; "The doctors and the State"; "What does Mr. Bevan want?"</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref47_p82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unpublished commentaries/articles by Kanaar.</unittitle><container id="aspace_463fee65415f260df5d48331cc7213bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f98db5eeb4a9c5e3733fbe9c569eba40" parent="aspace_463fee65415f260df5d48331cc7213bc" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de46ec6b2dc0cfc4c44cb6f8e747c7c2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>originals and photocopies of the following items: "Escape to freedom"; "Genocide continues, despite Nuremberg"; "Agrarreform et alia"; "The lake in the wood"; "Denazification of a whole community" [a number of separate observations and comments]</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_b39c0423459e26fc23667e588239b9bb"><head>General note</head><p>the focus of all the items is on behavior of Russian troops and administrators in occupied areas of Germany and Poland post World War II</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref50_p1n" level="file"><did><unittitle>Communism.</unittitle><container id="aspace_accce774eb57ae9004838c94d08075cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_d79869682353ba7f01f12c505f417b6a" parent="aspace_accce774eb57ae9004838c94d08075cc" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d0cf252bab67979d723037aa34eb23bf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>typed "Selected bibliography on Communism" [by D. Fetler?], listing items 1935-1962; two sets of manuscript notes, one headed "Communism, peaceful co-existence", the other "Communism past and present, lecture to ???, 1979"</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref52_ura" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous newspaper/magazine clippings on communism and the cold war.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1948-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fe93b0c1070a8b7b1fded3cc308b042" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c981258ea1ada063467caba870823fa4" parent="aspace_5fe93b0c1070a8b7b1fded3cc308b042" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6927a93b5019b2ef9fd7d036f508330f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>items taken from both British and American publications</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref54_ws8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A physicians faith", by Adrian C. Kanaar.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1987 June 21</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ee17081b26714dd160d4965f7c9fc1fa" label="General Physical Description note">7 l.</physdesc><container id="aspace_1529c3583d1f04ca0ea316020de3f863" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_5586aa1e0362c4cfad83c198910e8bb8" parent="aspace_1529c3583d1f04ca0ea316020de3f863" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3fa6168ad3814bea30a58cb6bd2e8633"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>typescript, edited from a talk given at the Baptist Church, Poughkeepsie, New York</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref58_zjh" level="series"><did><unittitle>Personal Information</unittitle><unitid>Series 4.</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent></physdesc></did><c02 id="aspace_ref60_8lx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photograph.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_b187b52a8fd68d9ab353e26d3f157d67" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_910283ac5d83503d616ae21a40cc8462" parent="aspace_b187b52a8fd68d9ab353e26d3f157d67" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_092585ef1d00d7f5b9c97a3bb3daf9fe"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>3x4" portrait of Dr. Kanaar</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref62_8wj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biographical materials.</unittitle><container id="aspace_430a20a40fee66afe2e00fba305cd7c7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_dcd3044db4c8f45d35e2d556e2907244" parent="aspace_430a20a40fee66afe2e00fba305cd7c7" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de570aae47ab874eb021445c85fe695e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>selective list of "Personal particulars", 1911-1947; curriculum vitae, Nov. 1976 (updated to June 1986)</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref64_0fi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Obituary and memorial letter.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ff2f58c7e494feb2abff94f0c177fde" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b071d516a7c064f0b83b968dfc2ec5ca" parent="aspace_7ff2f58c7e494feb2abff94f0c177fde" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf6544cfebd91f807a8d4767792cca50"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>one-page typed obituary; Christmas letter to Dear Family and Friends, signed Margaret, with snapshots of the Drs. Kanaar and Jones-Kanaar together, and Dr. Kanaar alone</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref66_x4i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Margaret Holden Jones-Kanaar, MD, 1904–2001.</unittitle><container id="aspace_41b84e57c4aa2cf90d5bb84168755f98" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_8372838ea5c06fef61e78fb8a34a90ba" parent="aspace_41b84e57c4aa2cf90d5bb84168755f98" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fc9483a1defa63f628c3edb85bf7574a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>manuscript letter from Dr. Kanaar's second wife, covering transmittal of additional Kanaar material to the UCLA Biomedical Library, 21 Sep 1994; clipping of Dr. Jones-Kanaar's obituary from the "Los Angeles Times", 12 Dec 2001</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_2f890c4dae6cc029777d7c0cdca1a960"><head>General note</head><p>Dr. Margaret Jones-Kanaar was a retired UCLA pediatrician and renowned pioneer in the treatment of cerebral palsy</p></odd></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
