<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8qf90bd/">alfi0592.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Alfin-Slater (Roslyn) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Roslyn Alfin-Slater Papers <num>LSC.0592</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Angel Diaz, 2018.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 14 June 2018.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-12-07 12:22:49 -0800</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Roslyn Alfin-Slater papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.0592</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.4 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(16 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/2000" type="inclusive">1946-2000</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a5ced96f4de2e113026c1671aab68742">Roslyn B. Alfin-Slater (1916-2002) was faculty in the UCLA Department of Public Health and known in the field for her common-sense approach to diet and nutrition. The papers include correspondence, research notes, administrative materials from the UCLA Department of Public Health, drafts and final copies of manuscripts, and grant proposals and documentation. This collection also includes research correspondence, collected materials and publications related to Alfin-Slater's research on the effects of dietary intake of cholesterol, with a focus on avocado and palm oils.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_aea040b2d3e6182abd3fa3192ec4fbab">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_89f4267354d8b0d7567cbdd345f2082f">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dc0cefb15f3789cade7f31931df1723e">
    <head>Conditions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b4c086a35576a27faeaf8abc94204fc5">
    <head>Conditions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1a52360ee870bf87a551d91f1a078e33">
    <head>Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Roslyn Alfin-Slater and Grant Slater, 2002.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bc675561cf7339d55eae5f2281ca6ddf">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Roslyn Alfin-Slater papers (Collection 592). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5b5b3262daa71ed0e05dffdb574807f6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Angel Diaz, 2018.</p><p>This collection was processed at the box level. </p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_28bc0c6fb5f1d64106b80e10ad614723">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9947696293606533">9947696293606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b8fc24ecb281785b6dc24756fd2ab253">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Roslyn B. Alfin-Slater was faculty in the UCLA Department of Public Health and known for her common-sense approach to diet and nutrition. She was born in Brooklyn, New York in 1916 and received a BA from Brooklyn College (1936), and a MS in chemistry (1942) and PhD in biochemistry (1946) from Columbia University. Following appointments at the Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research and the Department of Biochemistry and Nutrition at the University of Southern California, Alfin-Slater joined the faculty of UCLA's School of Public Health in 1959 and helped found its program in Public Health Nutrition.</p><p>Alfin-Slater was one of the first scientists to examine how diet affected health status. She studied the relationship between cholesterol and essential fatty acid metabolism, and was among the first to question the effects of dietary intake of cholesterol on cholesterol levels in the blood. She wrote more than 200 scientific papers, co-edited the four-volume series <emph>Human Nutrition, A Comprehensive Treatise</emph> (1979-1993) and the book, <emph>Nutrition for Today</emph> (1973). Alfin-Slater also co-authored the <emph>Los Angeles Times</emph> column "Science, Food and Health" (1972-1982).</p><p>Alfin-Slater formally retired in 1987, but remained active in nutrition and the UCLA community, serving as president of the Emeriti Association from 1989-1990. Her husband, Grant Slater, was a research biological chemist at the UCLA School of Public Health. Alfin-Slater died in Los Angeles in 2002. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b042bea6d6f36ad933a6ec8cdcc4ffcd">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Roslyn Alfin-Slater papers contain materials related to the professional research of UCLA Professor of Community Health Sciences, Public Health and Biological Chemistry, Roslyn Alfin-Slater. The papers include correspondence, research notes, administrative materials from the UCLA Department of Public Health, drafts and final copies of manuscripts, and grant proposals and documentation. This collection includes research correspondence, notes, collected materials and publications related to Alfin-Slater's research on the effects of dietary intake of cholesterol, with a focus on aplm oil and avocados.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1e4a7423afbb0632e6681c7821234a2f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Materials are arranged by type.</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3fb0c09fbf31d3b507439e62a4bb32ed">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href=
"https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942303073606533">Interview of Roslyn B. Alfin-Slater [A passion for nutrition oral history transcript] / Rebecca Stone, interviewer.</extref> UCLA Library Special Collections, Center for Oral History interview, 1994-1995. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh91002896" source="lcsh">Women nutritionists -- United States -- Archives</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85010549" source="lcsh">Avocado</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85097227" source="lcsh">Palm oil</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79058494" source="naf">University of California, Los Angeles. School of Public Health. Faculty -- Archives</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_506e864f24d08ad4608e81a127add213" level="series"><did><unittitle>Biographical and professional work</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/2000" type="inclusive">1970-2000</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_5516afebb9a75a1cbcf8a38efa5b3bed" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_a073284d6865f151168cecf0c7a8fadd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_27ffeb5a88736ab8d8a80984c5b95a7e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8923b9dd0b5e6e8c5485b8d293983456"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Boxes include biographical materials, including curricula vitae, bibliographies, and faculty promotion materials; administrative materials, memos, and agendas from the UCLA Department of Public Health; and materials related to the Emeriti Association, of which Alfin-Slater served as president from 1989-1990. Also includes materials related to Alfin-Slaters advisory role with the American Council on Science and Health.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_65704ba526a3c34243ac0b37a028d1b8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1998" type="inclusive">1955-1998</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_48737058b7178a28e2682fe39bf8891e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_1ea6f6fa5f55fd539e1e8444bb14ab88" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ab62bd3f501752f78f092424425a603"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondence between Alfin-Slater and colleagues at UCLA, mentors, fellow researchers, publishers, government officials, food industry leaders, and other agencies. Topics related to Alfin-Slater's research and manuscripts, conferences and other speaking events, consulting, and committee work.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9645b2180dd694190c9bb9b0843d3854" level="series"><did><unittitle>Research: Palm oil</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/1994" type="inclusive">1987-1994</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_f4cd641eda319fc510df330f314c3804" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_9b279d3aaab150160d5b5b2b355b6f59" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_55f403e1b6a965292e0fefcd99c3729b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc8980743c3da9157835d016b9e60c67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from Alfin-Slater's research on the health impacts of palm oil intake, including correspondence, research grant proposals, reports and manuscripts, conference and meeting documents, and collected research materials. Alfin-Slater served on multiple committees related to palm oil research, including the Palm Oil Research Institute of Malaysia and the US Nutrition Advisory Committee of Palm Oil.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d90b77dfb4a09a394ff2b345667c0555" level="series"><did><unittitle>Research: Avocados </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1995" type="inclusive">1954-1995</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_c8dce14d884f1f3fe21d8c285d9b2c6e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_a2e6d062980bc28e503ec7a0f98e8781" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_85611387e4ce16c36e277ea19233163c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_33f696da0671a1b7f78480d2ff73c852"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from Alfin-Slater's research on the health impacts of avocado consumption, particularly on cholesterol. Materials include correspondence, research proposals, reports and manuscripts, conference and meeting documents, and collected research materials. Alfin-Slater served as a scientific member of the California Avocado Commission, and its predecessor the California Avocado Advisory Board, attending committee meetings and reviewing informational and promotional materials.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3e20601bc7d2a726961feb4921b6a87d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Research: Health topics</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1995" type="inclusive">1955-1995</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_ca837f445078b687832d50fbc7450975" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_6f0b4f5a54844deab082ea131eec9efd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_9c900d230b63c3a6258d2c76f01810c4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_c50f4f3afe277b62e72a3411a52c0ddb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bdc9ea9a4b6773b8f4fd4f1f6b3a9582"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Boxes include correspondence, clippings, notes, manuscripts drafts, and promotional materials related to a number of Alfin-Slater's research topics, including aging, cholesterol, heart disease, fat metabolism, meat, the Mediterranean Diet, nutritional mythology, pectin, sugar, raisins, vitamin E, and others. The boxes also include materials related to research grants, such as correspondence and reports.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f8ba8dc2a586f961852ff2305b43f5cc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications and talks</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1992" type="inclusive">1946-1992</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_5f361cbf40ca3a393cc902a78cdc5544" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_15896a32bddb5d26ba82d4a0e955afc8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 9.5h 4w)" id="aspace_e27091fe6914b40320a1815e3b5d64c5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_902badaa1394dabab563e2699139be90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Boxes include drafts of, correspondence related to, and published papers by Alfin-Slater. She maintained a column for the <emph>Los Angeles Times</emph> with Derrick Jelliffe called "Science, Food and Health" (1972-1982). There are also lectures and talks delivered at conferences, meetings, and other events, as well as Alfin-Slater's dissertation, <emph>Further Studies of the Action of Pancreatic Amylase</emph> (1946).</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
