<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf9199p2v5/">bella917.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Bell (Alphonzo E.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Alphonzo Edward Bell Papers <num>LSC.0917</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by UCLA Library Special Collections staff; machine-readable finding aid created by Myra Villamor and Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2002.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject source="cdl"></subject><subject source="cdl"></subject><subject source="cdl"></subject><subject source="cdl"></subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-31 15:45:40 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Alphonzo Edward Bell papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Bell, Alphonzo Edward</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.0917</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 unknown</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box and 1 oversize box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/1947" type="inclusive">1900-1947</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0b25af22daf8479b46064199043ea595" label="Abstract">Alphonzo Bell (1875-1947) was born in Los Angeles, California. He was a farmer, land developer and subdivider near Santa Fe Springs. He developed the residential subdivision, Bel Air, in West Los Angeles and owned substantial developments of crude oil in the Santa Maria Valley. The collection consists of letters, ephemera, and photographs relating to his career and life.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_e355a6598e4399b913a0fa1363a212e2">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f74c8011bf2660c0398a2e86f854792c">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_af048dc2d9c97546329e4a0fead63c55">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fe3ab7e36ed983f4fef7ebedd603420a">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_07af24482891ac0347b5c6a060063fab">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Alphonzo Edward Bell Papers (Collection 917). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_01f321af59eaad4beb56b899212f4466">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by UCLA Library Special Collections staff.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_10ed9a7a006aa083df63993dbfc6d2f2">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma994623463606533">994623463606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1c375473f612fab8f8901efb0fd71794">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Bell was born on September 29, 1875 in Los Angeles, California; graduated from Occidental College Academy, 1891; BA, Occidental College, 1895; student, San Francisco Theological Seminary, 1895-97; became farmer, land developer and subdivider near Santa Fe Springs; oil wells were developed on some of his land; organized Alphonzo E. Bell Corporation, 1922, and developed the residential subdivision, Bel Air, in West Los Angeles; owned substantial developments of crude oil in the Santa Maria Valley; member of Occidental College board of trustees; died on December 27, 1947.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_97c33dd79762e56d73a540a3c38edbcb">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection consists of letters, ephemera, and photographs relating to the career and life of Alphonzo Bell, and the development of Bel Air, Los Angeles, California.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <odd id="aspace_4828377e3294b03b22561743345f0482">
    <head>General note</head>
<p><emph render="italic">Description derived from in-house card file.</emph></p>  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bel Air (Los Angeles, Calif.).</geogname>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Real estate developers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.</occupation>
    <persname source="naf">Bell, Alphonzo Edward, 1875-1947--Archives.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_71u" level="collection"><did><unittitle>Alphonzo Edward Bell Papers. Los Angeles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1900-1947.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e814b39abdad410ddd2bb9f13c78ff68" label="General Physical Description note">(1 box and 1 oversize box).</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dffe2027ec04ed2cf6a7ddfcee8ff971"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Letters, ephemera, and photographs relating to the career and life of Alphonzo Bell, and the development of Bel-Air.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
