<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8cv4j9q/">blinn262.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Blinn (Marjeanne J.) collection on Frances Clarke Sayers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Marjeanne Blinn Collection on Frances Clarke Sayers <num>LSC.0262</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Gloria Gonzalez with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli, July 2012; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2012.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-10-03 16:25:12 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marjeanne Blinn collection on Frances Clarke Sayers</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="local">Blinn, Marjeanne Jensen </persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.0262</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.0 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1950/1970" type="inclusive">circa 1950-1970</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2cd28c82743fc26fcf028d614567601a" label="Abstract">Marjeanne Blinn, a children's librarian and former student of Frances Clarke Sayers, worked with Sayers on an anthology of Sayers' writings, <title render="italic">Summoned by Books: Essays and Speeches by Frances Clarke Sayers</title>, published in 1964. The collection includes over sixty 3" reel tape recordings of Sayers' lectures, speeches and workshops, two vinyl albums of Sayers' storytelling, and a scrapbook that contains a typed manuscript of <title render="italic">Summoned by Books</title>, correspondence, literature review research, and other documents related to Sayers and the making of <title render="italic">Summoned by Books</title>.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_8e14e463136460191dbb462d244cd7b3">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_dc3ce0b9fce4bea82206177b9f098261">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_9fdeb389bb1669fff706541e80cb0781">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ed59a92fb5ba6ac67a7e376ce6dfed27">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_443c7dbb44c363d185c64ca752409a60">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio materials. Audio materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </phystech>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d6afa4fc43042976c73f5fbeca5115d7">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Marjeanne Blinn, 2012.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_15e36890705b1be1b48ac24e64dffc32">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Marjeanne Blinn collection on Frances Clarke Sayers (Collection 262). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9adebc2b1f51f1a252424b6506842794">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Gloria Gonzalez with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli, July 2012.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_e0dd6340f327080f46681516db028d94">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9970547363606533">9970547363606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9185421815b0e32f1a022e189c8aa185">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>Marjeanne Jensen Blinn was a 1962 graduate of the UCLA Graduate School of Library Service and later served as an assistant librarian at the UCLA University Elementary School Library. Blinn compiled and edited the anthology <title render="italic">Summoned by Books: Essays and Speeches by Frances Clarke Sayers</title>. While enrolled in the School of Library Service, which later became the Graduate School of Education and Information Studies, Blinn was a student of Frances Clarke Sayers (1897-1989) who lectured on children's literature at UCLA from 1954 to 1965. After graduation, Blinn frequently attended and recorded Sayers' lectures, workshops, and symposiums. Blinn began working very closely with Sayers on the anthology in the fall of 1963, and was granted a summer leave of absence from the University Elementary School Library to work full time on the book in 1964. <title>Summoned by Books: Essays and Speeches by Frances Clarke Sayers</title>, which includes an introduction by Dr. Lawrence Clark Powell (1906-2001), was published in 1965.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_7cfe9d2ce13913ea7a9df4bdf4be28ac">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Marjeanne Blinn collection on Frances Clarke Sayers contains 3" reel tapes, vinyl records, and scrapbook titled <title render="italic">Frances Clarke Sayers and the making of Summoned by Books</title>. The 3" reel audio recordings span from 1963 to 1982, and include a variety of Sayers' lectures from English 118: Literature for Children and Library Science 203: Work with Children. Also included are recordings of speeches, storytelling workshops, a luncheon and Sayers' retirement symposium; the vinyl records contain Sayers' storytelling and speeches. The scrapbook, compiled by Blinn, contains a typed manuscript of the book, research correspondence, and book reviews as well as obituaries and memorials written after Sayers' death in 1989.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="local">Blinn, Marjeanne Jensen </persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref4_5k9" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Summoned by Books</title> memorabilia scrapbook, and vinyl records titled <title>Frances Clarke Sayers, Storyteller</title> and <title>Summoned by Books: Speeches Delivered by Frances Clarke Sayers</title> </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1990" type="inclusive">1963-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_a845e176dd6f58c2143254cc301f8b4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref6_gst" level="file"><did><unittitle>3-inch reel audio recordings of Frances Clarke Sayers' English 118: Literature for Children lectures</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ea21448cd194f0e8f7fe120fe8088a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29eb22e55caf380996dad65eaaf9f0e9"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Lecture topics include poetry, <title>Alice in Wonderland</title> and Lewis Carroll, Fantasy, Epics, Fables, Fiction, Folktales, Mythology, Hans Christian Anderson, and the history of children's books.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref8_iqk" level="file"><did><unittitle>3-inch reel audio recordings of Frances Clarke Sayers' Library Science 203: Library Work with Children lectures, storytelling workshop, retirement symposium and speeches.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1982" type="inclusive">1965-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_29c7c236d552c012a0ca05c821563738" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6cc66ddc66a99a6962a87ec2139a397"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Storytelling workshop recordings include three stories told by Sayers, Laramee Haynes, and Richard Chase followed by a discussion of storytelling techniques. The recording of Sayers' retirement symposium includes speeches by Augusta Baker, Mae Durham, Rosemary Livsey, Ruth Hill Viguers and Laramee Haynes.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
