<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" scriptencoding="iso15924" audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft">
<eadid xmlns:cdlpath="http://www.cdlib.org/path/" countrycode="US" mainagencycode="CLU-SC" identifier="ark:/13030/kt867nf2zq" cdlpath:parent="ark:/13030/tf129008pn" cdlpath:grandparent="ark:/13030/tf8z09p95s">PUBLIC "-//University of California, Los Angeles::Library Special Collections//TEXT(US::CLU-SC::170/588::Henry Brooke 13 Weeks on the Lord Warden)//EN" "br170588.xml"</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for Henry Brooke's 13 Weeks on the Lord Warden, 1873-1874</titleproper>
<titleproper type="filing">Brooke (Henry) 13 Weeks on the Lord Warden</titleproper>
<author>Cataloged by Jonathan Naito, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, July 2004; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher>
<address>
<addressline>UCLA Library Special Collections staff</addressline>
<addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline>
<addressline>Box 951575</addressline>
<addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline>
<addressline>Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.library.ucla.edu/libraries/special/scweb/</addressline>
</address>
<date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">© 2009</date>
<p>The Regents of the University of California. All rights reserved.</p>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from database containing container list structure and data, encoding added via MS Access and Notetab Pro; Date of source: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 2004-2007;</date> frontmatter gathered MARC Record. Supplementary encoding and revision supplied by Caroline Cubé.</creation>
<langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English.</language></langusage>
<descrules>Finding aid prepared using <title linktype="simple">Describing Archives: a Content Standard</title></descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection" id="archdesc-1.2">
<did id="did-1.2.1">
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<unittitle label="Title">Henry Brooke <title>13 Weeks on the Lord Warden</title></unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1873/1874">1873-1874 </unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection number" repositorycode="CLU-SC" countrycode="US">170/588</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname rules="aacr2">Brooke, Henry</persname></origination>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>100 leaves : paper of various kinds, ill. ; 157 x 123 mm. bound to 164 x 131 mm.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract label="Abstract">This handwritten journal records the journey of the Englishman Henry Brooke from England to Australia aboard the Lord Warden. The journal is largely an account of the seafaring life, with reference to daily weather, animal sightings, and social events onboard the ship. There are 27 pen and ink illustrations, all of which relate to the material discussed in the journal.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Language">Finding aid is written in 
<language langcode="eng">English.</language>
</langmaterial>
<repository label="Repository">
<corpname>University of California, Los Angeles. Library Special Collections.</corpname>
<address><addressline>Los Angeles, California 90095-1575</addressline></address>
</repository>
<physloc label="Physical location">Stored off-site at SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</physloc>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo" id="descgrp-1.2.2">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UCLA Library Special Collections. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>
</userestrict>
<processinfo>
<head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Cataloged by Jonathan Naito, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, July 2004, in the Center For Primary Research and Training (CFPRT).</p>
</processinfo>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Henry Brooke <title>13 Weeks on the Lord Warden</title> (Collection 170/588). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.</p>
</prefercite>
<odd>
<head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p> UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref actuate="onrequest" show="new" href="http://catalog.library.ucla.edu/vwebv/holdingsInfo?bibId=4230403">4230403</extref></p>
</odd>
</descgrp>
<bioghist encodinganalog="545" id="bioghist-1.2.3">
<head>Biography</head>
<p>According to the manuscript, Brooke is English. It is unclear whether or not he settled in Australia.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="scopecontent-1.2.4">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>This handwritten journal records Brooke's journey from Gravesend, England to Melbourne, Australia aboard the Lord Warden. Composed from October 7, 1873  through February 27, 1874, the daily journal documents events and customs of life on board a ship. The journal begins with a pen and ink drawing of a woman packing Henry Brooke's trunk, and quotes from Othello and Antony and Cleopatra. It appears that Brooke began to create a title page, as the words "13 Weeks on the Lord Warden" are traced in faint pencil on leaf 4r. Brooke mentions sailing customs such as throwing a dead horse overboard, rituals involved with reaching the equator, and Christmas at sea.</p>
<p>The daily journal ends with Brooke's arrival in Melbourne in January, 1874, though he does append two pages on Melbourne and describes a journey by ship to Launceston, Tasmania. On that journey, he happens to be on the same ship as the "English Eleven" cricketers; he subsequently watches them in a cricket match with a Tasmanian team. Brooke copied the ship's log and the dimensions of the vessel into his journal; he has also transcribed two pieces by fellow passenger A. G. Guillemard (author of <title>Over Land and Sea: A Log of Travel Round the World in 1873-1874</title>): a short essay on the tropics and an account of the playing of cricket onboard the ship. The narrative ends abruptly with Brooke in Tasmania. There are 27 pen and ink illustrations, all of which relate to the material discussed in the journal.</p>
</scopecontent>
<controlaccess id="controlaccess-1.2.5">
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres and Forms of Material</head>
<genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Manuscripts.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544" id="relatedmaterial-1.2.6">
<head>Related Material</head>
<p>
<extref href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt538nb916" actuate="onrequest" show="new">Bound Manuscripts Collection (Collection 170)
</extref>. Available at the UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<dsc type="in-depth" id="dsc-1.2.7" score="2" C-ORDER="1" MAX-C-ORDER="8">
<head>Container List</head>
<note>
<p>Binding: Deteriorating brown leather binding, exposed spine.</p>
</note>
<c01 level="item" id="c01-1.2.7.3" score="1" C-ORDER="3"><did>
<unittitle>ff. 5r-57r: Daily journal of the voyage from England to Melbourne</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item" id="c01-1.2.7.4" score="1" C-ORDER="4"><did>
<unittitle>ff. 57v-63r: Transcription from the ship's log, such as coordinates, weather, and notes  on the passage down the channel</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item" id="c01-1.2.7.5" score="1" C-ORDER="5"><did>
<unittitle>ff. 64v-65r: Comic poem by L. W. Novelli entitled "Dirge of the Dinnerless," describing the
 dinner of December 14th</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item" id="c01-1.2.7.6" score="1" C-ORDER="6"><did>
<unittitle>ff. 65v-67r: Program from the Christmas Charade</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item" id="c01-1.2.7.7" score="1" C-ORDER="7"><did>
<unittitle>ff. 67v-68r: Observations on Melbourne</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item" id="c01-1.2.7.8" score="1" C-ORDER="8"><did>
<unittitle>ff. 68v-70r: Journey to Launceston, Tasmania.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
