<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8kk9cmp/">brod1914.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Brodkin (Karen) research files and recorded interviews</titleproper><titleproper>Finding aid for the Karen Brodkin research files and recorded interviews <num>LSC.1914</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Gloria Gonzalez, September 2012.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated on 2020 September 14.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-01 13:50:02 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in <language>English.</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Karen Brodkin research files and recorded interviews</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79041523" rules="aacr" source="naf">Brodkin, Karen</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79041523" role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="naf">Brodkin, Karen</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n90626030" role="dnr" source="naf">Howes, Carollee</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.1914</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(5 shoe boxes and 4 document boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2009" type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2000s</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_67091306c428da16869f1c99549ee391" label="Abstract">Materials on labor, race, gender, the environment and contemporary grass roots social movements in Los Angeles communities. The materials were produced through the academic research of Karen Brodkin, Professor Emeritus in the UCLA Anthropology Department. The collection mainly consists of recorded interviews in a variety of formats. Additionally, the collection includes audiovisual materials as well as  documents, photographs, and negatives from research in Los Angeles and surrounding areas.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_747ba03e54bbb9a84258ab7e7cd2b753">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_da1cda73c1147502d3720fe7f96c9368">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f873b694f69d06c336036507bdff0195">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_2926542259d32b158334329f0d6593e6">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>CONTAINS DIGITAL/AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed digital and audiovisual materials. Digital/audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file level. All requests to access processed digital or audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_674a36d5a320c0a053be606da846e4ea">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright to portions of this collection has been assigned to the UCLA Library Special Collections. The library can grant permission to publish for materials to which it holds the copyright. All requests for permission to publish must be submitted in writing to Library Special Collections. Credit shall be given as follows: The Regents of the University of California on behalf of the UCLA Library Special Collections.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dd386deb4be8d8acc2985e8660e30d3b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Karen Brodkin research files and recorded interviews (Collection 1914). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_19e6a0d6190c25ae47f5df820db58481">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Gloria Gonzalez with assistance from Kelley Bachli, September 2012.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_df1a66e4a6aba03f667003416a97c829">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9970922263606533">9970922263606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_94c36a3383e43f9c3c9bc3c52319352f">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>Karen Brodkin is Professor Emeritus in the UCLA Anthropology Department. Brodkin recieved her Ph. D. from the University of Michigan in 1971. Her research concentrates on social movements, gender, work and kinship, political economy, as well as race and contemporary North American cultures. Selected works of Brodkin's include <emph render="italic">Power Politics: Environmentalism in South Los Angeles</emph> (2009); <emph render="italic">Making Democracy Matter: Identity and Activism in Los Angeles</emph> (2007); <emph render="italic">How Jews Became White Folks and What That Says About Race in America</emph>(1988), in addition to <emph render="italic">Caring by the Hour: Women, Work and Organizing at Duke Medical Center</emph> (1988) and <emph render="italic">Sisters and Wives: the Past and Future of Sexual Equality</emph> (1979). Brodkin is also the creator of the 1998 documentary video, <emph render="italic">Let's Own It! The Struggle of the Lincoln Place Tenants Association</emph>.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5ec7bd86fcd960239fb967e6f40f0810">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection mainly consists of recorded interviews in a variety of formats. Additionally, the collection includes audiovisual materials as well as  documents, photographs, and negatives from research in Los Angeles and surrounding areas. Topics of the material include labor, race, gender, the environment and contemporary grass roots social movements in Los Angeles communities.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79041523" role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="naf">Brodkin, Karen</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n90626030" role="dnr" source="naf">Howes, Carollee</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref2_o46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital images and video recordings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1995" type="inclusive">Circa early 1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_4440372493713569542b423d1a6ee140" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3e48af506a91692e528cefa3a21f118"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Contains "Oakwood: Struggle to Hold On to a Community" on VHS and DVD; "Let's Own It: The Struggle of The Lincoln Tenants Association" and "The Energy Puzzle: One Man's Solution" in VHS format; "Our Lives Are Not For Sale: EJ Victory Against Power Plant in South Gate, CA" on DVD; and a Mini CD labeled "from CBE: yuki@cbecal.org" that contains five image files of CBE assemblies and events.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_322ce295f41b68fdee5ee5c3b51bbbcc"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing.  To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.</p></phystech></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref5_jrc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interviews from <emph render="italic">Power Politics: Environmentalism in South Los Angeles</emph> on audio cassette tape</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a2e0fd75eaf8d1b25f7f7184659b880" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93085bc9b39fe304c47fbabf0184fc99"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Contains interviews with South Gate community members including students, community organizers and activists, and workers from Communities for a Better Environment. Interviewees include Martha Andrade (South Gate community activist), Milton Hernandez (Youth Environmental Justice activist), Raul Morial (South Gate mayor), Rhonda Nitschsky (Downey community activist), Roy Abadi (South Gate community activist), Xochilt Ruvalcaba (South Gate City Councilor) and Yuki Kidokoro (South Gate lead organizer).</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_24d43db4b8b484ba3d30350ef774c085" level="item"><did><unittitle>2nd Group Interview with Communities for a Better Environment leaders (Alvaro Huerta, Yuki Kidokoro, Angelo Logan)</unittitle><unitid>yrlsc_1914_002_001</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Sound Recordings</extent><extent altrender="carrier">(1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:59:25)</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001-04-06/2001-04-06">2001 April 6</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfc2545826f8cc15777cc6ac196296f8" label="Audio" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4b963a309fc34b2485f60934130affde" parent="aspace_bfc2545826f8cc15777cc6ac196296f8" type="case">1</container></did><phystech id="aspace_7fac5a94dfc0f065f97bcc97d690da86"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><scopecontent id="aspace_20f5d7b9b4b519b8846bd29474784f15"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Transcribed from container: Side A only. Copy.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_8sz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interviews from <emph render="italic">Power Politics: Environmentalism in South Los Angeles</emph> on audio cassette tape</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ba4f957a2a83dceee148feae277cdfc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3cb97866e3eebc13a06afd26f16986e7"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Contains interviews with South Gate community members including students, community organizers and activists, and workers from Communities for a Better Environment. Interviewees include Abram Ruiz (South Gate High School student), Angelo Logan (Communities for a Better Environment (CBE) organizer), Bahram Fazeli (CBE staff scientist), Celine Leyva, Marina Jimenez (South Gate community activists), Hector de la Torre, Henry Gonzalez (South Gate City Councilors), Leticia Ortiz, Veronica Sanchez (South Gate High School teachers) Jackie Amparo, Jairus Ramos, Geyman Hernandez, Jorge Duenas, and Marco Martinez (South Gate High School students).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref7_vcw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio cassette tape recordings of interviews with Venice activists and from <emph render="italic">Power Politics: Environmentalism in South Los Angeles</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/2001" type="inclusive">1989-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_131343f32c7681cc018d83e84f2d8341" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5764274cb59c90158787ee25da9f279"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Interviewees include Carol Fondiler, Mary Jane, Pearl White, Flora Chavez, Shearwood Flemming and Regina Hyman.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref8_u7k" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio cassette tape recordings of interviews from <emph render="italic">Making Democracy Matter: Identity and Activism in Los Angeles</emph> and <emph render="italic">Power Politics: Environmentalism in South Los Angeles</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/2001" type="inclusive">1999-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a9a088f6489add80c8225d67a05a597" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_20df7c978e22272af717f4fde9438114"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Interviewees include Aisha Livingston, Aquilina Soriano-Verzosa, Douglas Marmol, Eileen Ma, Michelle Mascarenhas, Milton Pascual, Norma Martinez, Quinh Nguyen, Roxane Auer, Liz Sunwoo, and Communities for a Better Environment members.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_b3df4b02ee0cefe9aa35fc573fd70344" level="item"><did><unittitle>Group Interview with Communities for a Better Environment leaders (Alvaro Huerta, Yuki Kidokoro, Angelo Logan, Milton Hernandez)</unittitle><unitid>yrlsc_1914_005_001</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Sound Recordings</extent><extent altrender="carrier">(1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:59:25)</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001-03-01/2001-03-01">2001 March 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea30e377e065618107c7025d4a516821" label="Audio" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_66a2a07799772fbd82516a9dd9d76ebf" parent="aspace_ea30e377e065618107c7025d4a516821" type="case">1</container></did><phystech id="aspace_b3c0502788f96243833863d0b1731e46"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref9_fhg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Microcassette tape audio recordings of interviews from <emph render="italic">Making Democracy Matter: Identity and Activism in Los Angeles</emph> and <emph render="italic">Power Politics: Environmentalism in South Los Angeles</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/2002" type="inclusive">1999-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_f35c3f8053370115cd974e8381eaf909" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8ebbabc51bfedff6a7aafa5e9eff9e2"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Interviewees from <emph render="italic">Making Democracy Matter</emph> include Aisha Livingston, Aquilina Soriano-Verzosa, Douglas Marmol, Eileen Ma, Joann Lo, John Delloro, Michelle Mascarenhas, Milton Pascual, Norma Martinuez, Quinh Nguyen, Roxane Auer, Stephanie Monroe, Tori Kim, and Liz Sunwoo. Interviewees from <emph render="italic">Power Politics</emph> include Angelo Logan, Carlos Porras, Carmen Avalos, Celine Leyva, Hector de la Torre, Henry Gonzales, Jairus Ramos, Leticia Ortiz, Veronica Sanchez, Jorge Duenas, Luis Cabrales, Robert Cabrales, Marco Martinez, Martha Andrade and Raul Morial.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref11_9mb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Venice research files
</unittitle><container id="aspace_da7f211d7d2a41037b390c475dd4e0f5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ecdebb8b4ae4358d371d79202d825fd9"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Files contain documents, photographs, and negatives from research with various collaborators and research assistants including Bobi Jackson, Venice poet and musician; Quinta Seward, co-researcher on the <emph render="italic">Oakwood: Struggle to Hold onto a Community</emph> video project about Venice's African American community; Rachel Chapman, UCLA anthropology graduate student and Venice activist researcher, and Oakwood researchers Adande Washington and Monica Russel y Rodriquez.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_7p4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lincoln Place Tenant Association and Venice research files</unittitle><container id="aspace_c2ef2df88f2a5c081525c74179506e30" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e58a17df7027bdb1549a426b652125f1"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Files contain documents, photographs, and negatives from research with various collaborators and research assistants including Mary Hardy, collaborator on the <emph render="italic">Let's Own It!</emph> project with the Lincoln Place Tenants Association and Lincoln Place researcher Gail Sansbury.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref16_yn0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs from Lincoln Place Tenant Association project; notes and ephemera from the <emph render="italic">Power Politics</emph>, South Gate, and Common Threads projects</unittitle><container id="aspace_4f01c39a9bcef56f89223a2f491a4cfb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
