<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6n39s2d4/">buel1202.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Buell (Llewellyn M.) Postcard collection</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Llewellyn Morgan Buell Postcard Collection <num>LSC.1202</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Chris Marino with assistance from Megan Hahn Fraser in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), July 2011; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2011.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-19 14:46:30 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Llewellyn Morgan Buell Postcard collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Buell, Llewellyn M. (Llewellyn Morgan)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.1202</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.6 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(3 shoe boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1900/1955" type="inclusive">circa 1900-1955</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5c67c9ac712bbcfb993955f1930731e4" label="Abstract">Llewellyn Morgan Buell was a founding faculty member at UCLA in the English department. His collection consists of approximately 2,300 postcards of landmarks and art in the United States (especially New Hampshire), Europe, Mexico, and North Africa.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_07a50f621b6a9c653810db6a076e5a66">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1b4c41c52ed136630ce6a25802d9444f">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_84f11fb663c227c79fd39f9d0835455e">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fa92db689c971b5b87ebbebda3882433">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2d049c44b8a614990c7c5151bc556404">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Mrs. L.M. Buell, 1977.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9c9f2a20de503d5741f352ca93a64901">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Llewellyn Morgan Buell Postcard collection (Collection 1202). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0d2f24d148ca8a8442edb9298b430d94">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Chris Marino with assistance from Megan Hahn Fraser in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), July 2011.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_70805b78cd22e7f57a284cd06e7dd3d2">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942304273606533">9942304273606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_13a16d0e6e92efe7aaa32cdb6f646ce0">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Llewellyn Morgan Buell was born in Jamesville, New York in 1888. In 1910, he received his bachelor's degree from Cornell. He earned a master's degree at Harvard in 1911 and a PhD in 1917. During World War I he served as a lieutenant in the U.S. Army Air Service. Buell taught at Yale, University of Missouri, and was a founding faculty member of the English department at UCLA. Aside from a year long leave of absence from 1925-1926, Professor Buell taught at UCLA from 1922 until his retirement in 1955. Llewellyn Morgan Buell died in 1975, at the age of 86.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a47f7b497aecf2e40fa248312073f4b9">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection consists of approximately 2,300 black and white and color postcards of landmarks and art in the United States (primarily the east coast, including numerous views of New Hampshire), Mexico, Europe (primarily Italy) and North Africa. The majority of the postcards have not been used; some have messages written on the back. This collection dates from 1900 to 1955.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Postcards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Picture postcards.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_suy" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Hampshire</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1900-1955.</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1601d1a295b309768298d2f290b6ff3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_514e78bf1165d89e328ac36c82fdbf50"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Black and white and color postcards of landmarks in New Hampshire.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_exh" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States, Mexico, Europe, and North Africa</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1900-1955.</unitdate><container id="aspace_f61cc4982c34d5a43943b9f71ad95a07" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1460d33e6646794100e1b729f6066608"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>First half of box contains postcards from the United States, primarily the East coast. The second half of the box contains postcards from Europe, the majority of which are from Italy. There are a few of postcards from Egypt and around 15 from Mexico. The last thirty postcards within this box are from Llewellyn Buell's friends to him; see blue handwritten note which denotes beginning of this section.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_qx3" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States and Europe</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca 1900-1955.</unitdate><container id="aspace_08193d605d90ea270032c6d31dcf3423" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9a7f3872d8b3eb2385f8cb63134706ad"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The majority of the postcards in this box depict European art. Handwritten notes within the box denote different themes such as: secular painting, mosaics, and the female form within painting and sculpture. There are some postcards of United States national parks and monuments.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
