<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6489r85p/">ca170136.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">California land claims, v. 1-24, and misc. vols.</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the California land claims, v. 1-24, and miscellaneous volumes <num>LSC.170/136</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by UCLA Library Special Collections staff; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2009</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address><p>Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2q81b7n">LSC's Metadata Rights Statement</extref> for more information.</p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-07 12:34:59 -0800</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>California land claims, v. 1-24, and miscellaneous volumes</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.170/136</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box, 28 leaves : paper ; 25 x 20 cm </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3eb1f47b4cab97d2dbe33f6f4266dcdc" label="Abstract">This is an augmented index to the California Land Claims, v. 1-24, a record of claimants and briefs for ranchos in the 1850s and 1860s.</abstract>
    <physdesc id="aspace_bbccff8e013642cbf6791a975f072f2b" label="Physical Description">28 leaves : paper ; 25 x 20 cm Layout: Average of 25 lines per page. Script: Typescript.</physdesc>
    <physloc id="aspace_2b067d957f7d260376515828e96cb616" label="Physical location">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_d03d144b92c2bd349b19b6c5f1e4efa2">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7c52798069963dc521cb66af57da48df">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fd8d8bb9d99ee66abd2a73e68af548d1">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <odd id="aspace_3dd0a33c6a4bf2f11447cab1f0d02597">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942304033606533">9942304033606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c15ceae0388a0ab910977495cd766c00">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], California land claims, v. 1-24, and miscellaneous volumes (Collection 170/136). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e4baf6181976b355d0a2b2c046a0272c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's library collections and archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2e4418a835a8724343d84da0cd1ccd48">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>When the United States took possession of California and other Mexican lands in 1848, it was bound by the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo to honor the legitimate land claims of Mexican citizens residing in those captured territories. In order to investigate and confirm titles in California, American officials acquired the provincial records of the Spanish and Mexican governments in Monterey. Those records, most of which were transferred to the U. S. Surveyor General's Office in San Francisco, included land deeds, sketch-maps (diseños), and various other documents. The Land Act of 1851 established a Board of Land Commissioners to review these records and adjudicate claims, and charged the Surveyor General with surveying confirmed land grants.</p><p>Additionally, to determine the validity of Spanish and Mexican land grants in California, Congress set up a Board of Land Commissioners. Unless grantees presented in two years evidence supporting their title, the property would automatically pass into the public domain. Although the Land Commission eventually confirmed 604 of 813 claims, the cost of litigation forced most Californios to lose their lands. Government attorneys appealed 417 claims, out of a total of 813. Some cases were appealed several times; appeals prolonged each litigation process for an average of seventeen years. Questions of title were settled by the Federal courts, and authority to segregate claims judicially confirmed was vested in the proper executive officers of the United States. </p><p>The remainder of privately owned Mexican territory annexed to the United States was settled under the the eighth section of the act of July 22, 1854, which made it the duty of the surveyor-general to ascertain the origin, nature, character, and extent of all claims to lands under the laws, usages, and customs of Spain and Mexico and to report the conclusions to Congress. The law did not impose a limitation of time in the presentation of claims or a penalty for failure to present. In the next thirty years, more than one thousand claims had been filed with the surveyor-general, of which less than one hundred and fifty had been reported to Congress, and of that number, Congress acted upon seventy-one. Under the law, only copies of the original title papers were submitted to Congress. Of the 813 grants ultimately claimed, the land commission approved only 553.</p>  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ca516cba9c18761ede8feec85a932194">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt538nb916">Bound Manuscripts Collection (Collection 170) </extref>. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Land titles -- California.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Land grants -- California.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_433d988138c6c24e26485ad28809c8b2" level="series"><did><unittitle>[Alphabetized list of land claimants]</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee07df469c21bc33437c114e64543eb8"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>This short, edited index contains an alphabetized list of land claimants, with the corresponding name of the rancho that he or she claimed to own in their brief. </p><p>Additional notations in red ink and pencil have been added to the typed text, with a note on the title page explaining the meanings of of the marks. </p><p>These notations include: 
<list type="simple">
<item>an indicator that the rancho in question has a corresponding map in a collection called "California land claims maps"; </item>
<item>United States Land Commission numbers, as listed in the Appendix to Ogden Hoffman's Reports of Land Cases; and Supreme Court numbers. </item>
</list></p><p>Starting on page 24, the index also lists miscellaneous public lands, including swamps, water front property, and school areas, with references to dated legal documents that pertain to each type of land.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
