<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt167nf0qz/">cart1488.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Cartter (Allan M.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Allan Murray Cartter papers, 1952-1975 <num>LSC.1488</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Caroline Cubé, 2011.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2011</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-31 16:05:23 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Allan Murray Cartter papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Cartter, Allan Murray</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.1488</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1975" type="inclusive">1952-1975</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d9bd6eb68f0b39131fdd30737d5c5be9" label="Abstract">Allan Murray Cartter (1922-1976) was an accomplished economist, scholar, and professor. He is known for his many contributions in graduate education evaluation, income analysis, and research in education. The collection contains a sampling of some his academic and professional contributions, mainly from the latter years of his career as an educator and administrator.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_e5c6f7f56b27f21d1807c0479ac88ca8">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_6361bc89f279c7ad59e9f76f3a55a5cc">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_700d3c58e584ac2a5f162ea915f0ffac">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_215496426a5b8d331595e3a2ba239eb7">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_69d8fd60b1b02709445b4c40172492af">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Allan Murray Cartter papers (Collection Number 1488). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ad639a6fd1bb8fbb2b9e20a52575b355">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of the estate of Allan M. Cartter, May, 1989.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b0f052eb201c0e7af3046e4174172f36">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Jesse Erickson in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), with assistance from Megan Hahn Fraser, August 2011.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_112779c2e47891239fb0d7f32f5e9016">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9942326683606533">9942326683606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b56189c29bca1f72cbd1a25eac9f221b">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Allan Murray Cartter (1922-1976) was born in Plainfield, New Jersey. He completed his undergraduate studies at Colgate University where he received his B.A. in 1946. He attended Yale University where he earned his M.A. in 1949 and his Ph.D. in1952. He also served in the U.S. Army from 1942-1945. Cartter served dual positions as both professor in the Duke Economics Department and as Dean of the Graduate School from 1959 to 1962. In 1963, Cartter secured a new professorship at New York University, where he later served as the university chancellor from 1966 to 1972. He was also served as vice president of the American Council on Education in Washington, D.C from 1963 to 1966. In 1973, Cartter accepted a position at UCLA where he was Professor of Higher Education and Director of the Laboratory for Research on Higher Education.</p><p>Cartter's specializations were in education and economics. His more specific research interests included the evaluation of graduate education, national income analysis, and labor and tax policy. His <title>Rating of Graduate Schools: An Assessment of Quality in Graduate Education</title> became a national standard and set the precedent in terms of its quality for future studies of this kind. Other important works from Cartter include <title>Higher Education: Who Pays? Who Benefits? Who Should Pay?</title> (McGraw Hill: 1973), and <title>Ph.D.s and the Academic Labor Market</title> (McGraw Hill: 1976). He died on August 4, 1976 in Los Angeles, California.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a7bc57d93cde0884df50de9bca234477">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection consists of various pamphlets, transcripts, and evaluations in the form of draft reports spanning from the years 1973 to 1975. Included in these reports are joint findings from interdisciplinary academic clusters, and from a bio-medical research panel and an academic survey of state colleges and universities. Also included is a copy of his dissertation from 1952.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Educators -- United States -- Archives.</occupation>
    <persname source="naf">Cartter, Allan Murray--Archives.</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">University of California, Los Angeles. Graduate School of Education--Faculty -- Archives</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_30z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Projects</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1974-1975.</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb41ccb02257a5b7a95e5ec943123574" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_febe8294994be46c6dcb05431c16df24" parent="aspace_bb41ccb02257a5b7a95e5ec943123574" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5e4dd1cedfeefb54b686e729cf97cd7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Pamphlets and reports with descriptions and evaluations of the UCLA Teacher Education Laboratory. Includes a report on the Teacher Credential Program for the academic year of 1974-1975.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_0f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Projects</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">June 13, 1975.</unitdate><container id="aspace_9bb2e2e9cc96ea2ec98bf8d48e56fd29" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3be17b487290f6f834dbc81e07dc586a" parent="aspace_9bb2e2e9cc96ea2ec98bf8d48e56fd29" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d14b9158daa4385670972fd41e43357"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Thirty-six page report titled Mini Project: Affirmative Action and its Impact Upon Students' Appraisals of their Employment Prospects with appendices.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_uf2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">October, 1975.</unitdate><container id="aspace_0931a66c32f6d2e75ffccc0818352110" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_84ef9bd6d9dcf658134bbf66c6c2e96f" parent="aspace_0931a66c32f6d2e75ffccc0818352110" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e314f1c652b8e49f80c7b4d3386696c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Draft excerpts from the President's Biomedical Research Panel. Includes the report of the Behavioral Sciences Interdisciplinary Cluster and the Report on the Status and Future of Communicative Sciences.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_rqf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">October, 1975.</unitdate><container id="aspace_d31b7849a39220c32b54f40fb05a8c9e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a80a3872d0172822f6a62be85376a42e" parent="aspace_d31b7849a39220c32b54f40fb05a8c9e" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_654d14ccd46fe03ffe3b143f1c73250e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Draft excerpts from the President's Biomedical Research Panel. Includes the final reports of the Epidemiology, Biostatistics and Bioengineering Interdisciplinary Cluster, the Nutrition Interdisciplinary Cluster, the Pharmacology, Substance Abuse, and Environmental Toxicology Interdisciplinary Cluster, the Social and Behavioral Development Interdisciplinary Cluster and the Tissue and Organ Biology Interdisciplinary Cluster.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_g6d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">April, 1973.</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca3abfe28f6c0909b03092904e30536c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2d96790e6e00a4f52da9e1137279305a" parent="aspace_ca3abfe28f6c0909b03092904e30536c" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_673ddde4c912554d3741ff75fb7ddd9e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Draft chapter excerpt from a survey of 279 institutions included in the membership of the American Association of the State Colleges and Universities and a report from the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Develpmont, Education Committee titled The Education Situation in Member Countries: A Review of Trends and Priority Areas for Policy.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_suy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">June 8, 1973.</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d37672c6cba8b3f70df4e925012c1d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2bd9babebaa206325b1797cf8238d8cd" parent="aspace_8d37672c6cba8b3f70df4e925012c1d3" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e4bd630f0b64fc760f91bb2ad599c536"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>A transcript of the Proceedings of the Conference on Availability of Data Relating to Careers, pp. 1-46.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref23_l1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">June 8, 1973.</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ee9fcb1d414cca7d70441c8100d13a6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5d46cc1cf4429f642a0c77b28a26b36c" parent="aspace_5ee9fcb1d414cca7d70441c8100d13a6" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9dfb0d8a338eb1074c303ab5cb4c9b08"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>A transcript of the Proceedings of the Conference on Availability of Data Relating to Careers, pp. 47- 103, with appendices.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref25_sns" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allan M. Cartter's doctoral dissertation (bound)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1952.</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba4c11bab3ca55e429c3e1d9d948a419" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_39ae37b3fe59461ce418b9359d31f7fe"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Redistribution of the Income in Post-War Britain through Central Government Finance.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
