<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">

<ead>
<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" scriptencoding="iso15924" audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft">
<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="CLU-SC" identifier=" http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5q2nf0z3 ">PUBLIC "-//University of California, Los Angeles::Library Special Collections//TEXT(US::CLU-SC::170/053::Commonplace Book)//EN" "co170053.xml"</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for the Commonplace Book, 1684-1720</titleproper>
<titleproper type="filing">Commonplace Book</titleproper>
<author>Cataloged by Manushag Powell, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, July 2004; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cub&#x00E9;.</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher>
<address>
<addressline>UCLA Library Special Collections staff</addressline>
<addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline>
<addressline>Box 951575</addressline>
<addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline>
<addressline>Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.library.ucla.edu/libraries/special/scweb/</addressline>
</address>
<date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">&#x00A9; 2008</date>
<p>The Regents of the University of California. All rights reserved.</p>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Text rekeyed by Caroline Cub&#x00E9; from in-house paper finding aid, <date>2008</date>. Machine-readable finding aid derived from rekeyed finding aid, encoding added via Notetab Pro. Date of source: <date>2004</date>.</creation>
<langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" 
scriptcode="Latn" >English.</language></langusage>
<descrules>Finding aid prepared using <title linktype="simple">Describing Archives: a Content Standard</title></descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<unittitle label="Title">Commonplace Book</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1684/1720">1684-1720 </unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection number" repositorycode="CLU-SC" countrycode="US">170/053</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname rules="aacr2">unknown</persname></origination>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>59 leaves extant : paper ; 145 x 96 mm. bound to 150 x 100 mm.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract label="Abstract">This commonplace book's unidentified author was a student at Oxford.  Much of the small volume is filled with accounts and receipts; these include statements of the author's expenses, ranging from tutors and booksellers to tobacco and candles. It also includes short letters, verse and prose entries, and directions for drawing and painting. Written in English, with some Latin and Hebrew.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Language">Finding aid is written in 
<language langcode="eng">English, </language>
<language langcode="lat">Latin, </language><language langcode="heb">Hebrew.</language></langmaterial>
<repository label="Repository">
<corpname>University of California, Los Angeles. Library Special Collections.</corpname>
<address><addressline>Los Angeles, California 90095-1575</addressline></address>
</repository>
<physloc label="Physical location">Stored off-site at SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</physloc>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UCLA Library Special Collections. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="534">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Commonplace Book (Collection 170/53). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.</p>
</prefercite>
<odd>
<head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p> UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref actuate="onrequest" show="new" href="http://catalog.library.ucla.edu/vwebv/holdingsInfo?bibId=4230403">4230403</extref></p>
</odd>
<processinfo>
<head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Cataloged by Manushag Powell, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, in the Center For Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), July 2004.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
<head>Biography/History</head>
<p>The author is a student at Oxford during the reign of James II.  He is thus likely teenaged, and certainly male.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="530">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The book is a miscellany written in a single hand.  It appears that the pages in the volume were filled at different times (and in no particular order), but the bulk seems likely to have been between 1684 and 1686. Contents include accounts of the author's expenses while at Oxford University, including tutors and booksellers, clothes, shoes, handkerchiefs, foodstuffs, and his pocket money.  It also contains a few short letters, verse and prose entries, the latter often in Latin, and a few acrostics/puzzles in both English and Latin.  The author also seems to be taking Hebrew lessons, and occasionally practices his Hebrew characters.  One section of the book is devoted to directions for drawing and painting, and on cleaning artwork as well as mixing chemicals and paints.  This includes recipes for mixing paints of a wide variety of colors, often with somewhat whimsical names.  Towards the end of the book is a section of Biblical studies.</p>
<p>Binding: Original sheep binding.</p>
</scopecontent>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres and Forms of Material</head>
<genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Manuscripts.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related Material</head>
<p>
<extref href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt538nb916" actuate="onrequest" show="new">Bound Manuscripts Collection (Collection 170)
</extref>. Available at the UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
</archdesc>
</ead>