<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8kw5gvn/">cure9422.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Cure (Alfred C.) photograph albums</titleproper><titleproper>Photograph albums of Alfred Capel Cure, 1850-1856 <num>LSC.94/22</num></titleproper><author>Jane Carpenter with assistance from Simon Elliott; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-04-04 13:57:25 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English.</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Photograph albums of Alfred Capel Cure</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Capel Cure, Alfred, 1826-1896, photographer.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.94/22</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 albums</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(ca. 300 photographic prints) : salt paper, ambrotype ; 33-34 x 26-29 cm (albums)
<lb/>Photographs are mounted on leaves of white paper, with ms. captions indicating date, location, and other subject information. A numbered list of the photographs in Vol. 2, in the same hand, is affixed to inside back cover of the album.
<lb/>Vol. 1 half-bound in brown leather and marbled paper boards, with gilt rules along corner pieces and backstrip; rebacked spine, with original black leather spine label preserved, bearing gold-stamped title "Photographs." Vol. 2 is half-bound in green leather and scuffed green marbled boards, with ornamental embossed borders along corner pieces and backstrip; spine rebacked, with gold-stamped spine title "Album of Alfred Capel Cure. 2." Capel Cure's engraved bookplate, with his crest and motto ("Fais que doit arrive que pourra") on front pastedown. Bookplate of C.K. Ogden in upper left-hand corner of front pastedown.
<lb/>Spec. Coll. copy: each album housed in its own modern beige cloth clamshell box with velcro closure; box titles in black: "Photographic Experiments" (v. 1) and "Album of Alfred Capel Cure" (v. 2).</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1856" type="inclusive">1850-1856</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_49b042c01f1017db044188cc8a4b8955" label="Abstract">Early photographs of castles and country houses, landscapes, and portraits in England, Gibraltar, and Ireland, taken between 1850 and 1856 taken by Alfred Capel Cure.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_30af106093a492cb27c1df0af5ffbc5e">Stored off-site at SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz002kmsgj" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Photograph albums of Alfred Capel Cure (94/22 v. 2)" xlink:type="simple">
    <daodesc><p>Photograph albums of Alfred Capel Cure (94/22 v. 2)</p></daodesc>
  </dao>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_067ba38d05347be3be347ab095115a6a">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ae1aa2f5029a5742984c639919cae453">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UC Regents. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <odd id="aspace_0141ebe4370abd240e2d658221726c27">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9963566453606533">9963566453606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a402c7a66200729672b07e7f4a1424f8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Photograph albums of Alfred Capel Cure (Collection 94/22). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_798fef38c13eae130194515d440f66c6">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>Alfred Capel Cure was an officer in the British Army, and an early pioneer of photography. His uncle, the painter and photographer Robert Henry Cheney (1800-1866), taught him photography, and in 1850, Capel Cure began making salt prints of architectural subjects--manor houses, cathedrals, abbeys, and churches. Capel Cure was initially commissioned into the 55th Regiment of Foot, and later, as a member of the Grenadier Guards, he fought in the Crimean War, where he was wounded in the attack on the Redan at Sebastopol. He attained the ranks of Lieutenant-Colonel (1858) and Colonel (1863). Capel Cure died July 29, 1896, in an accidental explosion while dynamiting tree roots in his park.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b635c083a9d58930d0a038dc7e7b7fca">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Volume 1, with ms. title "Photographic Experiments, 1850-1851," contains some of Capel Cure's earliest photographs of medieval manor houses and castles in the English countryside, particularly Derbyshire, Shropshire, Sussex, and Hertfordshire, many of which have long since been demolished. Included in Vol. 1 are views of Stokesay Castle, Wenlock Abbey, Badger Hall (Capel Cure's family home), Millichope Park, and Chetwynd Park in Shropshire; Ashridge and Down Hall in Hertfordshire; Stoke Edith and Hereford Cloister in Hereford parish; Darley Abbey Hall, the paper mill in Darley, and Duffield Bridge in Derbyshire; Powis Castle, with its distinctive terraced gardens, located in Powys, Mid Wales; Shrubland Hall in Suffolk; and Holland House, Kensington, London. Vol. 2 contains photographs taken between 1850 and 1856, many of them views of British Army garrisons and barracks in Gibraltar and Ireland. Photographs from 1851-1852 include several views of Casemate Barracks from the Montague Cavalier station at the British garrison in Gibraltar, some with uniformed fellow soldiers in the shot, as well as several views of Capel Cure's summer house in Gibraltar. There are many photographs from 1853 and 1854 of the British barracks at Roscrea, Templemore, Athlone, and Shannonbridge in Ireland, and portraits of soldiers stationed there, many of whom served with Capel Cure in the 55th Regiment of Foot, and later, in the Grenadier Guards. He has noted in some of captions which comrades were killed, when, and where (Crimean War--Balaklava, The Alma--1854). Capel Cure also photographed civilians around the barracks, such as a knife grinder, barracks gate boy, chimney sweep, rag boy, and beggars, and included many views of nearby landmarks, such as Corville Abbey, Rosecrea (1853), the Rock of Cashel, Cashel Cathedral, King Cormac's Chapel, Culdee Chapel and Round Tower in Clonmacnoise on the River Shannon south of Athlone (1853), and Loughmoe Abbey just south of Templemore (1854). There are also numerous views of Badger Hall, photographed with family, friends, and dogs "Pharaoh", "Jet", and "Flush", during 1854; and several portraits of the photographer himself. The photographs dated 1856 include a series of shots of Exeter Cathedral, and Greenstead Church (the oldest wooden church in the world), Bovinger Church, Blake Hall in Essex, and Battle Abbey and Pevensey Castle in Sussex. Capel Cure's experiments with photography are evident in two views of Roscrea Castle from 1852: one made with a single lens, the other with a double lens. He also identifies two ambrotypes he made in 1854, using the collodion wet plate process.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_292b22e6ebdb8189f6754d2d1502c913">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Part of the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6489s0cc/">Photograph Album Collection (Collection 94) </extref> in UCLA Library Special Collections.</p><p>Additional information and images of photographs by Alfred Capel Cure (1856-1860) and Robert Henry Cheney (1850s) at the website of the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.cca.qc.ca/en">Centre Canadien d'Architecture / Canadian Centre for Architecture (CCA) </extref> in Montréal, Québec.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <processinfo id="aspace_29c4862be8f7b9dc532ae47650540d8f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Sussex (England) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Gibraltar -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photograph albums -- England -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Ambrotypes -- England -- 1854.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photographs -- Ireland -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photographs -- Gibraltar -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photographs -- England -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Salted paper photographic prints -- Ireland -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Salted paper photographic prints -- Gibraltar -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Salted paper photographic prints -- England -- 1850-1856.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Rosecrea (Ireland) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Athlone (Ireland) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Templemore (Ireland) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Ireland -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Great Britain. Army -- Barracks and quarters -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Great Britain. Army -- Military life -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Great Britain. Army. Regiment of Foot, 55th (Westmorland)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Architecture, Medieval -- England -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Architecture, Domestic -- England -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Country homes -- England -- Photographs.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Derbyshire (England) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Shropshire (England) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Hertfordshire (England) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Suffolk (England) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <persname source="ingest">Capel Cure, Alfred, 1826-1896 --Homes and haunts --Photographs.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Capel Cure, Alfred, 1826-1896 --Photographs.</persname>
    <persname role="fmo" rules="rda" source="naf">Ogden, C.K. (Charles Kay)</persname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Exeter Cathedral --Photographs.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
