<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" scriptencoding="iso15924" audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft">
<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="CLU-SC">PUBLIC "-//University of California, Los Angeles::Library Collections//TEXT(US::CLU-SC::1813::Edward A. Dickson Cuneiform Tablet collection)//EN" "dick1813.xml"</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for the Edward A. Dickson Cuneiform Tablet collection, Ur III period-Neo-Babylonian period (ca. 2100-562 BCE)</titleproper>
<titleproper type="filing">Dickson (Edward A.) Cuneiform Tablet collection</titleproper>
<author>Transliterations by Justin Cale Johnson.  Processed by Sara Brumfield in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli, 2008; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cub&#x00E9;.</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher>
<address>
<addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline>
<addressline>Box 951575</addressline>
<addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline>
<addressline>Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.library.ucla.edu/libraries/special/scweb/</addressline>
</address>
<date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">&#x00A9; 2009</date>
<p>The Regents of the University of California. All rights reserved.</p>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from database containing container list structure and data, encoding added via MS Access and Notetab Pro; Date of source: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 2008;</date> frontmatter gathered MARC Record. Supplementary encoding and revision supplied by Caroline Cub&#xE9;.</creation>
<langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" 
scriptcode="Latn" >English.</language></langusage>
<descrules>Finding aid prepared using <title linktype="simple">Describing Archives: a Content Standard</title></descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<unittitle label="Title">Edward A. Dickson Cuneiform Tablet collection</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2100/562">Ur III period-Neo-Babylonian period (ca. 2100-562 BCE)</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection number" repositorycode="CLU-SC" countrycode="US">1813</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname rules="aacr2">Dickson, Edward A.</persname>
</origination>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>1 oversize box.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract label="Abstract">The majority of the eight tablets are administrative in nature, citing loans, receipts, and inventories. Most of the administrative texts date to the Ur III period (Third Dynasty of Ur).  One tablet contains a royal inscription from the Early Old Babylonian period (ca. 2000-1800 BCE) on a clay cone.  This collection was donated to UCLA by Edward A. Dickson.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Language">Finding aid is written in 
<language langcode="eng">English.</language>
</langmaterial>
<repository label="Repository">
<corpname>University of California, Los Angeles. Library Special Collections.</corpname>
<address><addressline>Los Angeles, California 90095-1575</addressline></address>
</repository>
<physloc label="Physical location">Stored off-site at SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</physloc>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. Literary rights, including copyright,
are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of
the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the
copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC
Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>
</userestrict>
<processinfo>
<head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Transliterations by Justin Cale Johnson. Processed by Sara Brumfield in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli, 2008.</p>
</processinfo>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Edward A. Dickson Cuneiform Tablet collection (Collection 1813). Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>
</prefercite>
<odd>
<head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p> UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref actuate="onrequest" show="new" href="http://catalog.library.ucla.edu/vwebv/holdingsInfo?bibId=6426937">6426937</extref></p>
</odd>
</descgrp>
<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
<head>Biography</head>
<p>Edward Augustus Dickson donated his collection of tablets to the University of California-Los Angeles. Dickson was one of the founding fathers of the Los Angeles campus for the California university system. He was appointed to Board of Regents in 1912 and served until his death in 1956, at the age of 76.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The majority of texts in this collection are administrative in nature, citing loans, receipts, and inventories. All but one of the administrative texts date to the Ur III period (Third Dynasty of Ur), known for its abundance of economic documents. During the Ur III period (ca. 2100-2004 BCE), the state reached a level of centralization that was unprecedented. To accommodate the large population of workers and products under this state run economy, written records of business transactions and inventories were constantly issued.</p>
<p>The collection also contains a royal inscription from the Early Old Babylonian period (ca. 2000-1800 BCE) on a clay cone. Clay cones were often used to commemorate the building of monumental architecture. An inscription praising the king and his deities would be written around the cone on its vertical axis. Then the cone would be inserted into the wall of the structure obscuring the inscription from human eyes.</p>
<p>The cone is from the reign of Lipit-Ishtar (ca.1934-1924 BCE). His seat of power was in the city of Isin. Lipit-Ishtar is best known for his set of laws, issued even before Hammurabi's famous law code. When Lipit-Ishtar published his law code, he also built the Enisisa (literally, "house of justice") and he had its construction recorded on over a hundred clay cones, of which this is just one.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>Tablets are described at the item level.</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects</head>
<persname role="subject" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">Dickson, Edward A. (Edward Augustus), 1879 or 80-1956--Archives.
</persname>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related Material</head>
<p>
<extref href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt438nf4h2" actuate="onrequest" show="new">Cumberland Clark Cuneiform Tablet Collection (Collection 1826)
</extref> Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<dsc type="in-depth">
<head>Container List</head>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 1 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of sheep and goats from Drehem in the 5th month of the 8th year of Amar-Suen's reign</unittitle>
<unitdate> 2039 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373972" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>List of sheep and goats from Drehem, Iraq dating to the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE). The 8th year of Amar-Suen's reign dates to 2039 BCE. The festival of Ninazu is
 the 5th month of the Drehem calendar year.
</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 2 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of sheep and goats from Drehem in the 5th month of the 47th year of Shulgi's reign</unittitle>
<unitdate> 2048 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373973" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>List of sheep and goats from Drehem, Iraq dating to the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE). The 47th year of Shulgi's reign dates to 2048 BCE. The festival of Ninazu is the
 5th month of the Drehem calendar year.</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 3 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of types of grain from Umma in the 1st year of Ibbi-Suen's reign</unittitle>
<unitdate> 2028 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373974" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>Lists of different types of grain from Umma, Iraq dating to the reign of Ibbi-Suen (c. 2030 BCE). The first year of Ibbi-Suen's reign dates to 2028 BCE. The month that
 "the brick was placed in the brick mold" is the second month of Umma's calendar year.</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 4 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of reed mats</unittitle>
<unitdate> ca. 2000 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373975" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>A note describing a reed mat(?) of unknown provenience dating to the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE).</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 5 </unitid>
<unittitle>Adminstrative tablet of sheep and goats from Drehem in the 42nd year of Shulgi's reign</unittitle>
<unitdate> 2053 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373976" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>List of sheep and goats from Drehem, Iraq dating to the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE). The 42nd year of Shulgi's reign dates to 2053 BCE. The month of "eating the
 gazelle" is the first month of Drehem's calendar year.</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 6 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of sheep and goats from Drehem in the 4th year of Amar-Suen's reign</unittitle>
<unitdate> 2042 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373977" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>List of sheep and goats from Drehem, Iraq dating to the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE). The 4th year of Amar-Suen's reign dates to 2042 BCE. The month of An's
 festival is the 10th month of Drehem's calendar year.</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 7 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of hired workers in Umma from the Ur III period.</unittitle>
<unitdate> ca. 2050 BCE</unitdate>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>A list of two hired workers and oxen from Umma, Iraq dating to the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE). Currently missing from Special Collections holdings.</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 8 </unitid>
<unittitle>Royal inscription from the reign of Lipit-Ishtar</unittitle>
<unitdate> ca. 1930 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373978" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>Royal inscription of Lipit-Ishtar on a clay cone dating to the Old Babylonian period. Lipit-Ishtar was king in Mesopotamia for ten years between 1934-1924 BCE. Lipit-
 Ishtar ruled from the city of Isin and is famous for issuing a set of laws. When he published his laws, Lipit-Ishtar also built Enisisa, the "House of Justice," and he had its construction
 recorded on lots of clay cones like this one.
 Note: this text = RIME 4.1.5.4 (Frayne 1990, 52-54).
 For another exemplar of this inscription see:
 <extref href="http://special.lib.umn.edu/rare/cuneiform/UM15.phtml" actuate="onrequest" show="new">http://special.lib.umn.edu/rare/cuneiform/UM15.phtml
 </extref></p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
<c01 level="file"><did>
<container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
<unitid>Item: 9 </unitid>
<unittitle>Administrative tablet of a silver loan from the reign of Nebuchadnezzar II</unittitle>
<unitdate> ca. 580 BCE</unitdate>
<dao linktype="simple" href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/search/archival_view.php?ObjectID=P373979" actuate="onrequest" show="new"/>
</did>
<scopecontent><p>Citing loan of silver and witnesses involved dating to the reign of Nebuchadnezzar II in the Neo-Babylonian period. Nebuchadnezzar II was king of Mesopotamia from
 604-562 BCE.</p>
</scopecontent>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>