<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c86d5zs9/">djed2315.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">DjeDje (Jacqueline C.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Jacqueline C. DjeDje papers, 1939-2004 <num>LSC.2315</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Angel Diaz, 2017; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 9 August 2017.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-06-17 15:12:41 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jacqueline C. DjeDje papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">DjeDje, Jacqueline Cogdell</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.2315</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.2 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(4 document boxes, 1 half box, and 1 flat box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/2004" type="inclusive">1939-2004</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2004" type="bulk">1980-2004</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5f84776d61c46b0e6e70e79e5333663d" label="Abstract">Jacqueline C. DjeDje joined the UCLA faculty in 1979. She was Chair of the UCLA Department of Ethnomusicology and Director of the UCLA Ethnomusicology Archive. DjeDje specialized in African and African American music, West African fiddle music, gospel music, and music historiography. The collection consists of professional and teaching materials, musical event materials, and sheet music.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_5630664c0458efefd8c339c575b79358" label="Physical Location">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_33c4d139d428731cc6efb6c7f53b4f01">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0a89319b4817dfaae4b43c18aa45fd97">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_083c3135371aba01ee73c07b780d0e50">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_91f37d0798262e671de67a465515ce2c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Copyright to portions of this collection has been assigned to the UCLA Library Special Collections. The library can grant permission to publish for materials to which it holds the copyright. All requests for permission to publish must be submitted in writing to Library Special Collections. Credit shall be given as follows: The Regents of the University of California on behalf of the UCLA Library Special Collections.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e4df4a6f829e41b6b57ff2d68b62ec5f">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Jacqueline C. DjeDje, 2014.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_f0153b60a25c16320aa616c71b255192">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9981682633606533">9981682633606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_32d7b00963b66c02a23464812581a462">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Jacqueline C. DjeDje Papers (Collection 2315). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0fe39975ffc06daec6d56a39589efb8d">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Angel Diaz, 2017.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's Library Collections and Archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ce6dd6a13994a01d7282bc17c244d2e3">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>Jacqueline Cogdell DjeDje is Emeritus Professor and former Chair of the UCLA Department of Ethnomusicology (2005-2010) as well as former Director of the UCLA Ethnomusicology Archive (2000-2007). She was born in Jesup, Georgia on November 4, 1948. She received her BA in music from Fisk University in 1970, her MA in ethnomusicology from UCLA in 1972, and PhD in ethnomusicology from UCLA in 1978. Her graduate work focused on African and African-American music. Before joining UCLA's faculty in 1979, she taught at Tuskegee University from 1975-79. </p><p>DjeDje taught theoretical area courses in African and African-American music and was director of an African-American vocal ensemble. Much of DjeDje's research focused on performance practices as they relate to the one-string fiddle tradition in West Africa. She is author and editor of several books: <emph render="italic">Black Music Research Journal</emph> special issue, "Music of Black Los Angeles" (Spring 2011); <emph render="italic">Fiddling in West Africa: Touching the Spirit in Fulbe, Hausa, and Dagbamba Cultures</emph> (2008); <emph render="italic">Turn Up the Volume! A Celebration of African Music</emph> (1999); <emph render="italic">California Soul: Music of African Americans in the West</emph> (co-edited with Eddie S. Meadows, 1998); <emph render="italic">African Musicology: Current Trends, Vol. 1</emph> (co-edited with William Carter, 1989); <emph render="italic">African Musicology: Current Trends, Vol. 2</emph> (1992); <emph render="italic">Distribution of the One String Fiddle in West Africa</emph> (1980); <emph render="italic">Black Religious Music from Southeast Georgia</emph> (1979); and <emph render="italic">American Black Spiritual and Gospel Songs from Southeast Georgia: A Comparative Study</emph> (1978). </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_87460f79c7ed4c41c717d53c5b61b4a9">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Jacqueling C. DjeDje papers span from 1939 to 2004 with the bulk of the materials from 1979 to 2004. The collection consists of UCLA Department of Music faculty meeting minutes and correspondence; Ethnomusicology Archive correspondence, meeting agendas, events, and other materials; UCLA events featuring Dje Dje flyers and programs; UCLA Gospel Choir correspondence, programs, flyers, and photographs; Los Angeles and international music event flyers and programs; DjeDje's course syllabi and student work; and sheet music.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_152545cdcc254f543b9654ddff47281a">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has been arranged in the following series:
<list type="simple">
<item>Series 1: UCLA files, 1978-2004</item>
<item>Series 2: Teaching materials, circa 1980-2003</item>
<item>Series 3: Sheet music, 1939-1999</item>
</list></p><p>Materials are arranged alphabetically. </p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_cbd5ca1fa852f8e5fc23646ae9353d51">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p><extref xlink:href="https://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c81n8029
" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Jacqueline Cogdell DjeDje Collection</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">DjeDje, Jacqueline Cogdell -- Archives</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">University of California, Los Angeles. Department of Ethnomusicology--Faculty -- Archives</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref3_13e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: UCLA files.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/2004" type="inclusive">1978-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_0827b7a567a777738f6cc57cd6638d76" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ce9f3bb1ba3eb6440522062c9c1ea2cc" parent="aspace_0827b7a567a777738f6cc57cd6638d76" type="folder">1-14</container><container id="aspace_064f219f9e6faafcf5c4e4348b8465d8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_bafaa2a86a629f314905548c667311d8" parent="aspace_064f219f9e6faafcf5c4e4348b8465d8" type="folder">1-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1bb4c7badb5ffa582952684832f4f0e6"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 1-2: UCLA files are organized alphabetically by name, project, publication, event or subject. Materials include correspondence; conference agendas and notes; UCLA Department of Music faculty meeting minutes; Ethnomusicology Archive correspondence, meeting agendas, events, and other materials; UCLA events featuring Dje Dje flyers and programs; UCLA Gospel Choir correspondence, programs, flyers, and photographs; Los Angeles music event flyers and programs; international music event flyers and programs; music catalogs; and world music band, Nipa's album on compacts discs and Professor Ian Hall's musical direction on audio cassettes.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_fb548f85dba04b923feb598469f099d9"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>SERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p><p>SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref4_u2l" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Teaching materials.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa 1980-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c04b3e92cf19be1249399c76b23f7cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b8b24927435124add9ebce8fac86c6d6" parent="aspace_5c04b3e92cf19be1249399c76b23f7cc" type="folder">9-19</container><container id="aspace_7fdc96b11410955375c12be42988a905" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_33ae1840ce2a67052e36f58d8d068406" parent="aspace_7fdc96b11410955375c12be42988a905" type="folder">1</container><container id="aspace_36a0a016d09cf0bc181738a0ec101033" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_b30e6646d1e8d8c06345805409a48f5d" parent="aspace_36a0a016d09cf0bc181738a0ec101033" type="folder">1-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_790d1772017caae554871c632232cef3"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 2-4: Teaching materials are organized by course number, starting with materials from Department of Music and followed by Department of Ethnomusicology. Materials include DjeDje's course syllabi, assignment descriptions, course readers, lecture notes, and student work.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref5_dki" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Sheet music.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1999" type="inclusive">1939-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b8e59bca7bf5e0deb79b82f49dd0f47" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_bf65f2709b6cbba927bd11944c25b77e" parent="aspace_5b8e59bca7bf5e0deb79b82f49dd0f47" type="folder">1-4</container><container id="aspace_ac90d061283ceed55e94488658258781" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_646c119c1e071916c92040e232958cf6" parent="aspace_ac90d061283ceed55e94488658258781" type="folder">1-4</container><container id="aspace_570606975b2d10e6ee4f65c45e1df5bb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_00e17c9ca3f4660c8e0d316e01d699d4" parent="aspace_570606975b2d10e6ee4f65c45e1df5bb" type="folder">2-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2cbb5166f11af10e85c36c00b7705284"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 4-6: Sheet music organized in alphabetical order, by composer's last name or genre. Materials include published or photocopied sheet music for gospel songs, Broadway musicals, popular music, African music, and spirituals.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
