<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8mc91d3/">ethio937.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">A collection of Ethiopic manuscripts</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for a Collection of Ethiopic Manuscripts <num>LSC.0937</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Kesis Melaku Terefe, October 2008; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2013.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-02 14:01:28 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>A collection of Ethiopic manuscripts</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.0937</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 unknown</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(13 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">various dates</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3a5084188297b04b22db26c812bcc9fc" label="Abstract">Collection contains 64 Ethiopian manuscripts.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_54eb0a92580549afe4f2692490f390ba">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8ec5df5c187fa94df58dc46ee11cc7c4">Materials are in English, Ethiopic (Ge'ez), and Amharic.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_adf1178ee7730b58dd9bc791bc1819ec">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_008e4f57ef1ca964f03412133aa5ca29">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Existence and Location of Copies note for the link to the digitized materials.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_603cafa7328f0cd168410c6bd6ee040f">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bf8e406a520dee98489ce2f499589a8e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], A collection of Ethiopic manuscripts (Collection 937). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f74e9e70b0a7500381d871da60ea0559">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>Processed by Kesis Melaku Terefe, October 2008.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_51184f41dbc2dfe1233ac95f9cdc8b97">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma999643443606533">999643443606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6139bad5b71034b46e498c45d35efe78">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection contains 64 Ethiopian manuscripts. Of these, 14 are magical prayers, 10 of which are in scrolls. Most of the manuscripts are service books of Ethiopian Orthodox Church. There is one manuscript which is the prayer book of Beta Israel (Ethiopian Jewish community); it is one of very few Jewish manuscripts written in Ethiopic (Ge'ez) and Agaw. Most of the manuscripts are written in the Ethiopic (Ge'ez) language but there are some manuscripts in Amharica.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <altformavail id="aspace_1c7f50dffed13b25099935802a5038ef">
    <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
<p>Digitized materials are available electronically at<extref xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/x3xg9000zz-89112" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new"> https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/x3xg9000zz-89112. </extref></p>  </altformavail>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_714e09d33ed9f3efd9fd344a0f2a132d">
    <head>Ge'ez descriptions available</head>
<p>To obtain a copy of this finding aid which contains Ethiopic language (Ge'ez) descriptions of the material, please contact UCLA Library Special Collections. A computer with the Ge'ez font installed is necessary to view the Ge'ez descriptions.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ethiopic manuscripts.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref10_1w8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Qeddasé Maryam, Malek'a Kidana Mehrat<lb/> Uniform title: Anaphora of Mary, Images of the Saints<lb/> Title (English): The Anaphora of Mary and Image of Kidana Meherat (Covenant of Mary).</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1842-1854.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4594240eded02cee262798a24bf662ce" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: two columns of text, 14 lines of text per page<lb/>Size: 97 mm x 64 mm x 28 mm (heighth, width, spine)<lb/>Velum, 120 pages (60 leaves)<lb/>the manuscript composed in six quires 10 leaves each<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each prayer, instructions for the priests and deacons, Saint Mary's name and the name of the Holy Trinity are in red ink<lb/>Binding: stamped leather over wooden boards.<lb/>Written by a single hand.<lb/>No drawings.<lb/>Quires??</physdesc><container id="aspace_508985870ab3fd805c95a8997eceb5fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_a5971e5a884ee9473ae13be39b1c2c15"><head>Biography</head><p>Based on the size of the manuscript (it is too small for church service), we can say the purpose of this manuscript is for private use.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_b2a6444560df59a4966aa008b5b8ee79"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p. 82, the previous owner's name is overwritten with ink and, at the bottom of the page, it says "Ayela Eyasus's origin is in Wallaga."</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_8236bd8f38f3725a4a6a8b9d8e84a4b4"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>One of the the official fourteen anaphoras of the Ethiopian orthdox church. Praise for St. Mary and discourse on the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit as the major part of the liturgy.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_8x5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Arede'et , Sena Feterat, Mes?ira Hayamnot, Amestu A'emada Mes?ir<lb/> Uniform title: The Book of Disciples, Beauty of the Creation, Mystery of the Faith<lb/> Title (English): The Book of Disciples, Beauty of the Creation, Mystery of the Faith (The Five Pillars of Mystery).</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">18th-19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_adb4b0212bc4fea2f9b7177025b597b1" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column of text, the first book 14 lines of text per page the second book with different hand has different lines per page.<lb/>140mm x 95m x 73m<lb/>Vellum, 300 pages<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each prayer and the names of Jesus, Christ, Mary, and also the name of the owner are in red ink<lb/>Binding: Wooden board.<lb/>The second part of Beauty of the Creation is written by another scribe in poor handwriting.<lb/>Quires?</physdesc><container id="aspace_808a6658291d3cf45d8bcaa4893e941c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_adad21984b5f996c51a0dab9834235ef"><head>Biography</head><p>The manuscript contains four books. Book of the Disciple is the Christian version of the same book which is also used by the Beta Israel (Falasha or Ethiopian Jew). It narrates how Jesus told his disciples his hidden names. The second book, The Beauty of the Creation, also lists what God created in six days. The Five Pillars of Mystery teaches the basic doctrine of the Ethiopian Church in catechism format.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_12b12c3404bad4da545e3575aa283f73"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner (scribe?) was Gabra Heyewat. On pp.89, 90, 97, 99, 100, 120, his name is erased and over it inserted the second owner's name Waleda Hawareyat. The scribe of Beauty of the Creation mentions Abuna Wold (pp. 180).</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_lhq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Weddasé Maryam, Anqa?a Berhan, Yewédeswa Mala'ekt, Malk'a Maryam, Malek'a Eyasus<lb/> Uniform title: Wedase Mareyam<lb/> Title (English): Praise of Mary, The Gate of the Light, Angeles Praise Her, The Image of Mary, and the Image of Jesus.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">late 19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_041a3438d330a9e8c0b326a6f225db6c" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns on vellum, 17 lines per page<lb/>Vellum, 128 pages<lb/>Size: 147 mm x 105 mm x 30 mm<lb/>Binding: stamped red leather over the board<lb/>Text in black ink, Jesus and Mary's name and the beginning of each prayer (maleke) are in red.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_59204f9d693e2296c7bd16e702faeec0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_3f99fcfc5183bb98c109f93b5344eec5"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p.126, the owner wrote in Amharic and Ge'ez that "this book belongs to Gabera Hana."</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref22_zmh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?oma Deggwa<lb/> Uniform title: Church Hymns<lb/> Title (English): Hymns for Lent.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Late 19th-early 20th cent.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_65df111686aaf6472c4a287ebc01d59c" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 222 pages.<lb/>Two columns per page, 21 lines of text per page.<lb/>Size: 161 mm x 124 mm x 50 mm<lb/>Text mainly in black ink. The musical tones, the type of song, and the day for that song are in red ink. Small hand.<lb/>Some missing musical notes added in blue ink (pen)<lb/>Musical notations throughout, above each line of the hymn.<lb/>Binding: wooden board with leather spine, in sewn plastic case with applique and cloth strap. String<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>Illustration of Saint Yared p. 4.</physdesc><container id="aspace_3ea1d3c9d5f5ab97f5d41a277390c11a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_b8d1c95ad7dc39ae21baaf47dc6f4222"><head>Biography</head><p>Soma Degguwa is one of St. Yared's well-known hymn books. It is the standard for traditional church education. Learning Soma Degguwa is the second great step after finishing reciting psalm.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_7825a1007a5bf86aa6ae2319fe836045"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner is listed in pencil as Tafasa of Dabera Amin Takla Haymanot (p. 1)</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_bde56192485c556f92939a51e7b82c6c"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Hymns for Lent season. St.Yared, the author of these hymns, divided the Lent season into eight weeks. Almost all of the hymns are constructed around the teaching and miracles of Jesus. The hymns discuss the teaching of Jesus in the Synagogue, his cleaning of the temple, the miracle of healing paralysis, the parable of the faithful servant, his discussion with Nicodimus, his teaching about his second coming, his glorious entrance into Jerusalem, his last days in Jerusalem, and his crucifixion.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref27_2iv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Yetbarak Egzi'abehér amelaka Esra'él …<lb/> Uniform title: Prayers of the Beta Israel<lb/> Title (English): Blessed Be the Lord God of Israel ….</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th.c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_7f4a580ba8943b473b5a05f77cac2f27" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 200 pages<lb/>Two columns, 14 lines of text per page<lb/>Size: 145mm x 130mm x 40mm<lb/>Text in black ink. The beginning of each section ('me'eraf), the names of God, and the angles are in red ink.<lb/>Binding: without cover boards.<lb/>The manuscript composed in 12 quires</physdesc><container id="aspace_e71aca680a22000f1050c3c71c9027d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_dd9314c634f42e45937bffb0a5b31a37"><head>Biography</head><p>A rare and important collection of Beta Israel prayers in the Ge'ez and Agaw languages. Most of the Ge'ez prayers are derived from the Bible, especially from Psalms, those in Agaw are more indigenous and difficult to translate. One of the last Beta Israel books to be written in Ge'ez or Agaw. See David Appleyard, Title??? (publisher, date).</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_0dd7277d2c7523ffad87e9905d9f8812"><head>Provenance</head><p>p. 145, the owner of the book is named Abba Barok. Purchased by Prof. Wolf Leslau.</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref31_ini" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ma?ehafa ?emeqat<lb/> Uniform title: Book of Baptism<lb/> Title (English):Book of Baptism.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_5317330990d07813db3c8d10d718d712" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 72 pages<lb/>One column of text, 14 lines of text per page<lb/>Size: 148 mm x 110 mm x 40 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards with leather spine<lb/>Text in black ink, some names and the beginning of the prayers and instructions for Deacons and Priests are in red.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_882cc0f0ce23b4f85390230df8fb52ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_7cbdfeb41e65903737c7403e8637b6a8"><head>Provenance</head><p>"This book belongs to Wayzaro Walatta Kidan. She gave the book to the church of Kidane Merhat" (p. 64)</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref34_sf9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Mazemura Dawit, ?alota Nabiyat, Wedasé Maryam, Anqa?a Berhan<lb/> Uniform title: Dawit<lb/> Title (English): Psalter, Canticles of Old and New Testament Prophets, Praise of St. Mary, The Gate of Light.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4c32ea60170dd9a53864e17a8e389d8a" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column of text, 22 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 142 pages<lb/>Size: 170 mm x 115 mm x 30 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards.<lb/>The front wooden board and two thirds of the Psalms pages are missing. The Psalms begin with Psalm 111 (112): 3b.<lb/>The manuscript is damaged, probably by water. The text in red ink is totally washed out or faded.<lb/>The manuscript composed in seven quires of two quires has 12 leaves each , four quires of 10 leaves each and one quire of 8 leaves.<lb/>The text is in black ink; the name of God, angels, and saints, including the scribes and the owners, and the first line of each book, is in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_c42ec785f65b81b10055de3436806a20" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref36_i7o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta ?emama Ayena ?ela wa- Ayena Wareq, Mahléta ?egé, Seyefa Selassé,Qeddasé Maryam<lb/> Uniform title: Prayer, Qedasé<lb/> Title (English): Prayer against the Disease of Ayena ?ela and wa- Ayena Warek, Canticles of the Flower (Mary), Sword of Trinity, Anaphora of St. Mary.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_8b1c8885c6126e07ee3185722e2d2661" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: pp1-65 and 207-217 One column of texts. Pp75-206 and 219 two column of text<lb/>Vellum, 272 pages. The first four blank pages with out page numbers.<lb/>Size: 120mm x 94 mm x 40 mm<lb/>Binding: stamped red leather over the board each book written with different hand.<lb/>The first book of the manuscript composed in one quire of two leaves, three quires of ten leaves each and one quire of six leaves.<lb/>The second book of the manuscript composed in one quire of four leave one ten leave six quires of eight leaves each one qiere of five leaves.<lb/>The third book in composed in one quire of six pages.<lb/>The fourth book composed one quire of ten leaves one quire of eight leaves and one quire of six leaves.<lb/>Text is in black ink. Divine and saints name in red ink</physdesc><container id="aspace_9af72664af8b8a446199806065e9ddc4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_40ebaf94598f3366c39c5ec99dd382d9"><head>Provenance</head><p>The magical prayer agianst ayena tela was owned by Fekada Egezi'e (pp. 2, 6, 12, 13, etc). Canticles of the Flower was owned by Hayela Sellase (pp. 141). And the second owner of that book is Waleda Mareyam (pp. 141). Sword of Trinity owned by Walda Zena Markos (pp. 209, 212, 217). The Anaphora of St. mary was owned by Walda Tensae (pp. 219, 265).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_c684f5cde8f03234e909e9745aa4034c"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The prayer against the disease of ayena tela uses magical names for protection from evil spirits. Mahaléta ?egé are songs for St. Mary sung during Zamana Sege (the season of flowers), the season between Meskaram (September/October) 26 and Hedar (November) 6. The seaons is the commemoration of the flight of the Holy Family to Egypt. Sword of Trinity. Praise for the Holy Trinity and prayer for protection from evil spirits and evil people.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref40_ibx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ta'amera Mareyam Maqdem Tergwame<lb/> Uniform title: Te'amera Mareyam<lb/> Title (English): Commentary on the Introductory Rite of Almuqqa of the Miracle of Mary.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b21aba5cc5a6bf2a144cb72658210a5d" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, 11 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 134 pages. The first four pages are blank and with out page nambers<lb/>Size: 100mm x 70mm x 35mm<lb/>Composed of quires of eight and ten leaves each.<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each chapter (parts) and also the divine and church father names in red ink. Binding: wooden boards</physdesc><container id="aspace_a85a12d09e5959178b58baba7ee8a9ad" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_fac6dd052ada0e61089eedde661a1bc5"><head>Biography</head><p>According to the tradition of the Ethiopian Orthodox Church, the introduction of the Miracles of St. Mary must be read before any other reading from the book. There are two types of introduction. The longer one presented in this manuscript is read every Sunday and on the feast of St. Mary. The introduction of the Miracles of St. Mary is also known as the Book of Order, which discusses how the book of the Miracles of St. Mary came to Ethiopia. In addition to its introduction about the honor of St. Mary and her miracles and the importance of reading her miracles, the book also lists the 33 feasts of St. Mary. Based upon the method of andmeta commentary, the author tries to comment on the introduction and points out the importance of honoring her feast and hearing the reading of the miracle. The author also explains the severity of the anathema of the fathers on those who have not followed this order.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_a573cad102bcd11ff3b4b4ba3a332a74"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p.133, Debetara Zena is mentioned as the owner.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_074dc34d14636e9b15b41744ac95db7d"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Commentary on the introduction to the Miracles of St. Mary; it is a rare individual commentary. The writer follows the 'anedemta' commentary style. The main theme is about the usefulness of listening to the reading of the book of the Miracles of St. Mary and keeping the 23 feasts of St. Mary</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref45_aqf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?abiba ?abiban; Arde?et<lb/> Uniform title: Hymn to God; Book of the Disciples<lb/> Title (English): The Wisest of the Wise; Book of the Disciples.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Late 19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0d01c98542c4e5228e2ef7716d10fd47" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column of text per page,11 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 166 pages<lb/>Size: 102 mm x 74 mm x 33 mm<lb/>Binding: stamped red leather over the board<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of eight leaves each<lb/>Text is in black ink. The beginning of each chapter (parts) and prayers with divine names are in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations</physdesc><container id="aspace_80684dc4c31c488393ec16eedccb2526" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dbf4fa8402eb8bd961fb040d0a49835d"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Tebiba Tabiban is a hymn for God written in metrical poetry. For Ared'et, see MS no. …</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref48_359" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Deresana Mika'él<lb/> Uniform title: Deresan<lb/> Title (English):Homilies on St. Michael the Archangel.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_7ca9519f6040a0010ce00d9ba98968fd" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 274 pages<lb/>Two columns per page, 19 lines of text per page<lb/>Size: 195 mm x 140 mm x 59 mm<lb/>The manuscript composed of fourteen quires of two quires of four leaves, four quires of twelve leaves and eight quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>Text in black ink. The beginning of each homily and the names of Jesus and the archangel Michael are in red ink.<lb/>Binding: wooden board with string binding<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_b8246ba0c1c654adf3707e9728cd0c01" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_4044b4c4db0621f11df29938c160ee42"><head>Biography</head><p>These thirteen homilies are written to be read during the feasts of St. Michael each month. Each homily includes a miracle of the Archangel Michael and hymns for him.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_6a90a102eccead77af4fedef8ddedf07"><head>Provenance</head><p>The original owner is unknown. The later owner inserted his name in pencil as Takela Maryam.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_a3b9599a71fdfb801da253dae28934fb"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>A collection of thirteen homilies in honor of the Archangel Michael. Following each homily there is one miracle of St. Michael and the Synaxarium about St. Michael for each month.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref53_5a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Sayefa Sellasé, Dersana Mika?él, Amestu A'emada Mes?ir<lb/> Uniform title: The Sword of the Trinity, Homily of St. Michael, The Five Pillars of the Faith<lb/> Title (English): The Sword of the Trinity; Homily On St. Michael; Introduction of The Five Pillars of the Faith.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Late 18th.c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ba2e636ecd0397ab6137d135c2f33f63" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns per page,17 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 100 pages<lb/>Size: 165 mm x 130 mm x 30 mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>Text is in black ink, the beginning of each prayer and divine names are in red ink.<lb/>Binding: wooden board without a cover for the spine<lb/>Some borders as illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_942220e2426015b786f1752f2fa75d5e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_bd0110b0a4b2d0b2e1b22aad47b3321e"><head>Provenance</head><p>The previous scribe or owner's name, Takla Haymanot, has frequently been erased from the text and replaced with the name Gabera Heyewot</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_7f1adbb432044a0b80da3c0f63bd0081"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Prayer to the Holy Trinity (Father, Son, and the Holy Spirit). Praise of the Trinity based on God's attributes. Theology of the Triune God. Prayer for protection from evil spirits, evil persons, magicians, and sorcerers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref57_ibu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Nages (Egzi?abehér Nagesa)<lb/> Uniform title: Hymns for Saints' Feasts<lb/> Title (English): Enthroned (God Is Enthroned).</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f15b29d736e5588c369d4ebd01aa18a9" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column per page, thirteen lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 222 pages<lb/>Size: 135 mm x 87 mm x 48 mm<lb/>Text in black ink, beginning of each nagese divine and saints' names in red ink.<lb/>Binding: wooden boards. With protective vellum cover over the vellum only. Leather spine cover.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of very different quires (in number of leaves and size).<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_099eb8ddc02a75a110c42e1d1971c15d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_122ad1d94777e37f81cba08916196c80"><head>Provenance</head><p>The first owner is listed as "Gabera Egezi'abeher Saneduna Qale" on p.217, the second owner is listed as "This book belongs to Dabetera Nadew's. End of Nages [the book]." (p. 2)</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_7a411112ae6382a328a64405dfdbcbe2"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Nages for feast days</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref61_dbw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Amesetu A?emada Mes?ir; Bahera ?asab; Nags<lb/> Uniform title: The Five Pillars of Mystery; Computus; Hymns<lb/> Title (English): The Five Pillars of Mystery, Computus of Ethiopian Calendar; Hymns to God and Saints.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Late 19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f45d4eeedcdafd66123fa16fa7b85006" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 120 pages</physdesc><physdesc id="aspace_f123690d046401a128c53692f1b6060f" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, fourteen lines of text per page<lb/>Binding: wooden boards<lb/>Size: 122 mm x 85 mm x 29 mm<lb/>Most of the manuscript is composed of quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>The text is in black ink; the name of God, angels, and saints, including the scribes and the owners, and the first line of each book, is in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_262c99d65cdc5923015f08eeb1186bff" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_7a10b222938277336a3a675ff63d8ed0"><head>Provenance</head><p>"This picture is for Aleka Hiruy" p. 1 (later addition?)</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref65_r6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Mesalyata Salomon; Daqiqa Nabiyat<lb/> Uniform title: Book of Proverbs and Minor Prophets<lb/> Title (English): Proverbs of Solomon; The Minor Prophets.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th-20th c,.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9f822b4126e081798f53af45aadf933b" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 178 pages<lb/>Binding: wooden boards<lb/>Size: 185mm x 165mm x 65mm<lb/>Text is in black ink, some names and titles of the chapters are in red.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of ten quires of one quire of four leave one quire of eight leaves eight quires of ten leaves each.</physdesc><container id="aspace_4faac47e5bfeafee7458fcde6e060c90" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_70335f9f982069b419a39fa0a336220e"><head>Biography</head><p>Amesetu Masahefeta Salomon (the five books of Solomon) is the name which is given to Proverbs, Tagsas, Wisdom, and Ecclesiastes and Song of Songs.In this manuscript Song of Song is not included. The reason seems to be that Song of Songs is usually attached with Psalms and it becomes part of the church service book. The manuscript also contains the books of the 12 minor prophets. Like the other Christian traditions, the Ethiopian scholars also divided the book of the prophets of the Old Testament into two parts, Abayet Nabiyat (major prophets) and Daqiqa Nabiyat (minor prophets). Critical editions and translations of parts of the Ethiopic versions of the books of Solomon and minor prophets of Ethiopic version were conducted, especially in Europe. For full discussion see ??????.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_1517d4f7a7f27640207a89976384a603"><head>Provenance</head><p>There is a note in Amharic from Abba Matthias, the Catholic Bishop of Shoa: "this book is for Tasaruye Waleda Selasse. I, Abba Matthias, put the seal twice by mistake." p.177 Tasefa Iyasus is also mentioned as the owner.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_6eabfa690d658d9acb617dcb7d50e3b3"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Part of the wisdom and prophetic books of the bible, which include Proverbs, Ecclesiastes, the Wisdom of Solomon, and the books of the minor prophets</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref70_ovs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Saatat; Nages; Liton<lb/> Uniform title: The Hours; Hymns for Saints; Liton<lb/> Title (English):The Hours; Hymns for Saints; Liton.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">early 18th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e9dc6dc78593549a3758ccd57bd27c35" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns per page,13 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 226 pages<lb/>Size: 145 mm x 140 mm x 68 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards<lb/>Text is in black ink; the beginning of some prayers and St. Mary's name are in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of fifteen quires of eight and ten leaves each.<lb/>Some leaves missing at the end.</physdesc><container id="aspace_8ae199df94e5591ae51d9ddb55842b59" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_1290a918fdc545194c09e50f628328b9"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p. 2 appears the names of Priest Wolda Abb and Priest Habta Giyoregis. Someone has inserted as a bookmark a blank form of colonial Italy's 'Telegramma in partaenza'. On the back of the form, it is written in Amharic, 'I, Mekonnen Gezaw, borrowed from my father Abba Jerom four Ethiopian Birr. Regarding my borrowing, I have confirmed it with my signature. I swear by the name of my father Abba Jerome. The guarantor is Aleqa Like Tebebt. Genebot (May ) 16, 1938 [EC]."</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref73_btn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Sayefa Malakot<lb/> Uniform title: The Sword of Divinity<lb/> Title (English): The Sword of Divinity.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_620ef6dce29eaa7e35b91929966f4f77" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, eight lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 36 pages<lb/>Size: 120 mm x 85 mm 12 mm<lb/>Text in red ink. Some faded parts are written for the second time in blue ink. Last page in blue ink.<lb/>Binding: Cardboard boards and string.<lb/>Illustrations.<lb/>Quires?</physdesc><container id="aspace_17092a11a652b6873e28884b692beda9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_530ecafb1a31f8a7af9920760f973882"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical names with magical illustrations. It is a prayer asking God for protection from various demonic and personal attacks.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref76_ysv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Dersana Mika?él<lb/> Uniform title: Deresan<lb/> Title (English):Homily on St. Michael the Archangel.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2ee388e7f261aa18dd6ff547457ef239" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column per page; 19 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 244 pages<lb/>Size: 214 mm x 149 mm x 60 mm<lb/>Binding: smooth wooden boards with leather case and strap<lb/>Text in black ink, the archangels and saints' names and titles of the chapters are in red.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of four, ten, twelve, and sixteen leaves each<lb/>Illustrations: some drawings and illustrated borders at the beginning of each month. Pp.2, 3, 234, 238, 242 Illustrations of Mary, St. Michael, and St. Gabriel with pen and color. Pp. 25, 42, 79, 154, 244 Crude drawings with pencil.</physdesc><container id="aspace_1b1d767bda7de0fc8083a96b59f89788" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_d608451660d493dd824be5c4a1656db2"><head>Biography</head><p>Thirteen homilies attributed to Ethiopian and other church fathers.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_a2a1108d8d65a00f12ae9ba4df7b3f9b"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p.78, the first owner is listed as Wolda Mareyam. The second or last owner wrote his name and his family's name in many place in the text: Gabra Selase, Senesata Mareyam (Tajitu), Gabera Madehen, Gabera Selase (Bafeqadu).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_6496c2ea5138a151addbf66a20ec316e"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Collection of thirteen homilies in honor of the Archangel Michael. Following each homily there is related one miracle of St. Michael and the synaxarium about St. Michael for the twelfth day of each month.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref81_xis" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ta?amera Maryam; Ta?amera Eyasus; Ta?amera Giyorgis; Ta?amera Mikaél;Ta?amera Gaber?él<lb/> Uniform title: Taamer<lb/> Title (English): The Miracles of Mary, Miracle of Jesus, Miracle of St. George, Miracle of Michael, Miracle of Gabriel.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_53f44e4dc4cc8dc3fd71c2437c34d103" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 170 Pages.<lb/>Two columns per page, 19 lines of text per page.<lb/>Size: 210 mm x 160 mm x 52 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards with stamped leather and string to tie closed.<lb/>The majority of the manuscript is composed of quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>The text is in black ink; the divine names of the saints and also the first few words of the miracles with the Trinitarian formula are in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations</physdesc><container id="aspace_14ed8bcb062d9a3cc2b1f6590e3e85c1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_1f775b6dcf32e53ab866a30b99cbd7a3"><head>Biography</head><p>The collection of miracles included in this manuscript are part of the readings for morning prayers. Local saints or patron saints or angels of that particular church can be added in the readings of collected miracles. But these miracles are the most popular among laity and clergy. The collection of the Miracles of Mary are always at the center of the readings. The Miracles of St. Mary have a special introduction.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_f3e112af79427c244a99d37efeb1c324"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owners were Gabera Madehen and Gabera Hiwot (passim).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_5eb3fbb37b5aad602569acd2051a4026"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Collection of the Miracles of Jesus, St. Mary, St. George, St. Michael, and St. Gabriel.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref86_wrg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Lefafa Sedeq; Manegada Samay<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayers<lb/> Title (English):The Bandlet of Righteousness, The Way of Heaven.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_587f40c701e3fc80b4c103e0b0c5ac10" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, folded a concertina<lb/>Size: 48 mm x 55 mm x 15 mm<lb/>Binding: Faced with paper board and tied with string. On two strips of vellum.<lb/>The text is in black ink; the divine names, the saints, and the name of the owner with the Trinitarian formula are in red ink.<lb/>Two illustrations in crude hand.</physdesc><container id="aspace_88a209cb7999e733d280b68e2500ad5d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_b350ef639dec9e4bf00fc4a635e24c15"><head>Biography</head><p>The Bandlet of Righteousness is a magical book which is very popular among the laity and nuns of the Ethiopian Orthodox church. In the past, like the Egyptian book of the dead, it was buried with the dead, but this tradition is no longer common.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_a69498fffe12f335af7862cf9f1e53f6"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner is Le'ula Qal Yeheyes and his Christan name is Gabera Mareyam.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_cf2720630966fab870525977270b5320"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>It is claimed that The Bandlet of Righteousness was written by the "holy hand of God the Father" and given to St. Mary before Christ was born. It contains prayers and the hidden names of God.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref91_t7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Mazemura Dawit, Asmat<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Psalms (for magical purposes).</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6d135ecb5f87180b7783f43d6bc69988" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, folded like concertina, text on both sides.<lb/>Size: 60 mm x 65 mm x 5 mm<lb/>No binding, composed of two strips of vellum.<lb/>The text is in black ink, but like other magical books, the beginning of each prayer and some magical names ('asmat') and magical tables are in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_7a442393f0ed06d75c4807e75c8d46a3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_0569fcd4e32e244eb85e0d7242c742f0"><head>Biography</head><p>In the tradition of the Dabtara (the unordained clergy of the Ethiopian orthodox church), parts of the Psalms are useful for magical purposes. The scribe of this magical book is himself Dabtara. Added at the end of the Psalms are other magical prayers and claims that reciting these prayers can bring love and wealth.The instruction is in Amharic mixed with some Ge'ez words.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7c30e5bdd91353d02526271cf51c7fe2"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Three chapters from Psalms with magical prayer instruction.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref95_ojo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot b?eneta ?amasno ma?esaru lasayetan<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer to Destroy the Binding of Satan.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_82a30b83a7a7fed74c869bec0977c4b5" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, folded like concertina, text on both sides.<lb/>Size: 55 mm x 53 mm x 14 mm<lb/>No binding, composed of two strips of vellum.<lb/>The text is in black ink, but like other magical books, the beginning of each prayer and some magical names ('asmat') are in red ink. The magical images are drawn with black and red inks.<lb/>Twenty nine magical illustrations in black and red ink.</physdesc><container id="aspace_abf8fae3277925ab60acbb4bcad6d7b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_7e0df64d235825e8890896cda1fd4aed"><head>Biography</head><p>This magical book is written for the healing of the disease called Barya (epilepsy).</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_bcdc887ec6827ed66f7e6146129a52e6"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner was Amata Egeziabeher (a woman), mentioned near the middle of the text.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_0d360cbc518b09398a6c24b58aecdc0a"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer against demons, zar, epilepsy, and so on. In addition to the magical or hidden names, it also contains certain passages from the the gospels.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref100_3n5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Sayefa Malakot<lb/> Uniform title: Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Sword of Divinity.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1900s.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_bcaa280842748b1aeaacdac13ff0bd86" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, 10 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 56 pages<lb/>Size: 86 mm x 70 mm x 14 mm<lb/>Binding: hard paper boards, but text in vellum<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_c203981fe69a7f53b9fa9adbc8fd10a9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_a8b5008e118d19acb6dec12c8a6422ec"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner might be Waleda Hana, who is mentioned on p. 9.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_df619288c793b69b8fb0cd9349c07e82"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer with magical names (hidden names) for seven days.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref104_5ya" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Mazemura Dawit; salota nabiyat; Weddasé Maryam; Aneqa?a Berhan<lb/> Uniform title: Psalter<lb/> Title (English): Psalter, Old and New Testament Canticles, Praise of Mary, and The Gate of Light.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">18th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_40d9a09620a34d9b53b970089e98a06a" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 360 pages</physdesc><physdesc id="aspace_938b5e01a04d03dc2718db7464b64bb4" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, 21 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 360 pages<lb/>Size: 160 mm x 120 mm x 64 mm<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each chapter, title of the chapter, and names of God, Mary, and the angels in red ink.<lb/>Binding: stamped leather over wooden board.<lb/>In Psalms, strings of words were missing, but were then inserted above the line or after the line by the same scribe. These additional words (often ten or twelve in a row) are written in the same hand, but smaller<lb/>The manuscripts composed in eighteen quieres</physdesc><container id="aspace_4d352af55aaef22d4a95e3ba6f60e96b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_d6c988ca8c99e8a4e02bcf69c78c505f"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p.1, there is writing and a very crude pencil drawing which says "this is the seal (of) Dejazmach Emru." On p.3, someone tried to erase the writing that said "this psalter is for Dejazmach Emru."</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref108_art" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Masehafa Qeddasé<lb/> Uniform title: Qedasé<lb/> Title (English): The Book of Missal.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f1fd0b3e7c59a2de329ab5c45d30c1a4" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 268 pages<lb/>Layout: Two columns per page, 14 lines of text per page<lb/>Size: 250mm x 222mm x 60mm<lb/>Binding: stamped leather over the board<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each prayer and anaphora, instructions for the priests and deacons, and also the order of pointing and benediction over the Host (bread) and the cup (wine) are in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript composed in fifteen quires</physdesc><container id="aspace_2e227793d2300babfe1cb23c64d404fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_0fee4f852aeceaf9881f8e0e39f21608"><head>Biography</head><p>The manuscript contains only the fourteen anaphoras which are commonly used in the church. In addition to that, like most published missals, it also contains the Office Prayer, Liton, intercessory prayers, and "enthronement" prayers. The order of the fourteen anaphoras and the following prayers are the same as in the published book of missal.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_3b96ad4437d3fcbcaee50f77cad8628c"><head>Provenance</head><p>The original owner's name is Gabra Selasse (p. 56)</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref112_3dn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ta'amra Eyesus<lb/> Uniform title: Miracles of Jesus<lb/> Title (English): Miracles of Jesus.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b3e19b7f486a1581575c78b110b8e9bc" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 124 pages.<lb/>Two columns, the majority of the text is in 21 and 25 lines of text per page.<lb/>Size: 234 mm x 188 mm x 54 mm<lb/>Text is in black ink. The beginning of each miracle and the names of Jesus and Mary are in red ink.<lb/>Binding: with wooden board and string.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of seven quires of eight leaves each and one quire of six leaves.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_19dd2a303268fe9e1cee3d33fc268dba" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_70dffb8898de30d65d830eb566774bd7"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner is mentioned by the name of Qale Kerestos and Eheta Giyorgis (p. 2, 121). Walata Rufael (probably the second owner) also inserted her name (p. 124). The most recent owner is Abba Gabera Mika'el, who is listed on the end page and put the anathema on those who would try to steal the book.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_83330ef569a811d3c7dcd3dcb9a24ddf"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Different miracles performed by Jesus. Some of them are similar to stories about his infancy from the apocryphal gospels.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref116_4ow" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Teregwame Wanegel<lb/> Uniform title: Commentary<lb/> Title (English): Commentary on the Gospel.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_fc7fe53e35d09aad8e3b9d10ec7f6add" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns; lines of text per page vary<lb/>Vellum and paper, 214 pages<lb/>Size: 230mm x 168mm x 58mm<lb/>Binding: wooden board<lb/>Text in black ink, the beginnig of each section (guba'e) is in red.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of one quire of eight leaves, five quiries of ten leaves each, and two quires of fourteen leaves each, one quire additional of six leaves.</physdesc><container id="aspace_fe6f0e4df16fd2d63924f5336965f3b9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_0d2e5a85714fdaeb7edd2496fb0c3d0c"><head>Provenance</head><p>Hayele Mariam is the owner (p. ??)</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_237010bd1122bcdcf3223f0a2062a7de"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Commentary on the Gospel of Mathew and Mark. Most of the text is in abbreviated form. The purpose of the manuscript is to serve as a pneumatic or reference book for the 'andem' student trying to memorize the whole text of the gospels.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref120_cfe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Mazemura Dawit,?alota nabiyat, Mahalya Mahaley,Weddasé Maryam, Anqasa Berhan<lb/> Uniform title: Psalter<lb/> Title (English): Psalter, Old and New Testament canticles, Song of Songs, Praise of Mary, and The Gate of Light.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Late 19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c00deb8ad93bdc8523d28972d7508a82" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Psalms and the canticles are written in one column per page and 22 lines of text per page. Praise of Mary and Gate of Light are written in two columns.<lb/>Vellum, 382 pages<lb/>Size: 154 mm x 93 mm x 52 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards<lb/>The majority of the manuscript is composed of seven quires of twelve leaves each.<lb/>Text is in black ink. The opening verse of the chapters of the Psalter, the first word of the prayers from Praise of Mary and Gate of Light, and the name of the Virgin Mary are in red ink.<lb/>Illustrations p. 2, 3</physdesc><container id="aspace_1283babfb52e47713ec71db960f41eab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref122_k31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Dersana Mahyawi, ?alota Kidan<lb/> Uniform title: Homily and Office Prayer<lb/> Title (English): Homily of the Savior and Office Prayer.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3635ee369fb772958faf2fcb3c006987" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: two columns, the majority of the manuscript is eighteen lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 210 pages<lb/>Size: 212 mm x 169 mm x 50 mm<lb/>Binding: Wooden board covered with sewn khaki fabric and khaki handle<lb/>Most of the manuscript is composed of quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>Text in black ink but the opening of prayers and the name of Christ is in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_a5ccc4a77bcae4450ac52855e03bd731" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_57db28b3058117d0b4875f4cd69aa083"><head>Provenance</head><p>The first owner is Waleda Takela Hayemanot; but the second owner, Gabera Mika'el, cancelled the previous owner's name and inserted his own name and his wife's name Amata Mika'el (pp. 265).</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref125_7iv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Arede'et<lb/> Uniform title: Prayer book<lb/> Title (English): The Book of the Disciples.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1900s.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f665748d92d088dcdb96dcffc2fbc5e4" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 88 pages.<lb/>One column of text per page, 17 lines of text per page.<lb/>Size: 132 mm x 89 mm x 32 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards and string.<lb/>Text is in black ink, the beginning of each prayer and Christ's name are in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of four quires of ten leaves each and one quire of four leaves.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_3e370a2805820bfd89b80e276ba0db60" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_74fea3a8a07d617b39c9e115d28a37c0"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The Book of the Disciples is the Christian version of a book also used by the Beta Israel (Falasha or Ethiopian Jewish) community. It narrates how Jesus told his disciples his hidden names.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref128_c49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): A'emada Mesetir, Ra'eya Barok<lb/> Uniform title: Dogma (doctrine) of the church, Catechism of the Ethiopian Church<lb/> Title (English): The Pillars of Mystery, The Vision of Baruch.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1900s.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6de2c70013eb65ef0f8d38cdf9c83c42" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: pp.1-22 one column per page, pp. 23-138 two columns,14 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 138 pages<lb/>Binding: wooden board<lb/>Size: 194 mm x 123mm x 45mm<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each chapter, divine names, and church fathers names in red ink.<lb/>Manuscript is composed of seven quires of ten leaves each.</physdesc><container id="aspace_5dabe40f4909e1be76c04fe54d7ba8c3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_91a855522b888363c56efb8bbedeab48"><head>Biography</head><p>The Pillars of Mystery is a very important doctrinal book in the Ethiopian Orthodox Church. It is the summery of the faith of the Orthodox church and the basis of the systematic theology of the church. Based on the Nicene Creed it presents the faith of the Orthodox fathers. The manuscript is the early Amharic translation of the Ge'ez text. The Vision of Baruch is one of five books attributed to Baruch, the scribe of the Prophet Jeremiah. The Vision of Baruch is also called The Fifth Baruch or The Ethiopic Apocalypse of Baruch, also used by the Ethiopian Jewish (Beta Israel) community. For a detailed discussion about the Beta Israel/Falasha version, see Leslau's Falasha Antology (1951).</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_c5863a191777bb758b9832695eeaef8d"><head>Provenance</head><p>Bedlu Wolde Mika'el's seven generations are listed (p.118).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_80073d016d2280ca02e81f3c7fcdc1f1"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The Pillars of Mystery is the discussion of the teaching of the the mystery of the trinity, the incarnation, baptism, holy communion, and the resurrection of the dead. It is in the format of questions and answers from the Old and New Testaments and also from the patristic writings. The second book, The Vision of Baruch, is the Christian rather than Jewish version of the Ethiopic Apocalypse of Baruch. When the Angel Sutu'el took Baruch to Heaven, he saw the punishment of sinners and the reward of the just.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref133_3yb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Qeddasé Maryam, Kidan, Malke'a Madehané Alam, Malek'a Mika?él, Malek'a Edom<lb/> Uniform title:Anaphora, Images of the Saints<lb/> Title (English): Anaphora of St. Mary, Office Prayer, Image of the Savior of the World, Image of St. Michael, Image of Edom.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 32</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1900s?.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6c72d9387b7c78d2d7e6aafb6caf6a73" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column of text per page, 14 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 178 pages<lb/>Size: 116 mm x 83 mm x 42 mm<lb/>Binding: Wooden boards<lb/>Text in black ink. Angels' and saints' names and the beginning of prayers are in red ink.<lb/>Some border designs; no other illustrations.<lb/>Quires?</physdesc><container id="aspace_703b785a28eddc21bf3d090a8a3d1bad" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_9559d1b1fb14b85db978569562c2a6d9"><head>Biography</head><p>In the Fasting of the Assumption especially, it is common to read the Anaphora of St. Mary. Listening to the commentaries on this Anaphora of St. Mary and also the Praise of Mary are at the center of the mass and private devotion.</p></bioghist></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref136_b5z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Tamahesanku … Giyorgis<lb/> Uniform title: Prayer book<lb/> Title (English): I Beseech George (Supplication to St. George).</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1900s.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_69c04a1bf8e48389e8687e132c894bc5" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: two columns per page, with 13 lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum, 92 pages<lb/>Size: 147 mm x 105 mm x 7 mm<lb/>Binding: Without cover, but string binding<lb/>The manuscript is composed of four quires of ten leaves and one quire of six leaves.<lb/>Text is in black ink with the names of saints in red ink.<lb/>Several notes in the upper margin of the pages serve as captions for the illustrations of the martyrdom of St. George, but some of the explanations and the images don't match. Probably the captions were written first and the illustrations done later.<lb/>Twenty-three illustrations of scenes from the saint's life. Most in black ink, some in pencil. descriptive data: Text in black ink, the name of the saint in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of Ten leaves each</physdesc><container id="aspace_7f8dff3c225c9411bb12f1b5e28894b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_a96a7057378fdfc4537c72b8390a9fbd"><head>Biography</head><p>Based on the hagiography of St. George, the author mentions the passion of the saint and asks for the protection of the martyr. Following each prayer, there is a list of hidden names which have magical power.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cddb9da8b40ccd1dffab3928667687ed"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The manuscript contains prayers or supplications to St. George.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref140_des" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?elota Kidan; Temehereta Hebu'at,;Malk'a Maryam; Malk'a Iyesus; Malk'a Giyorgis; Sayefa Sellasé;QedaseMareyam; Malek'a Sellasé;Malk'a Takela Hayemanot; Malk'a Medehane Alem.<lb/> Uniform title: Images of the Saints<lb/> Title (English): Office Prayer, Mystagogia, Binding of Demons, Image of Mary, Image of Jesus, Image of George, Sword of Trinity, Anaphora of St. Mary, Image of Trinity, Image of St. Takela Haymanot, Image of Medehane Alem.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 34</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1874-1926.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_d62b797c9f0c2ca7a8ca8269bce06b70" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: two columns of text, 15 lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum and paper, 432 pages<lb/>Size: 155 mm x 115 mm x 59 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards with stamped red leather. In leather case with strap (very typical case).<lb/>The manuscript is composed of nine quires of ten leaves each, seven quires of twelve leaves each. The remaining four quires have five, six, nine, eleven,and fourteen leaves each.<lb/>The text is in black ink; the names of God, angels, and saints, including the scribes and the owners, and the first line of each book, are in red ink.<lb/>Pp. 323-432 in paper leaves, the rest of the manuscript in vellum<lb/>No portraits but geographic drawings as borders.</physdesc><container id="aspace_9343fe5d6a852acae166e7be4f9ea9c2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_32124d267676c975b1bddb65c7622dd9"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of the manuscript is Gabera Walede and his wife Askala Mareyam (pp. 269). The second owner is Walda Meskel (pp. 141).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_02032cc607266e4b8e0b6f441ac9d78a"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The manuscript includes the Office Prayer and Mystagogia prayers which, according to church tradition, the apostles received from Jesus Christ after his resurrection. It also includes 'malek' or images of Jesus and the saints.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref144_irg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Arganon<lb/> Uniform title: Hymns for St. Mary<lb/> Title (English): Arganon (Praise) of Mary.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 35</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">16th c.-17th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6ce3a5b9950559d344eb4001b9b81027" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns per page, 18 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 256 pages<lb/>Size: 222mm x 190mm x 80mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards<lb/>Texts in black ink, the beginning of each prayer and St. Mary's name is in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of eight and ten leaves each.<lb/>Illustrations?????</physdesc><container id="aspace_8756c3de62054b9cc3d41c5b5aab80cf" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_13ac6f43f8f63413e02dc5bd1910fa6c"><head>Biography</head><p>The manuscript contains one of the writingd of Abba Giyorgis of Gascha or Segla in Ethiopia. Following the advent of the Book of the Miracles of St. Mary, Abba Giyorgis was vigorously promoting the cult of St. Mary. In Arganon he intertwined biblical and patristic writings of the church with his new Mariology.</p></bioghist></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref147_667" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Wanegel Zayohanes<lb/> Uniform title: New Testament (Gospel)<lb/> Title (English): Gospel of John.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 36</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ada646f7ce6a1ddfb4be5405c298a745" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 208 pages</physdesc><physdesc id="aspace_0ee6e2926c4c2b5c1c607301a69aa500" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns of text, 17 lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum, 208 pages<lb/>Size: 142 mm x 100 mm x 47 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards with a leather cover<lb/>Text in black ink, some names and titles of the chapters are in red.<lb/>No illustrations.<lb/>Quires?</physdesc><container id="aspace_66ed30a342707f450418bf7699b3d7d0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_6f1d7ab7b08b32c924ca8de1b142efc5"><head>Biography</head><p>The fourth gospel is the most copied book in Ethiopic manuscript collections. Apart from its prominent place in the church, the Gospel of John is the starting point in traditional church school for reading church books and developing Ge'ez vocabulary.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_9cf89eed66099f06d7df8590feb32b5e"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of the manuscript is a woman by the name of Walata Berehan (Daughter of light) (p. 204)</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref152_kkh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Dersana Raguel, Malek'a Raguel,Malek'a Giyorgis<lb/> Uniform title: Homily on St Raguel, Image of Saints<lb/> Title (English): Homily on St Raguel, Image of Raguel, Image of George.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 37</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_78b7a01b06f1308c3326f1b75534b40d" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column of text per page, 11 lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum, 94 pages<lb/>Size: 118mm x 88mm x 19mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards with stamped leather cover<lb/>Text in black ink. The beginning of the text and the saint's name is in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript composed in six quires of one quire of 2 leaves two quires of 8 leaves and three qiures of 10 leaves.</physdesc><container id="aspace_c000e8a4f822e3cd4ade88366c03bb9d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref154_60g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Malek'a Maryam, Malek'a Eyasus<lb/> Uniform title: Image of Mary, Image of Jesus<lb/> Title (English): Image of Mary, Image of Jesus.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 38</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0add23b5b73de9a10d42d77c2308c2c1" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column of text per page, 13 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 76 pages<lb/>Size: 115 mm x 85 mm x 32 mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of six and eight leaves each.<lb/>Binding: wooden boards with string. The back board is broken.<lb/>Texts in black ink, the beginning of each prayer and Christ's name are in red ink.<lb/>Some border designs, but no other illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_150a1ea536f971ccccdfc90f779b4376" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref156_4ao" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Sa'atat<lb/> Uniform title: Horologium<lb/> Title (English): The Hours.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 39</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_da888aa18be0a74f3b6280aaafe0615e" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column per page, mostly 13 lines of text per page, but it varies.<lb/>Vellum. 160 pages<lb/>Size: 110 mm x 85 mm x 40 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards<lb/>Text in black ink, some names and beginning of each prayer in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of ten quires of 8 leaves each.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_4ac4e643b20a88cf3f5120012db20a0d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_0637204481de5b1db81d878809e0b193"><head>Provenance</head><p>The latter owner is listed as "Priest Mogas" (p. 152).</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref159_2eu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Wanegel Zayohans<lb/> Uniform title: Gospel of John<lb/> Title (English): Gospel of John.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 40</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e27091f60f5d50d78d949a7ea4ab68a4" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: two columns per page, 17 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 150 pages<lb/>Size: 150 mm x 110 mm x 43 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards with stamped leather<lb/>The manuscript is composed of five quires of ten leaves each, two quires of eight leaves each, and one quire of nine leaves.<lb/>Text is in black ink; the beginning of the section (me'eraf) and the name of Jesus are in red ink.<lb/>Illustrations on pp. 2 and 149, and decorated borders elsewhere.</physdesc><container id="aspace_10504a18a0cae61d06764a28442babf4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_d6c099222a9b8d4c57738d3ded2e8ac0"><head>Biography</head><p>Part of the canon of Ethiopian Orthodox Tewahedo Church, the Gospel of John is the most popular gospel. It is part of the curriculum in the early stages of traditional church education.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_46edab82336293520656b15eecc2822d"><head>Provenance</head><p>The name of the owner has been deleted. The second owner is listed as Kidana Mareyam (p. 146). Also, with a crude hand are added the words, "This book is for Ato Gabera Mikael" (p. 149).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_f2dfa582c895762632049244e523bb1e"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The Ethiopic version of the Gospel of John has special characteristics concerning the method of dividing chapters. Ethiopian scholars divided the gospel into more chapters to help students to memorize the gospel with its commentary.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref164_snf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Tasea'elotata Zenahomu la'abew Manakosat Gebesaweyan<lb/> Uniform title: Monastic book<lb/> Title (English): Philoxenus or Questions on the Sayings of the Egyptian Fathers.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 41</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1700s or 1800s.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_022a862fb679d488b178b1e24dd3c5b0" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 216 pages<lb/>Two columns per page, 20 lines of text per page.<lb/>Size: 190mm x 170mm x 56mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed 12 quires of one quire of 2 leaves one quire of eight leaves ten quires of ten leaves<lb/>Text in black ink. The beginning of each chapter (each part) and also the names of saints and church fathers in red ink.<lb/>Binding: wooden board (broken)</physdesc><container id="aspace_5a9692f66d83ba64c5d1ceed834f9147" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_75e4399a7ff2ad4105aefe5348dc37e2"><head>Biography</head><p>According to the tradition of the church, and as it says in the introductory part of the text, this book was written by Philoxenus, Bishop of Mabbug or Hierapolis (modern Aleppo of Syria), one of the defenders of the non-Chalcedonian (Jacobite) movement. It is based on the collection of The Sayings of the Desert Fathers. Some modern historians reject the idea that Philoxenus authored this book and attribute it to Dadiso Qatrayas, a Nestorian monk of today's Qatar. For more on this debate, see the "Filkeseyus" entry in Encyclopedia Aethiopica, vol. ? (Hamburg, 19??).</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_bac76c82e9b699425640f2fecfc4a32e"><head>Provenance</head><p>The name of the previous owner is erased and written over with the name Aseqa Mika'el (P. 5 and 212).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_ca562c5623c812291b3470cd54d71ac8"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The formal text is accompanied by extensive notes in the margin in Amharic, called 'anedemta' commentary, which serves as a reminder to the reader of commentaries about the specific words or passages next to which the notes are written.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref169_ur6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ma?ehafa Qeddasé<lb/> Uniform title: Qedasé<lb/> Title (English): Book of Missal.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 42</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1874-1913.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6aaaaefb19f7933b1ddc155149133360" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 184 pages</physdesc><physdesc id="aspace_fbdba95f135b71a840e8dfc95696159d" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns per page, text lines per page varies.<lb/>Vellum, 184 pages<lb/>Size: 246 mm x 185 mm x 79 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards and string<lb/>Text in black ink. Beginning of each prayer and anaphora with instructions for Deacon and Priest in red ink. Includes musical notation.<lb/>No illustrations.<lb/>Quires????</physdesc><container id="aspace_d1cd20431aa293a0d514d4db8884b53e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_191a52119d375f1fccec28dd44bca441"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The manuscript contains office prayer, Liton, supplications, and seven anaphoras. The anaphoras included in this manuscript are used frequently in liturgical services.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref173_uxs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Malek'a Giyorgis, Malek'a Mika?él,<lb/> Uniform title: Malek'e<lb/> Title (English): Image of George, Image of Michael.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 43</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_daf839688174d137ee718b707a878ca5" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: one column per page, average thirteen lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum, 68 pages.<lb/>Size: 120 mm x 90 mm x 18 mm<lb/>Text is in black ink. The beginning of each prayer and the name of the saints are in red ink.<lb/>The manuscript is composed in four quires of eight leaves each.</physdesc><container id="aspace_9c12f5b27937578fbe33f02bff2c1f67" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_c1d377f3d0bdff93e5ba277afcdcd20b"><head>Biography</head><p>These two 'maleke' are the most popular prayers among the priests and some educated churchmen, especially Dabeteras. The manuscript has very interesting miniatures of various saints and demons. These drawings are used for magical purposes.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_107a0e0ef35849169bdc8e0192c270ef"><head>Provenance</head><p>On p. 4, the owner wrote in crude handwriting "By the authority of Peter and Paul, be cursed. This book belongs to Aleqa Bezabeh Kassa." But on p. 34 the owner is mentioned as Gebra Mareyam.</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref177_g2k" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Qeddasé Maryam<lb/> Uniform title: Qedasé<lb/> Title (English): Anaphora of St. Mary.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 44</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_53c7939252226457e07973f404b4972d" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, eleven lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum, 84 pages<lb/>Binding is wooden board.<lb/>Size: 112 mm x 80 mm x 30 mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of four quires of eight leaves each and two quires of four leaves each.<lb/>Text is in black ink. The instruction for priests and deacons and the name of St. Mary are in red ink.<lb/>Decorative borders but no other illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_f343450b5fda3a638991e5a24a3c70b4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_c93ff075298298135efcdf2ce99f1614"><head>Biography</head><p>The small size of the manuscript indicates that it was used for private prayer.In the Fasting of the Assumption especially, it is common to read the Anaphora of St. Mary. Listening to the commentaries on this anaphora and Praise of Mary are at the center of the liturgy and private devotion.</p></bioghist></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref180_58y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ta'amra Maryam<lb/> Uniform title: Miracles of St. Mary, Miracles of Jesus, Bible<lb/> Title (English): Miracles of St. Mary, Miracles of Jesus, Readings from the Bible.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 45</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1889-1913.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_155d796fc070964c403d4dda4c6fd85b" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 176 pages<lb/>Two columns per page, lines of text per page vary.<lb/>Wooden boards without leather; with string binding. In leather case with strap.<lb/>Size: 278 mm x 220 mm x 55 mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of ten quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>Text in black ink. The beginning of each miracle and the name of St. Mary are in red ink.<lb/>Decorative border illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_cf3425bcb4f512341ffefe0a2816b676" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref182_u4o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta bareya; ?alota Mastem<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayers against Epilepsy, Prayers of Mastem.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 46</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9d7b5e9dfc4b81454c41b4dabaa27acc" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, scroll<lb/>One column<lb/>Size: 2245 mm x 110 mm<lb/>Text in black ink. Some words and divine and owner's names in red ink.<lb/>Illustrations: two images in ink and color of angels and one magical drawing.</physdesc><container id="aspace_e12cc75ab2e9a05fafe06dbac5c69bd7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_e2ae74efc2b1bb6b545204ac2ab75a16"><head>Biography</head><p>A magical scroll with magical prayers against epilepsy and also prayers for the binding of demons.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_06596a694684d185fe37c0630d2d849f"><head>Provenance</head><p>The scroll was written for Walata Eyasus (her secular name is Berenash).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_e23fb0b972f089d68e716b04ea1a9766"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>A magical prayer for the binding (or drowning) of demons. The prayers for the binding of demons is for seven days, followed by horoscope analysis of the owner and her magical hidden name.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref187_o7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Lefafa ?deq<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Bandlet of Righteousness.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 47</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c286c45cdeb74f9f5211402d5aeceee1" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, 9 lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 68 pages<lb/>Size: 83 mm x 60 mm x 24 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards and the manuscript is in a leather case with a strap so it can be placed around the neck.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of four quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>Text is in black ink. The beginning of each prayer and the name of saints are in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_1f56df71d482ef43e1c3d429f8aa2d7d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_d756c299cb0c351eed8147979968dcf9"><head>Biography</head><p>It is a typical magical book that is popular among Ethiopian Orthodox nuns as a talisman. The nuns and older women put this manuscript around their necks. It also is put on the necks of children and animals when they become sick.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_446423aa4ad3721d357fd97dad96d896"><head>Provenance</head><p>Amata Mareyam and Walata Kidan are the owners of the manuscript (both of them are women).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_d4ceced6fd995cc9a19d40fb37bcbac9"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Like the Egyptian Book of the Dead, this book is also filled with the prayers of the soul on the way to heaven.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref192_ro6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Salamta, Nagara Haymanot, Malek'a Gabre'él, Mahlet ?egé, Saqoqawa Denegel<lb/> Uniform title: Maleke<lb/> Title (English): Greetings, part of The Beauty of Creation, Image of St. Gabriel, Canticle of the Flower, Lamentation of the Virgin, Greetings of St. Michael.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 48</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">119th.c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b49fe61c00031caba4f7a7214c3cf60a" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns per page, twenty three lines of text per page.<lb/>Binding: wooden boards with no leather cover, string binding<lb/>Velum, 102 pages<lb/>Size: 158 mm x 92 mm x 25 mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of six quires of eight leaves each and one quire of four leaves.<lb/>Text is in black ink and the beginning of the book and each prayer is in red ink.<lb/>Color illustrations of saints.</physdesc><container id="aspace_63877312076b35b234ca4e7622a0e384" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref194_04u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Marbabeta Salomon<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer of King Solomon for Catching Demons (Marbabta Solomon).</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 49</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_da5f660d94dc3efc1a7f5b5d080861c5" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, Scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with three strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1495 mm x 86 mm<lb/>The text is in black ink. The beginging of each prayer and the name of the owner and dvine names are in red ink.<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_7c93cf4dabfa552249be7abed77c0c0d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_0dd157d0a75e8bbe105d683d9b7f15ae"><head>Provenance</head><p>Aqba Giyorgis is the owner</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_fc0f1025464851e9447101daf5a336a2"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The scroll contains the magical prayer of King Solomon for catching demons. Marbabeta Solomon literally means "Net of Solomon." Healing images are common in most magical prayers. The prayer in this manuscript protects the owner from the hand of his enemies, from evil spirits which come as lions or tigers, and from other diseases.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref198_6k3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Marbabeta Salomon, ?alota Susnyos<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer of King Solomon for Catching of Demons, Prayer of Susneyos.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 50</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">18th. C.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_13a4451e73aad5e769ecbc5c5fcb9a64" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, Scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1600 mm x 115 mm<lb/>Text in black ink. Names of the saints, the beginning of each prayer, the names of the owners are in red ink<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_5b29a11704c9c2d4ad311cf46432c154" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_5f3601ece439b0a4fcbda210ef70ece7"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owners of the scrolls are Walata Muse and Askala Mareyam (both of them are women).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_37b239007dcbedc5072074454cf427bb"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer attributed to King Solomon for catching demnons. The scroll also includes the well-known magical prayer of Susneyos.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref202_9lk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta Ma?esaromu la- Agan?ent<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayer<lb/> Title (English): Prayer about binding of Demons. Prayer of St. Susneyos.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 51</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_34c8b491a919ebea00468d32e492a28a" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, Scroll<lb/>Size: 1685 mm x 95 mm<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with three strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>The text is in black ink. The beginning of each prayer, divine names, and owner's name are in red ink.<lb/>Some illustrations</physdesc><container id="aspace_ca0147ff8cacf5ca3e8887ae7079656d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_86cc1cd6a642263a5ad9e5f4c0079902"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner's name is listed as Walata Mareyam</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_866842d7051b7f1695691c0942d4b23c"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer for binding of the demons. The Prayer of Susneyos is a well-known magical prayer against children's diseases.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref206_oc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta Ma?esara Agan?ent<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer for the Binding of Demons, Prayer of Susneyos.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 52</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th. C.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_d76d3ff384a5d89e19fd870327e71c85" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with three strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1515 mm x 95 mm<lb/>Text in black ink. Saints and owners' names and the beginning of each prayer are in red ink.<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_d10928f543e0e27e5869b1eddd395f67" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_9736177a7f68bac08664f8448c515c79"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of this scroll is Wallata Eyasus.</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref209_6l8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta Ma?esara Agan?ent<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer for the Binding of Demons.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 53</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">18th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3292c90fd17f1aaf0615144f901f7bfa" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with two strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1240 mm x 90 mm<lb/>Text in black ink. Saints and owners' names and the beginning of each prayer are in red ink.<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_c53718cf3f014d72bd004c68762c67f5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_0d8e70dcbdf6c665773a8df61785cf73"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of this scroll is Waleda Tenesa'e (Lagase).</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref212_vn9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta Ma?esara Agan?ent<lb/> Uniform title: Magical Prayer<lb/> Title (English): Prayer for the binding of demons.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 54</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th. C.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c97771640960f00fbf6b90b94fd87e74" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, Scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with two strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1864 mm x 100 mm<lb/>Text in black ink. The beginning of prayer and the name of the owner are in red ink.<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_4001db824a9eee4183274b60781accab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_cba199cead76f142e724dbe6e7a0e4d3"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of the scroll is Amata Egzi'abeher or Belaynesh (the secular name) and Walata Mareyam</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_e52278f7a3e9363e2ee7be724908b9ea"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer against demons of blood and miscarriage.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref216_w33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta ma'esaromu la'aganenet<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer for the binding of demons.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 55</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">18th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_bf99fb10278b1f329dc50130169b437b" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with two strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1815 mm x 108 mm<lb/>Text in black ink, the beginning of each prayer and the name of the owner are in red ink.</physdesc><container id="aspace_a02b39b8bd8cb7a0e655b5302ae6cc4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_eedc26409a3e3166d8354e8a8debbc37"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of the scroll is Zawaleda Mareyam.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_4f5cde7424a9b3372e34bb52e12f21bc"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayers for the binding of demons and against ayenat and eplipsy, which confuse the mind. The scroll also has a magical prayer attributed to King Solomon.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref220_4tl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?enta Ma'esara bareya walégéwon<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayer for the Binding of Bareya and Legion.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 56</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Early 19th. C.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_cc903f939c74d24ddd9256fd27b5108c" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with four strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Size: 1930 mm x 105 mm<lb/>Text in black ink, the beginning of each prayer is in red ink.<lb/>Some illustrations</physdesc><container id="aspace_a2c8b67bb7bd5bdb8633a2f8c928c770" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_ee90e5cabf95d9c81f7a602f0d4e148a"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of the scroll is Walata Heyewat or Tabayen (Tabayen is the secular name).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_6c590bd73f29625e0ee95ce67c3243df"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer for a woman (probably mother of infant baby) to protect from epilepsy and miscarriage. Also includes well-known magical prayer to protect children from various diseases.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref224_8dl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot ba?eneta Ayena tela<lb/> Uniform title: Magical prayers<lb/> Title (English):Prayers against Evil Eye.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 57</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a40b40dd16ab4493726930bed2351b99" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, scroll<lb/>Layout: one column on a scroll composed with three strips of vellum in magic scroll format.<lb/>Text is in black, special names in red ink.<lb/>Size: 1725 mm x 100 mm<lb/>Some illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_2260cbc53379dae7a8a3534290d7631b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_770a00bde20c56cd14882b206cf3d5c4"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner of the manuscript is Eheta Mika'el Awaga (a woman).</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_21630943c563a7fa3e4284a853823e76"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Magical prayer against evil eye and different diseases. The scroll contains part of the first chapter of the Gospel of John</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref228_qf8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?alot s'elat wa'astabequ'ot<lb/> Uniform title: Collection of Prayers<lb/> Title (English): Prayers, Petitions, and Supplications.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 58</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c68a3e768156882c4b12c53555dfd23f" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: Two columns per page, seventeen lines of text per page.<lb/>Vellum, 338 pages<lb/>Size: 180 mm x 170 mm x 75 mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards with no leather cover; string binding.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of one quire of four leaves each, two quires of eight leaves each, one quire of twelve leaves, fourteen quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>The text is in black ink. The beginning of each prayer and the name of the owner is in red ink.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_5ff76bf99003f8d7ed863039b03e4efe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_fdc65bb0c5ed1a763e61ea72dd7439fc"><head>Provenance</head><p>The original owner's name was erased repeatedly and replaced with the last owner, "Kefla Mareyam" (passim, p. 336)</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_0ce3c67d4107ce83efc20f2f20774589"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Collection of prayers attributed to known church fathers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref232_qwc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ma?ehafa Ziq, Malek'a Sellasé<lb/> Uniform title: Church Hymns<lb/> Title (English): Book of Ziq, Image of the Trinity.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 59</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ac877c1ae7e69dba1eb1885ee5066566" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column of text, fifteen or sixteen lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 176 pages<lb/>Size: 130 mm x 100 mm x 36 mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards, in loose sewn cloth cover, in leather case with strap.<lb/>Text is in black ink, with the names of people and the divine in red ink. With musical notation.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of two quires of eight pages, eight quires of ten pages.<lb/>No illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_c170f61e72ea37e188af73cf0b72e1d9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_1dbc0a504cb8aed46cfcf3d27c7468c7"><head>Provenance</head><p>The owner's name is erased on p. 175, but elsewhere retained as Takela Haymanot Waleda Mareyam (p. 158)</p></acqinfo></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref235_nxf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): ?oma Degwa<lb/> Uniform title: Deguwa<lb/> Title (English): Hymns for Lent.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 60</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_526e4693cc02654af125336477d5c563" label="General Physical Description note"><lb/>Vellum, 232 pages<lb/>Layout: Two columns per page, twenty lines of text per page<lb/>Binding: Wooden boards with leather case<lb/>Size: 180mm x 137mm x 47mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of two quires of four leaves , one quire of eight leaves , two quires of twelve leaves and eight quires of ten leaves each.<lb/>The text is in black ink. The name of each section of the song is in red ink</physdesc><container id="aspace_cb223e9889022fc65e58498843048eab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_0a88b57e5c37682f8bab30e4869cf4eb"><head>Biography</head><p>The manuscript contains Soma Deguwa, the Lenten hymns of St. Yared the Musician.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_89abd283a7a388396eaa6ce28f9ca049"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Hymns for the Lenten season. St.Yared the Musician, the author of these hymns, divided the Lenten season into eight weeks. Almost all of the hymns are about the teaching and miracles of Jesus. The hymns discuss the teaching of Jesus in the Synagogue, his cleaning of the temple, his miracle of healing paralysis, his parable of the faithful servant, the discussion with Nicodimus, his teaching about his second coming, his glorious entrance into Jerusalem, his last days at Jerusalem, and his crucifixion.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref239_4ra" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Malek'a Mareyam, Malek'a Madehane Alam, Malek'a Mika?él, Malek'a Gaberél, Malek'a Giyorgis<lb/> Uniform title: Praise for Saints (Malek'e)<lb/> Title (English): Image of Mary, Image of the Savior of the World, Image of St. Michael, Image of St.Gabriel, Image of St. George.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 61</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">20 c.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9ca754c40477198d1c149d438786647a" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: two columns per page, twelve lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 134 pages<lb/>Binding: wooden boards with red stamped leather cover; inside leather case with strap<lb/>Size: 128 mm x 95 mm x 32 mm<lb/>The manuscript is composed of eight quires of eight leaves each. One quire has four blank leaves.<lb/>The text is in black ink. The beginning of each 'malk' and 'salamta' and the name of the saints are in red ink.<lb/>Decorative border, but no illustrations.</physdesc><container id="aspace_3235d3b161e0ca69d23f586720f7fe92" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref241_u4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Masehafa Ziq<lb/> Uniform title: Church Hymns<lb/> Title (English): The Book of Ziq.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 62</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">19th. C.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c53aeff00097d3cd404c1cd587bb75e5" label="General Physical Description note">Layout: One column per page, fifteen lines of text per page<lb/>Vellum, 284 pages<lb/>Binding is wooden board.<lb/>Size: 143mm x 105mm x 75<lb/>The manuscript is composed of seventeen quires of eight leaves.<lb/>The text is in black ink. The name of each greeting ('salamta') and saints' names are in red ink.<lb/>Musical notations throughout, above each line of the hymn.<lb/>Illustrations: none</physdesc><container id="aspace_0e4d17fa7b6c794078aa5aaebf72b6ad" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_7e318e0f6c65d8688b58d698ae4bd840"><head>Biography</head><p>Authored by various Ethiopian scholars, mostly from the Gondar region. The hymns are sung following the 'malek' image assigned to be sung that day. Based on this interpretation, some scholars say that "Ziq" means "below," in Amharic "'zeq belo." Dillmann suggested that "ziq" derived from "zarziq," which means "condensed or collected works," see Kay Kaufman Shelemay and Peter Jeffery.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5c8478f95b04b145a7592771ba6229a7"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Ziq is the collection of hymns praising God, Mary, and the saints. Following each malek assigned for that day, the ziq hymns will follow. Most of the ziq hymns come from other liturgical books, saints' lives, or the bible.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref245_vpq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Dawit ?alota Nabiyat,Weddasé Maryam, Anqa?a Berhan,Malek'a Gaber?él<lb/> Uniform title: Psalter<lb/> Title (English): Psalter and Canticles of New and Old Testaments Praise of Mary, The Gate of the Light; Image of Gabriel.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 63</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">17th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0bd55b353c5a5f160fce70a37d1f5466" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 346 Pages<lb/>Layout: one column on vellum; 19 lines of text per page. Praise of Mary and Gate of the light in two columns 19 lines of text per page.<lb/>Pages 346 (started from page 17 assuming the first missing quire is eight leaves.<lb/>Size: 140mm x 120 x 78mm<lb/>Binding: wooden boards<lb/>Text in black ink, some names and titles of the chapters are in red.<lb/>The manuscript is composed of quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>The front board is broken and sewn.<lb/>The first quire ( pp1-16) is missing.<lb/>Parts of one quire (including pp. 313 on the Praises of Mary) are inserted incorrectly in the manuscript. They appear earlier than they should. This misplacement probably happened in Ethiopia when the very old manuscript was rebound.</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c8be67297ce53c8d469416f3a944ef3"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Collection of Psalms, biblical canticles, and also praise hymns about Mary (attributed to St. Ephram of Syria [400s] and St. Yared of Ethiopia [600s])</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref248_wg2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Title (Romanized): Ra'eya Maryam, Lefafa ?edqe, Ta'amra Mika'el<lb/> Uniform title: Gadel<lb/> Title (English): The Lives of Abba Zamika'el and Gabra Krestos, The Vision of Mary, The Bandlet of Righteousness, The Miracle of St. Michael.</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript number: 64</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">late 16th.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_97497a738b8fd4fd1bcf6df799abcf59" label="General Physical Description note">Vellum, 206 pages, 103ff<lb/>Two columns, eighteen lines of text per page (the Miracle of St. Michael is 24 lines per page).<lb/>Size: 178mm x 160mm x 49mm<lb/>Binding is wooden boards with stamped leather back.<lb/>The majority of the manuscript (Gadela Zamika'el and Gadela Gabera Keresetose) is composed of quires of eight leaves each.<lb/>The text is in black ink; the name of God, angels, and saints, including the scribes and the owners, and the first line of each book, is in red ink.<lb/>The books of Gadela Abba Zemikael and Gadela Gabera Keresetos are written in the same hand.<lb/>Colophons:<lb/>ff. 53, is a supplement to the hagiography called Salameta (greeting) to Gabera Keresetos<lb/>ff. 101-102, is a list of the abbots who came before and after Zemikael (Aregawi) written in a second hand.<lb/>ff.78-79 Bandlet of Righteousness is written in raqiq ( small hand writing)<lb/>Images:<lb/>f.1r, is a miniature representing Abba Zamika'el (Aragawi)<lb/>f.54 is a miniature of Gabera Keresetos surrounded by dogs and with white leprosy spots (very important early representation of leprosy)<lb/>f.1v is in English handwriting in ink and says " Taken from King Theodores arsenal [parts of word obscured] at Magdala after the fall of the place. 14th April 1868"</physdesc></did><bioghist id="aspace_d6c6434b9d0b4924f852caeaee54d6ed"><head>Biography</head><p>The Life of Abba Zemike'el is well known because of the subject of the book, Abba Zamike'el, who was the founder of the great monastery of Dabra Damo. He is one of the Nine Saints of the fifth century who started the monastic movement in Ethiopia. Since the foundation of Dabra Damo, which is located in the Tigray Province, Abba Zamike'el has been considered the father of Ethiopian monastic life. The most respected monastic leaders included Abba Eyasus Mo'a and Abba Takela Haymanot, who not only made their monastic vows at Dabra Damo, but also considered themselves as the heirs of Abba Zamike'el. The Life of Abba Zamike'el is a very important 'gadel' (hagiography) which tries to explain how the celebrated monastic leader came to Ethiopia and founded the famous monastery. The gadel tells the story of Abba Zamike'el, the fourth generation after Saint Anthony and Saint Makars. Zamike'el was the son of King Isaac and Queen Edna of Rome, but he fled from his royal palace, and went to Abba Pachomius, founder of the first communal monastery of the Christian faith, and Zamike'el went to Axum carried on the wings of the angel. The book also narrates his struggle with the great serpent, which was considered by the local people of Dabera Damo as a god. The snake submitted and then took Zamike'el to the top of the mountain, where Zamike'el founded the monastery of Dabra Damo. Then King Gabara Maskal, son of King Kaleb, visited Dabra Damo. There is also the visitation of St. Yered the musician. </p><p>The second book is about the life of St. Gabera Keresetose who is known in the rest of the world as St. Alexi. In Ethiopia, St Gabera Keresetose is the patron saint of the rejected and out-cast people. The uniqueness of this manuscript, as the late Professor Leslau and Professor Richard Pankhurst said, is the very beautiful miniature which sheds some light not only on medieval Ethiopian painting but also the attitude of people towards the victims of leprosy disease.</p></bioghist><acqinfo id="aspace_f87d9834c054ab74ce196a8e24b1f930"><head>Provenance</head><p>In f.31v, 50v, 51r, 78r, the scribe mentions the owner Wolda Mareyam. Adara Giyoregis, inserted his name above the name of Wolda Mareyam.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_56ec87073f2e0967a7f0dc762a24b7cb"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Compilation of important Ethiopian texts. Copied after 1632 (when the Portuguese were expelled). The first book in the compliation is the Life of Abba Zamika'el (Aragawi) discusses the life of Abba Zamika'el. He is one of the Nine Saints of the fifth century and a leader among those saints. Abba Zamika'el is the founder of the Dabra Damo monastery. The second book in the compliation is the Life of Gabera Keresetos, which describes the acetic life of Gabera Keresetos, the son of King Theodosius of Constantinople, and what happened after he ran away on his wedding night. The other books are, in order,The Vision of Mary, The Bandlet of Righteousness, The Miracle of St. Michael, for a total of five books.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
