<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt3f59q1gj/">exhi1656.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts</titleproper><titleproper>Finding aid for the Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts, 1492-1848 <num>LSC.1656</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Ali Anooshahr, with assistance from Laurel McPhee, Fall 2004; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Finding aid last modified 3 June 2016.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-04-18 14:03:38 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in <language>English.</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.1656</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(5 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1492/1848" type="inclusive">1492-1848</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b1a4f158a920a31a7c2d05fb122c0409" label="Abstract">Collection consists of Persian, Ottoman Turkish, Arabic, and Armenian manuscripts dating from 1492-1848. The collection includes bound manuscripts, scrolls, manuscript fragments, decorative book covers, and artifacts. Subjects include history, lexicography, belles-lettres, theology, and philosophy.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_562dd7d10536731efd840c767235ba9e">Portions of the collection stored off-site. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
<lb/>
Boxes 1-4 stored off-site at SRLF; box 5 in YRL Special Collections stacks.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="per">Persian</language>
,       <language langcode="ota" scriptcode="Arab">Turkish, Ottoman (1500-1928)</language>
,       <language langcode="ara" scriptcode="Arab">Arabic</language>
,       <language langcode="arm" scriptcode="Armn">Armenian</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz0008hs4j" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts (6 items)" xlink:type="simple">
    <daodesc><p>Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts (6 items)</p></daodesc>
  </dao>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_228cf7465eb3c1abc0e6c6fcb7db9acb">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2fa2e67a898df5865199e5acde8d5647">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c3d590c5164a09980b059516b70e74aa">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>In 1991, for a potential future exhibition, the majority of the items in this collection were selected from two other collection in the department: the Minasian Collection og Near Eastern Manuscripts (Collection 1147) and the Qayani Collection of Arabic and Persian Manuscripts (Collection 1053).</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_a507318efe00d5023d394a6337f2829f">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9942329963606533">9942329963606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_74b0c39f707ad23a6cbc905bfb340946">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts (Collection 1656). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d5c34c1c4295f4a41f2e51c87821ec56">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Ali Anooshahr, with assistance from Laurel McPhee, Fall 2004, in the Center For Primary Research and Training (CFPRT).</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_465cfe9c7775cfe0b06a46d21bac7bf5">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection consists of illustrated and illuminated manuscripts from the ?afawid, Ottoman, Qajar, and Timurid domains, illustrated Armenian scrolls, decorative lacquered book covers, and several artifacts. There are eight works of belles-lettres, including two royal correspondence handbooks (one Persian, one Ottoman Turkish); four works of a religious nature, including two Koran fragments and a brilliantly illuminated Koran in a Qajar lacquered binding; four works of history, including manuscript versions of unedited texts; and single volumes of lexicography, logic, and philosophy. Of particular scholarly interest is a version of the ninth section of Kemalpasazade's Histories of the Ottoman House (<title>Al-daftar al-tas? min al-dafatir al-marsuma bi al-Sulaymaniyya</title>), and <title>Mu?n al-Din Yazdi's Humayun nama, ya</title>, <title>Mavahib-i ilahi</title> (<title>Book of Humayun</title>, or, <title>Divine gifts</title>). The collection includes numerous fine examples of Nast? liq script, one striking example of Divani calligraphy, and many beautiful leaves demonstrating ornate Qajar illumination, illustration, and decoration techniques. Artifacts include embroidered purses and a leather book bag.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_48fd0111fc8189f0d801080d9245c0bc">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in the following series: <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered"><item>Manuscripts</item><item>Scrolls</item><item>Book covers and artifacts</item></list></p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1191e27fd667e0bc9ddc44cb63591400">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p><list type="marked">
<item><extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7779q44r" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Minasian Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts (Collection 1147) </extref>. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.</item>
<item><extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt100017xg" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Qayani Collection of Arabic and Persian Manuscripts (Collection 1053) </extref>. Available in the Department of Special Collections, UCLA.</item>
<item><extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7t1nc9bh" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Wellcome Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts (Collection 1148) </extref>. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.</item>
<item><extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8mw2npn/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Persian and Arabic manuscripts in Special Collections Catalog</extref> Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.</item></list></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <altformavail id="aspace_e813ebabfd4073cd2c96d611ac641c3b">
    <head>Online Items Available</head>
<p>Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online:
<extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz0008hs4j">Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts (6 items)</extref>.</p>  </altformavail>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">manuscripts (documents) -- Arab countries.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref12_tnw" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref13_cjl" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kanz al-lughat / Treasure of words</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1658</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4fa0662b139e7929123085f6076f0897" label="General Physical Description note">375 leaves : paper, ill. ; 212 × 120 (167 × 77) mm. bound to 217 × 124 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_cae3c8e17e59484e32e0d4df6b86ef9a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz00090qwn" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Kanz al-lughāt = Treasure of words " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Kanz al-lughāt = Treasure of words</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89f0241f82e26e5ca8ef27becd500162"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Persian dictionary of Koranic Arabic and Hadith terms. The author praises Sul?an Mu?ammad and his heir (2a) and calls them "The adornment of the Hall of the Mus?afawi lineage, and the decoration of the pride of the Murta?awi family," implying a Sayyid king, possibly ?afawid. If so, the named Sul?an would be Sul?an Mu?ammad Khudabandah father of Shah ?bbas, and the date of composition would fall between 1577-1586 CE.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Mu?ammad ibn ?bd al-Khaliq ibn Ma 'arif, fl. 16th cent?</item><item>Scribe: Ibn Abi Turab Mu?ammad Ibrahim (al-?usayn?)</item><item>Language: Text in Persian and Arabic</item><item>Origin: ?afawid Persia</item><item>Layout: Average of 21 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Written in fine nast? liq hand.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated title page.</item><item>Binding: Decorated red leather binding. Covers painted with portraits of youths; inside covers painted with partridges.</item><item>Additional description: Arabic terms and phrases in red. Marginalia. Occasional bleeding of red ink, particularly in the last third of the text; light brown staining and black ink stains on a number of leaves. Misspelled fore-edge title; spine title.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-3a: Preface;</item><item>ff. 3a-4b: Table of contents;</item><item>ff. 4b-375a: Twenty eight chapters according to the letters of the alphabet (alif to ya).</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref16_joh" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kalilah va Dimnah / Kalilah and Dimnah</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1787</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a07bf2d82089711620464c78e7017d9a" label="General Physical Description note">262 leaves : paper, ill. ; 211 × 148 mm. bound to 211 × 148 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_6825a72141662126a47c13d6a07cd243" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1c2e8a4b29e715624ad8077d337c8f7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Belles-lettres, also known as Kalilah va Dimnah, ya, Anvar-i Suhayli (Kalilah and Dimnah, or, Lights of Canopus). Kashifi gives the history of the fables from the "Indian" version of Bidpay (3a), to Burziyah's Pahlavi (3a), Ibn al-Muqann? [sic] in Arabic (3b), Ridaki's Persian in verse (3b), and the prose Persian version of Bahram Shah Ghaznawid (3b). Kashifi states (4a) that the book was in danger of not being read on account of the difficulties in the language of the Bahram Shah version, which he (Kashifi) has now undertaken to make more accessible to his contemporaries (4a-5b). This was suggested to him by (4b) Amir Shaykh A?mad, known as al-Suhayli (d. 1501-3 CE), hence the second title of the book and the pun on Suhayl, or the star Canopus. The work was done at the time of the Timurid Sultan ?usayn Bayqara (4b), who reigned in Heart until 1506 CE.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Kashifi, ?usayn Va ?i?, d. 1504 or 5</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: Persia</item><item>Layout: Average of 21 lines of text per page.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated title page.</item><item>Binding: Black laquered book cover with floral ornamentation.</item><item>Additional description: Punctuation and introductory words in red ink. Marginalia in two hands: one hand resembles the scribe's, the other seems to have been involved in the production of the book (i.e. on leaf 227a, the second hand has extended the gilt text box to accommodate notes). Leaves 3 and 4 are detached, and 88 is missing. The copier has dated the finishing of some of the chapters.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-6a: Kashifi's preface;</item><item>ff. 6a-29b: Introduction;</item><item>ff. 29b-78b: Chapter one: on avoiding to listen to the words of a slanderer and calumniator;</item><item>ff. 78b-104a : Chapter two: on evil-doers finding their recompense and the inauspiciousness of their end;</item><item>ff. 104a-126b: Chapter three: on the benefits of being in harmony with friends and supporting them;</item><item>ff. 126b-157a: Chapter four: on keeping an eye on enemies and not feeling secure;</item><item>ff. 157a-169b: Chapter five: on the harmfulness of negligence and losing what is sought;</item><item>ff. 169b-175a: Chapter six: on the curse of haste and the harm of precipitancy;</item><item>ff. 175a-185a: Chapter seven: on prudence and discretion and finding deliverance from the snare of adversaries by ruses;</item><item>ff. 185a-194a: Chapter eight: on being on one's guard against men of malice and not relying upon their flattery;</item><item>ff. 194a-210a: Chapter nine: on the merit of forgiveness and discretion which are the best adjuncts to kings;</item><item>ff. 210a-216b: Chapter ten: on the recompense of deeds in the manner of punishments;</item><item>ff. 216b-223b: Chapter eleven: on the harmfulness of desiring too much at the expense of doing one's task;</item><item>ff. 223b-240a: Chapter twelve: on the merit of self-possession and dignity and being settled and staid, particularly for kings;</item><item>ff. 240a-250a: Chapter thirteen: on avoiding the words of men of treachery and treason;</item><item>ff. 250a-262a: Chapter twelve: on not regarding the fluctuations of time and basing One's affairs on fate and divine decree.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref19_534" level="item"><did><unittitle>Yisuf va Zulaykha / Yusuf and Zulaikha</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1511</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_930745c09d6b6143d5689fa894771fb2" label="General Physical Description note">152 leaves : paper ; 222 × 120 mm. bound to 206 × 123 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_bca775323f50708611215bf7caf9617d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_772592150f82e20cf1ec517c173feb93"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Belles-lettres. Jami's allegorical romance, in verse (completed 1483 CE).</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Jami, 1414-1492</item><item>Scribe: ?la al-Din Mu?ammad al-Haravi</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: Timurid Herat</item><item>Layout: Average of 14 lines of text in two columns per page.</item><item>Script: Written in a nasta? liq hand.</item><item>Decoration: Illumination on title page.</item><item>Binding: Black leather binding with stamped gilt leather decoration; painted red endpapers.</item><item>Additional description: Verses enclosed in gold and blue text box. Episode headings generally one to three lines; first line blue, second line gold, and third line red. Pagination in ink on upper corners.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-18a: Opening verses;</item><item>ff. 18a-19a : The story of the lighting of the candle of Yisuf's beauty in the otherworldly night-chamber and the burning of Adam's heart upon witnessing that light;</item><item>ff. 19a-21b: How the sapling of Yisuf's beauty was brought into the Garden of Testimony, and how it was nourished by the tears of Jacob's eyes and the desires of Zulaykha's heart;</item><item>ff. 21b-24b: On the qualities and attributes of Zulaykha, from the sunrise of whose beauty, the occident had become the orient, but even a thousand degrees more so;</item><item>ff. 24b-26a: On how Zulaykha saw in the scabbard of sleep the sword of Yisuf's beauty for the first time, and how she was love-slain by that sword in the scabbard; </item><item>ff. 26a-27b : On how the morning breeze blew upon Zulaykha and awakened her sleepy narcissus eyes, and on how she drank the blood of her heart like a blossom and sealed her lips from the nightly vision;</item><item>ff. 27b-30b: On how the string of the intellect of maidens was tied into a knot of astonishment when they witnessed the change in Zulaykha's condition, and how her nurse untied that knot by the fingertips of interrogation;</item><item>ff. 30b-33b: How Zulaykha saw Yisuf in a dream a second time, and how the chains of her love quavered, dragging her into the embroilment of madness;</item><item>ff. 33b-35b: On how Yisuf came to her dream a third time, and how she learned his name and status, returning to sanity and consciousness;</item><item>ff. 35b-37b: How the envoys of the monarchs of those parts other than Egypt came to ask for Zulaykha's hand, and how her heart was constricted from her resulting despair;</item><item>ff. 37b-39b: How Zulaykha's father sent a messenger to the ?ziz of Egypt, offering her to him, and how he accepted it;</item><item>ff. 39b-41b: How the breeze of acceptance blew from Egypt, and how Zulaykha's litter was conveyed to Egypt like a bouquet of flowers;</item><item>ff. 41b-43a: How the ?ziz of Egypt found out that Zulaykha had arrived, and how he rose to set out for her welcoming, and how he adorned the army of Egypt in rich array;</item><item>ff. 43a-45a: How Zulaykha saw the ?ziz of Egypt from an opening in the pavilion-tent and cried "He is not the one I have seen in my dream, and for whom I have suffered the tribulations of love";</item><item>ff. 45a-47a: How Zulaykha came into Egypt along with the ?ziz of Egypt, and how the Egyptians came out and sprinkled trayfuls of offerings upon Zulaykha's litter;</item><item>ff. 47a-50a: How Zulaykha spent her days in the absence of Yisuf, and how she pined and grieved during the passing of those mornings and nights;</item><item>ff. 50a-51a: The beginning of the brothers' jealousy, and how they cast Yisuf out of Canaan;</item><item>ff. 51a-52b: How Yisuf dreamed that the sun and the moon and twelve stars were bowing down to him, and how the brothers heard this, and how their jealousy was increased;</item><item>ff. 52b-53b: How the brothers held council with one another to see what ruse they might devise to separate Yisuf from their father;</item><item>ff. 53b-54b: How the brothers went to their father and asked him to take Yisuf into the wilderness with them;</item><item>ff. 54b-57a: How the brothers took Yisuf away from their father, and how they dug a well of darkness in the path of their own guidance, throwing him who was guiltless into the well;</item><item>ff. 57a-59a: How the caravan arrived at the well, and how they took Yisuf out of the well, illuminating the world once again by the light of his beauty;</item><item>ff. 59a-60a: How the proprietor brought Yisuf to the environs of Egypt, and how the king found out about it and sent the ?ziz to their welcoming;</item><item>ff. 60a-61b: How Yisuf got into the river Nile to wash himself of the dust of the road, and how he sat in a litter intending for the court of the king of Egypt;</item><item>ff. 61b-63a: How Zulaykha, arriving at court and asking the reason for the congestion, saw Yisuf's beauty and recognized him;</item><item>ff. 63a-65a: How the proprietor presented Yisuf for sale, and how Zulaykha bought him by doubling what the others were buying him for;</item><item>ff. 65a-68a: The story of a girl named Bazigha, a descendant of the ?id, who was like none other in her wealth and beauty, and who fell in love with Yisuf absently, and saw the Truth in that mirror of beauty, and reached the Truth via that path;</item><item>ff. 68a-70a: How Zulaykha instructed Yisuf, and how she served him with whatever was at hand;</item><item>ff. 70a-71b: How Yisuf described the tribulations of the road and the agonies of the well, and how Zulaykha realized that this was the cause for his sadness that day;</item><item>ff. 71b-72b: How Yisuf besought a shepherd, on account of the fact that there has never been a prophet who did not herd livestock, and how Zulaykha prepared the means of his shepherding;</item><item>ff. 72b-74a: How Zulaykha asked Yisuf for attainment, and how Yisuf fled from her;</item><item>ff. 74a-75b: How the nurse asked Zulaykha the cause of her burning and smoldering;</item><item>ff. 75b-77a: How Zulaykha sent the nurse to Yisuf to ask for her wish, and …[text faded];</item><item>ff. 77a-79b: How Zulaykha went herself to Yisuf and implored, and how Yisuf excused himself from satisfying her desire;</item><item>ff. 79b-81b: How Zulaykha sent Yisuf to the garden and how she set him up;</item><item>ff. 81b-83b: How evening fell, and how the maidens presented their beauties to Yisuf, to see unto which one of them would Yisuf be inclined;</item><item>ff. 83b-85a: How Zulaykha implored her nurse for a ruse that would bring about the attainment of Yisuf;</item><item>ff. 85a-86b: How the nurse built a house in which the pictures of Yisuf and Zulaykha were painted;</item><item>ff. 86b-90a: How Zulaykha summoned Yisuf into that house and asked for attainment;</item><item>ff. 90a-95a: How Zulaykha brought Yisuf into the seventh house, and how she set forth her endeavor into the Nile of desire, and how Yisuf ran away and left her rueful and pining;</item><item>ff. 95a-97b: How the ?ziz of Egypt came up to Yisuf in front of that house, and how [Yisuf] hid what had past between him and Zulaykha, and how Zulaykha divulged it;</item><item>ff. 97b-99a: How the captains dragged Yisuf to prison, and how a nursling infant testified to his innocence, and how he was left alone;</item><item>ff. 99a-103a: How the women of Egypt removed their hands from the mouths, and began upbraiding Zulaykha, and how the sword of the zeal of love cut their tongues and hands;</item><item>ff. 103a-105b: How the women of Egypt excused Zulaykha after they had witnessed Yisuf's beauty, and how Yisuf disdained submission to Zulaykha, and how she threatened him with imprisonment;</item><item>ff. 105b-108a: How the women of Egypt induced Zulaykha to send Yisuf to prison, and how Zulaykha obeyed them;</item><item>ff. 108a-111a: How Zulaykha regretted having sent Yisuf to prison, and how she began to weep and wail for his absence;</item><item>ff. 111a-113b: How Zulaykha grew impatient at Yisuf's absence, and how she went to prison at night along with the nurse and witnessed his beauty;</item><item>ff. 113b-115b: How in daytime Zulaykha went to the rooftop of her palace, and watched the rooftop of the prison from there, and how she began weeping and moaning over his absence;</item><item>ff. 115b-117a: The description of how Yisuf did good to the men in jail, and how he interpreted the dream of the confidants of the king of Egypt, and how he charged one of them to recall him to the king;</item><item>ff. 117a-120a: How the king of Egypt requested Yisuf for the interpreting of his dream, and how he pleaded that he investigate into what had passed between him and the women of Egypt;</item><item>ff. 120a-122a: How Yisuf came out of prison, and how the king honored him, and how the ?ziz of Egypt passed away, and how Zulaykha was stricken with loneliness and separation;</item><item>ff. 122a-125a: The description of Zulaykha's condition after the death of the ?ziz of Egypt, and how the love of Yisuf overpowered her, and how she was stricken with the tribulation of estrangement;</item><item>ff. 125a-127a: How Zulaykha came to Yisuf's way and built a hovel so she might find solace at the sound of the passing of his army;</item><item>ff. 127a-129a: How Zulaykha blocked Yisuf's way, and how she did not find favor, and how afterwards she went home, broke the idol, believed in God most high, went back to his way, and found favor;</item><item>ff. 129a-131b: How Zulaykha came to the private house of Yisuf, and how, by his prayers, she regained her sight, beauty, and youth;</item><item>ff. 131b-133b: How Yisuf took Zulaykha as wife by the order of God most high, and how he took her to the marriage bed;</item><item>ff. 133b-135b: How the love for Zulaykha overpowered Yisuf, and how he built a house of worship for her;</item><item>ff. 135b-137a: How Yisuf saw his mother and father in a dream, and how he asked God most high to pass away, and how Zulaykha panicked;</item><item>ff. 137a-142a: How Yisuf passed away, and how Zulaykha died from the pain of his separation;</item><item>ff. 142a-152a: closing material.</item></list> </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref22_rnb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Ma?l?-i s?dayn va majm? -i ba?rayn / The rising of the auspicious [lunar] mansions, and the gathering of the seas</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1492</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_d48c350ec6e08d5e9d24dc1c4d51fed8" label="General Physical Description note">430 leaves : paper, ill. ; 251 × 163 mm. bound to 253 × 167 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_90cc0295d61cd2c1d3932acd4ca8d81c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a67fb84924aa31347388cff4b32d7436"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>History. This is the second volume of Samarqandi's history of the Ilkhanid Mongols, Tamerlane, and the Timurids. Volume two covers the sons of Tamerlane up to ca. 1469 CE; also including the enthronement of Sul?an ?usayn Bayqara, ca. 1470 CE. While the first volume of this book borrowed from several other histories, the second volume reported the events that were contemporary, or near contemporary, with the author. The focus is mostly on events in Khurasan and Transoxiana, with due attention given to events in Iraq and Azerbayjan. The reign of the following Timurid Emirs are covered with varying degree of detail: Pir Mu?ammad, Rustam, Khalil Sul?an, ?Umar Shaykh, Shah Rukh, Ulugh Beg, ?bd al-La?if, ?bd Allah, Abi S? id, Sul?an A?mad, Ma?mid, and ?usayn Bayqara. The book also contains the report of the author's travels to India as an ambassador and his account of the strange things that he had seen there. The author refers to himself and his date of composition in a number of other instances, for example 58a (at the end of the section on Shahrukh's school and hospice built in Heart ca. 1410), or when he mentions his interview with Shahrukh ca. 1437 (192b).</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: ?bd al-Razzaq Kamal al-Din ibn Is?aq al-Samarqandi, 1413-1482</item><item>Scribe: ?bd al-Mi'min ibn Maq?id ?li al-Mu?allim</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: [Northeast Persia or Afghanistan?]</item><item>Layout: Average of 21 lines of text per page.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated title page.</item><item>Binding: Red leather binding with gilt stamping.</item><item>Additional description: Chapter headings, Koranic verses, and the words "verse" or "poem" in red ink. Each leaf has been numbered on the "b" side, in the right margin. Occasional streaking of ink, and ink-stained fingerprints. Possible water damage at tail.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1a-3b: Opening;</item><item>ff. 3b-11b: The enthronement of Shah Rukh Mirza;</item><item>ff. 11b-31a: Events of 808-809 AH;</item><item>ff. 31a-100a: Events of 810-819 AH;</item><item>ff. 100a-156b: Events of 820-829 AH;</item><item>ff. 156b-188b: Events of 830-849 AH;</item><item>ff. 188b-235a: Events of 840-849 AH;</item><item>ff. 235a-314a: Events of 850-859 AH;</item><item>ff. 314a-387b: Events of 860-869 AH;</item><item>ff. 387b-430a: Events of 870-874 AH.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref25_uxi" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tarassul / Letter writing</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1604</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b2ac8bd608c026d9560fa15426a74d9a" label="General Physical Description note">67 leaves : paper ; 215 × 135 mm. bound to 217 × 140 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_15a107d99146c85fe478ca2a928219a4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz00090qv4" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Tarassul = Lettering writing " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Tarassul = Lettering writing</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17591e9fd2287d13274d073a94c796ef"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondence manual. This is a handbook of official correspondence, meant for secretaries, providing samples of letters to various government functionaries or potentates according to rank or the occasion. These include not only letters addressed to Sultans (3b), letters to Sultans on occasion of victories (4b), letters addressed to supreme Emirs (9b), viziers (11b), judges (16b), etc.; but also how to answer such letters.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Manṣῡr ibn Muḥammad ibn ̒Alῑ al-Qazvῑnῑ</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: [?afawid Persia?]</item><item>Layout: Average of 8 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Divani.</item><item>Binding: Black leather binding with blind stamping.</item><item>Additional description: Blue paper with ivory and pink paper inlays. Headings and some punctuation in red ink. Pagination in Arabic numerals stamped on top right and left hand of facing pages. Fore-edge title.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1a-1b: Blank;</item><item>ff. 2a: Date;</item><item>ff. 2b-3b: Opening;</item><item>ff. 3b-66b: Sample letters;</item><item>ff. 67a-67b: Blank.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref28_vma" level="item"><did><unittitle>Asas al-iqtibas / The foundations of learning</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3bac81cf1fab1936551cd91d63bafcbe" label="General Physical Description note">276 leaves : paper ; 181 × 120 mm. bound to 184 × 120 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_37af38dac90dc52dfd5ad1f4f29c1db1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_69e04e5170cf553042b2a39036d192e9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Philosophy and logic. The division of the manuscript follows Aristotle's six-part "Logic," with the two appended books of "Rhetoric" and "Poetics," plus the additions of Porphyry of Tyre. Incomplete; page 1a begins in the middle of a sentence, and the critical edition of the text, ed. Mudarris Ra?awi (Tehran, 1976) shows this as the fourth line of the introduction.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: ?usi, Na?ir al-Din Mu?ammad ibn Mu?ammad, 1201-1274</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Layout: Average of 19 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Nast? liq.</item><item>Binding: Burgundy leather binding with blind stamped leather inlays. Front cover has been replaced with blue cloth over a wooden board.</item><item>Additional description: Chapter headings in red ink. Fairly extensive marginalia. Tables and charts (leaves 57-58). Spine title: Asas al-eqbas.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1a-2a: Preface;</item><item>ff. 2a-13b: The First discourse: introduction to logic or Isagoge;</item><item>ff. 13b-24a: The Second discourse: on the ten classifications. It is called Categories;</item><item>ff. 24a-74a: The Third discourse: on interpretation. The target of these subjects is definitive statements. It is called Hermeneutics;</item><item>ff. 74a-147a: The Fourth discourse: on the science of analogies. It is called Prior Analytics;</item><item>ff. 147a-196a: The Fifth discourse: on proof. It is called Posterior Analytics;</item><item>ff. 196a-233b: The Sixth discourse: on argumentation. It is called Topics;</item><item>ff. 233b-240b: The Seventh discourse: on fallacies. It is called Sophistry;</item><item>ff. 240b-269a: The Eighth discourse: on oratory. It is called Rhetoric;</item><item>ff. 269a-276a: The Ninth discourse: on poetry. It is called Poetics.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref31_isx" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tu?fat al-mulik / The kings' gift</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1822</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f62d794090a2b1b5372093de662410a7" label="General Physical Description note">201 leaves : paper, ill. ; 288 × 191 mm. bound to 292 × 200 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_1f8f7924cf9f42bf3bd7d4bef0529229" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe454e912b780037af4765b9984dd408"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Philosophy and belles-lettres. Political treatise written during the reign of Fat? ?li Shah Qajar at his request and that of the crown prince Mu?ammad ?aqi Mirza. The illustrations depict the circles of reason (often represented by the color of gold), and the circles of ignorance (often represented by black) to which people might ascend or descend.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Kashfi, Ja ?far ibn Abi Is?aq, d. 1850 or 51</item><item>Scribe: Qasim ibn Mu?ammad al-Na?rabadi</item><item>Language: Text in Persian and Arabic</item><item>Origin: Qajar Persia</item><item>Layout: Average of 29 lines of text per page.</item><item>Decoration: Several large cosmological illustrations.</item><item>Binding: Lacquered painted boards; outside covers show a floral medallion on a black background, bordered in gold; inside covers show a yellow flowering plant on an orange background.</item><item>Additional description: Chapter and section headings in red ink. The leaves are frayed and have been poorly taped. Charts and illustrations throughout. Interlinear Persian and Arabic text from ff. 194- 198.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-2b: Preface;</item><item>ff. 2b-18a: The first stratum: on the truth of reason;</item><item>ff. 18a-75b: The second stratum: on the quality of relationship, and its belonging to living beings, and all that belongs to it;</item><item>ff. 75b-137b: The third stratum: on the attributes and the signs and vestiges thereof, and that which belongs to them;</item><item>ff. 137b-187a: The closing: on one bit of the authority of reason which belongs to managing the populace; first part;</item><item>ff. 187a-201a: Second part.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref34_dnj" level="item"><did><unittitle>Divan-i ?afi? / Poems of ?afi?</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1831</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_620c6878926684ebc488e13d13fa8346" label="General Physical Description note">74 leaves : paper, ill. ; 346 × 215 mm. bound to 349 × 220 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_ca9d829255e325b936060b2701fa2420" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_749148b7ba68b33eea8048c147762570"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Belles-lettres. The anthology of the lyrics and poems of ?afi?.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: ?afi?, 14th cent.</item><item>Scribe: ?li Ashraf Khan</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: Qajar Persia</item><item>Layout: Average of 25 lines of text per page; some pages have 4 columns.</item><item>Script: Nast? liq.</item><item>Decoration: Leaves 1b and 6a are illuminated.</item><item>Binding: Lacquered painted boards with gold floral and bird ornamentation on a black background, framed in gold, red, and black borders. Inside covers depict a perched bird in gold on a red background, framed in gold and black borders.</item><item>Additional description: Ornate title page illumination. Poems generally in black ink. Quatrains towards the end of the text are designated with red ink headings. Some staining.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-3a: Prose introduction;</item><item>ff. 3b-6a: Opening verses;</item><item>ff. 6a-73b: Poems.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref37_60c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Qur'ān / Koran</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_77b95a96d40302a9eab44bec9f5fd5b7" label="General Physical Description note">7 leaves : paper, ill ; 218 × 147 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_88cdf4109fb66067c1d2ee79488f3b56" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz00090qtm" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Qur’ān [MS 1656/10]" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Qur'ān [MS 1656/10]</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad08b1a061a16a94a1912d98bd13d746"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Fragment containing parts or all of four short chapters 84 to 87, including: verses 16 to 25 of al-inshiqaq (The sundering), all of al-Burῡj (The mansions of the stars), all of al-Ṭāriq (The morning star), and verses 1 through 14 and the first two words of verse 15 from al-A̒alá (The most high).</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Arabic</item><item>Layout: Average of 11 lines of text per page.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated.</item><item>Additional description: One quire. Text in black ink, with every first, fifth, and eleventh line in larger script.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref40_nff" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tuḥfat al-zā ̒ir / The pilgrim's gift</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1830</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a5e7a53c1f039f50fcd3c2a405059b11" label="General Physical Description note">304 leaves : paper, ill. ; 229 × 141 mm. bound to 231 × 144 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_b43491d85589cad8be65798a980fef07" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz00090qx5" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Tuḥfat al-zā ̒ir = The pilgrim's gift" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Tuḥfat al-zā ̒ir = The pilgrim's gift</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70596f26ed38a8e44a2d4208240bea3d"><head>Scope and Content note</head><p>Religion. Majlisῑ's Ṣafawid-period treatise on pilgrimage, with a guide for reading one's fortune using the manuscript written on the very last leaf (304b). The author states that he wrote the book in Persian because most people could not read the Arabic books written on this topic.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Majlisī, Muḥammad Bāqir ibn Muḥammad Taqī, 1627 or 8-ca. 1699</item><item>Language: Text in Persian and Arabic</item><item>Origin: Qajar Persia</item><item>Layout: Average of 21 lines of text per page.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated title page.</item><item>Binding: Lacquered painted boards with decorative floral ornamentation.</item><item>Additional description: Text in black ink with gilt ruling; chapter headings in red and framed in gold. Occasional spelling errors and marginalia. Water damage. Paper fragments laid in provide bibliographical information about two other manuscripts, one them is in the present collection (ms. 25). </item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-2b: Opening;</item><item>ff. 2b-10a: Introduction;</item><item>ff. 10a-18b: Chapter one: the merits of repairing the holy tombs of the Prophet and the Imams, the merits of making pilgrimage to them, and the manner of making pilgrimage to them;</item><item>ff. 18b-36b: Chapter two: on the merit [?] and quality of making pilgrimage to the Apostle of God, Fa?ima Zahrá, and the Imams;</item><item>ff. 36b-77b: Chapter three: on the merit of making pilgrimage to [?li] and the quality of making pilgrimage to him;</item><item>ff. 77b-93a: Chapter four: on the merit of the noble Najaf, Kifa, the mosques of Kifa, and the waters of Euphrates;</item><item>ff. 93a-118b: Chapter five: on the merit of making pilgrimage to the Lord of the Martyrs, ?usayn ibn ?li;</item><item>ff. 118b-133a: Chapter six: on the merit of the glorious burial place and Karbala, and the merit of the tomb of Imam ?usayn, and the manner thereof;</item><item>ff. 133a-187b: Chapter seven: on the separated pilgrimages of his highness, which are not special to particular times, and the manners thereof, and other acts and prayers which must be done in the holy mausoleum;</item><item>ff. 187b-221a: Chapter eight: on the merit and quality of making pilgrimage to his highness which is special to known times and days;</item><item>ff. 221a-239b: Chapter nine: on the merit and quality of making pilgrimage to their highnesses Imam Misá Ka?im, Imam Ri?a, and Imam Mu?ammad Taqi; </item><item>ff. 239b-257b: Chapter ten: on the merit and quality of making pilgrimage to their highnesses Imam ?li Naqi, Imam ?asan ?skari, and the Lord of the Event;</item><item>ff. 257b-296a: Chapter eleven: on visiting the mosque where every Imam can be visited there;</item><item>ff. 296a-304a: Chapter twelve: on the manners of making the pilgrimage on another's behalf, and the manners of making the pilgrimage to the ofsprings of the Imams;</item><item>ff. 304a: Closing.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref43_sok" level="item"><did><unittitle>Al-daftar al-tas? min al-dafatir al-marsima bi al-Sulaymaniyya / The ninth book of the books styled al-Sulaymaniyya</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1593</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e5785a0955642b0c366d2e7962efbd01" label="General Physical Description note">81 leaves : paper ; 250 × 141 mm. bound to 250 × 145 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_0e14a378201c5d922e4b39533ad7397e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f8beb5b3ae49664b15096e0d766875b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This manuscript is the ninth part of Kemalpasazade's Histories of the Ottoman House, entitled Tevârî?-I Âl-I O<emph render="underline">s</emph>mân. The text describes the end of Bayezid II and the beginnings of Selim's reign.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Kemalpasazade, 1468 or 9-1534</item><item>Scribe: Mu?ammad ibn A?mad al-Waqi? [al-Wafi"?]</item><item>Language: Text in Ottoman Turkish</item><item>Origin: Ottoman Empire</item><item>Layout: Average of 17 lines of text per page.</item><item>Binding: Quarter leather binding with decorative purple wrappers over stiff paper boards.</item><item>Additional description: Text boxes, chapter headings, punctuation marks, and words introducing poetry in red ink. Leaf 59b entirely in red ink; leaves 72 and 79 are blue. Some spelling errors and marginalia.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-2b: Brief opening;</item><item>ff. 2b-3b: Death of Bayezid, Selim mourns;</item><item>ff. 3b-6a: Selim ascends the throne, Ahmed rebels;</item><item>ff. 6a-8a: Selim deals with brothers and nephews;</item><item>ff. 8a-10a: Ahmed returns from Arab provinces, defeated outside Yenisehir;</item><item>ff. 10a-11a: Süleyman appointed Emir;</item><item>ff. 11a-18a: Kizilbas (Qizilbash) movement in Azerbayjan;</item><item>ff. 18a-18b: The army gathers, ready to set out;</item><item>ff. 18b-22a: Selim sets out, holds court in the field;</item><item>ff. 22a-24b: Correspondence with Shah Isma'il leads to war. Selim marches to Çaldiran;</item><item>ff. 24b-29a: Battle of Çaldiran, Selim victorious;</item><item>ff. 29a-30b: Victory-letters dispatched about;</item><item>ff. 30b-32b: Selim enters Tabriz;</item><item>ff. 32b-36b: Selim leaves Tabriz for Rim;</item><item>ff. 36b-39b: Invasion of the isle of Rhodes;</item><item>ff. 39b-42b: Marine "gaza" from Gallipoli;</item><item>ff. 42b-49b: Selim sets out on victorious journey and raises imperial standards;</item><item>ff. 49b-51a: Crossing into Rhodes, intending "gaza";</item><item>ff. 51a-53b: Orders battle, councilors and commanders plot the taking of fortifications;</item><item>ff. 53b-57b: Ruler of Egypt joins the "gaza";</item><item>ff. 57b-62a: Instruction on the capture of enemy, battle;</item><item>ff. 62a-65a: Ruler of Egypt dies;</item><item>ff. 65a-67b: Ottoman forces lay siege to the fortress;</item><item>ff. 67b-69a: What was taking place in surrounding kingdoms while the siege continued;</item><item>ff. 69a-72a: Assault on the fortress;</item><item>ff. 72a-77a: Residents of the fortress sue for peace;</item><item>ff. 77a-79b: Rhodes fortress taken;</item><item>ff. 79b-81a: Triumphant return home.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref46_4mc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Humayin nama, ya, Mavahib-i ilahi / Book of Humayin, or, Divine gifts</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6ce11dac40cef430a17b11786752be22" label="General Physical Description note">271 leaves : paper ; 243 × 122 mm. bound to 244 × 126 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_7765675bac2a1227aa05c922e72628f5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a78bfa3e04466c3c7a60606703e735d5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Yazdi's history of the Mu?affarid dynasty of Shiraz, Isfahan, Kirman, and Yazd, written for Shah Shuja? in 1356 CE. The text appears incomplete, as it begins mid-sentence on the first page and ends abruptly on the last. It begins with the ancestry of his majesty the "Asylum of the Caliphate" (i.e Mubariz al-Din Mu?ammad), and mentions the birth of his sons Sharaf al-Din Shah Mu?affar, "Asylum of the Sultanate" (i.e Shah Shuja?), and Shah Ma?mid. It lays the ground for their further eminence, describing their meetings with the Ilkhanid Emperors Sultan Abi Sa" id and Arpa, and also mentions the affairs of the Injiids in Fars and the Chibanids.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Mu?in al-Din Yazdi, d. 1387</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: [Persia?]</item><item>Layout: Average of 21 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Nast? liq.</item><item>Binding: Black leather binding with blind stamping.</item><item>Additional description: Chapter headings in red. Some stains and discoloration.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1a-3b: Opening;</item><item>ff. 3b-9a: Introduction;</item><item>ff. 9a-271a: The text.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref49_vxk" level="item"><did><unittitle>Akhlaq al-Muhsini / The morals of the beneficent</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1802</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_34c629748ac53495b104bdb92ae39ff5" label="General Physical Description note">102 leaves : paper ; 248 × 140 mm. bound to 255 × 146 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_7e8c814fc176d14734461024a2c9c19b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_506d209e63f25750e1c90c412e4b743b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Islamic philosophy and ethics. Kashifi's moral treatise, dedicated to the Timurid Sultan ?usayn Bayqara circa 1494 CE.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Kashifi, ?usayn Va ?i?, d. 1504 or 5</item><item>Scribe: ?bd Allah ibn ?bd Allah ibn ?bd Allah</item><item>Language: Persian</item><item>Layout: 16 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Nast? liq.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated title page.</item><item>Binding: Brown leather binding with gilt stamping on spine.</item><item>Additional description: Chapter headings and verse markers in red ink. Text and outer page margins have been colored.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1a-4a: Opening;</item><item>ff. 4a-4b: Table of contents;</item><item>ff. 4b-5a: Chapter one: worship;</item><item>ff. 5a-5b: Chapter two: purifying;</item><item>ff. 5b-6a: Chapter three: prayer;</item><item>ff. 6a-7a: Chapter four: thanksgiving;</item><item>ff. 7a-8a: Chapter five: patience;</item><item>ff. 8a-8a: Chapter six: contentment;</item><item>ff. 8a-8b: Chapter seven: reliance on God, and the ability to live without;</item><item>ff. 8b-10b: Chapter eight: having shame;</item><item>ff. 10b-10b: Chapter nine: chastity;</item><item>ff. 10b-11b: Chapter ten: courtesy;</item><item>ff. 11b-12b: Chapter eleven: eminence of resoluteness;</item><item>ff. 12b-13a: Chapter twelve: purposefulness;</item><item>ff. 13a-14a: Chapter thirteen: endeavoring and struggling;</item><item>ff. 14a-15a: Chapter fourteen: steadfastness;</item><item>ff. 15a-23a: Chapter fifteen: justice;</item><item>ff. 23a-25a: Chapter sixteen: forgiving;</item><item>ff. 25a-26b: Chapter seventeen: restraint;</item><item>ff. 26b-27b: Chapter eighteen: affability and benignity;</item><item>ff. 27b-29b: Chapter nineteen: mercy and clemency;</item><item>ff. 29b-31b: Chapter twenty: good works and charity;</item><item>ff. 31b-34b: Chapter twenty one: generosity and beneficence;</item><item>ff. 34b-37a: Chapter twenty two: humility and respectfulness;</item><item>ff. 37a-38b: Chapter twenty three: trustworthiness and religiosity;</item><item>ff. 38b-41a: Chapter twenty four: loyalty to a pledge;</item><item>ff. 41a-41b: Chapter twenty five: honesty;</item><item>ff. 41b-42b: Chapter twenty six: bringing about the needs of others;</item><item>ff. 42b-43b: Chapter twenty seven: deliberation and careful regard;</item><item>ff. 43b-45b: Chapter twenty eight: consultation and planning;</item><item>ff. 45b-46b: Chapter twenty nine: vigilance and foresight;</item><item>ff. 46b-51a: Chapter thirty: bravery;</item><item>ff. 51a-53b: Chapter thirty one: zeal for honor;</item><item>ff. 53b-55b: Chapter thirty two: management;</item><item>ff. 55b-59b: Chapter thirty three: being wakeful and informed;</item><item>ff. 62a-63a: Chapter thirty five: concealing secrets;</item><item>ff. 63a-65b: Chapter thirty six: taking advantage of opportunity;</item><item>ff. 65b-72a: Chapter thirty seven: honoring the rights;</item><item>ff. 72a-74b: Chapter thirty eight: conversing with those who are upright;</item><item>ff. 74b-82b: Chapter thirty nine: repulsing rascals;</item><item>ff. 82b-102a: Chapter forty: on training servants and retainers, and their manners.</item></list> </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref52_mj7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tu?fat al-a?rar va … sub?at al-abrar / The gift of the free and ... the majesty of the upright</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[1450-1550?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_660a8525aa19b62360795d631f96c77f" label="General Physical Description note">168 leaves : paper, ill. ; 197 × 105 mm. bound to 210 × 108 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_faf1d71f636f821d4d221157ba3c1c11" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a7bb7da6885b4a65e9fdd5b8d0426482"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Belles-lettres. The manuscript contains two works. From ff. 1b-63a is Tu?fat al-a?rar, and from 64b-168a is Sub?a al-abrar. Both works are part of the "septet" of Jami, or Haft Awrang.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Jami, 1414-1492</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Origin: [Timuird Herat?]</item><item>Layout: Average of 15 lines of text per page; two columns.</item><item>Script: Nast? liq.</item><item>Decoration: Pages 1b-3a, and 64b-66b are illuminated.</item><item>Binding: Black leather binding with red leather inside covers.</item><item>Additional description: Text in black ink; lacks chapter headings.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1a-1b: Opening;</item><item>ff. 1b-63a: Tu?fat al-a?rar;</item><item>ff. 64b-168a: Sub?a al-abra.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref55_mym" level="item"><did><unittitle>Târih-i feth-i Belgrad ; Târih-i Bosna / The history of the conquest of Belgrade ; History of Bosnia</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1741 March</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b0348cd1a8c2560370744cc28ee278b9" label="General Physical Description note">167 leaves : paper, ill. ; 204 × 154 mm. bound to 204 × 155 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_92114ea7bc8433bd57c31b6acd63bca5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bdb0e53320c429c65349aec2758a6684"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The manuscript contains two historical works. The History of the conquest of Belgrade is an excerpt from Subhî's Tarih-I Sami ve Sakir ve Subhî (Istanbul, 1784) covering the reign of the Ottoman Sultan Mahmud (r. 1730-1754). The scribe begins with the events of the year 1736 C.E. (80a of the printed work) when the troubles with Afsharid Persia are brought to a close, and the Ottoman army heads west into the Balkans. To this excerpt, the compiler has added a selection by Ömer Bosnavi entitled Târih-I Bosna (History of Bosnia), known by its full title as Tarih-i Bosna der zaman-i Hekimzade Ali Pasa.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: Mehmet Subhî, d. 1769 and Ömer Bosnavi, 18th cent.</item><item>Language: Text in Ottoman Turkish</item><item>Origin: Ottoman Empire</item><item>Layout: Average of 23 lines of text per page.</item><item>Binding: Deteriorated brown leather binding with blind stamped leather cutout on cover; leather fore-edge flap.</item><item>Additional description: Text in black ink, punctuation marks (often misplaced) in red. Chapter headings and verse markers in red from ff. 72b-117b.</item><item>Contents: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-117b: Târih-i Feth-i Belgrad;</item><item>ff. 119b-167a: Târih-i Bosna.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref58_zyg" level="item"><did><unittitle>Ḥālnāmah / The book of ecstasy</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1566?</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_75da77bd2b16f6626a32043145171868" label="General Physical Description note">17 leaves : paper, ill. ; 218 × 143 mm. bound to 222 × 146 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_bdedac9cd445d7e6fc997d01c9ddce3e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz00090qs3" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Ḥālnāmah = The book of ecstasy " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Ḥālnāmah = The book of ecstasy</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f4ab84a20091d5bad3ce348e67959757"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Belles-lettres. Mystical story in verse, also known as Guy va chawgan, ya, Ḥālnāmah (The ball and polo stick, or, The book of ecstasy).</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Author: ?arifi, d. ca. 1449</item><item>Language: Text in Persian</item><item>Layout: Average of 12 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Nasta̒ lῑq.</item><item>Decoration: Illumination on title page; paper is painted in blue and gold floral motifs.</item><item>Binding: Red leather binding with three medallions blind stamped on cover.</item><item>Additional description: The leaves decorated in yellows, greens, and blues, with gold floral motifs. The text in black, chapter headings in gold. </item><item>Content: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-5b: Opening;</item><item>ff. 5b-11a: Narrative;</item><item>ff. 11a-17a: Closing.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref61_vr8" level="item"><did><unittitle>/ [Letter-writing]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_44ba3fc57322e4ddbedff909707e652d" label="General Physical Description note">67 leaves : paper ; 180 × 127 mm. bound to 181 × 126 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_ba3178dbfcf6cbca86fecab1c506685c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f2ad1c68c49b2a005e6f0ce69aeaa75"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This is a handbook of official correspondence, meant for secretaries, providing samples of letters to various government functionaries or potentates according to rank or the occasion. These include letters congratulating a person's appointment to the office of grand vizier (5a), a vizier's letter to the king (8b), or letters congratulating scholars being appointed to teach and to give legal rulings (16b).</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Ottoman Turkish</item><item>Layout: Average of 15 lines of text per page.</item><item>Decoration: Illuminated title page.</item><item>Binding: Brown leather binding with gilt medallion stamped on covers; detached fore-edge flap. Decorative green, red, and white endpapers.</item><item>Additional description: Official correspondence manual. Text in black and red ink.</item><item>Content: <list type="marked"><item>ff. 1b-5a: Opening;</item><item>ff. 5a-65b: Sample letters;</item><item>ff. 65b-67b: Blank.</item></list></item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref64_nuc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Qur'ān / Koran</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6722fefaddf56b463adebb9309d07982" label="General Physical Description note">1 leaf, 1 fragment : paper ; 123 × 80 mm., 21 × 78 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_60b1cc11d9eea7c369bdcdba8d05711e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d291095db093719333b07333578cc595"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Fragment of Chapter 8 (Sira al-Anfal, or the Spoils of war) from the fourth word of verse 15 to the very end of verse 72. Small fragment from Chapter 3 (Sira al ?Imran, or The family of Amram): recto has five words (the fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth) from the 195th verse; verso has seven words of the 198th verse.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Arabic</item><item>Layout: 15 lines of text.</item><item>Decoration: Chapter headings in gold.</item><item>Additional description: Text in black ink, vowels in red ink. Framed in gold border.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref67_06f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Qur'ān / Koran</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_8aa874c93b0a1397ae6d5cc7a1374edb" label="General Physical Description note">605 leaves : paper, ill. ; 257 × 162 mm. bound to 259 × 166 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_3d1fe83a362ea68a64bba7667ce45c46" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88ad61289e675443c497df7e1dca4330"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Koran with interlinear Persian translation, as well as exegetical marginalia attributed to "Husayn Kashifi", who may be the same 15th-16th century intellectual Husayn Va'iz Kashifi (d. 1504-5) of the Timurid court in Herat.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Arabic and Persian</item><item>Origin: [Qajar Persia?]</item><item>Layout: Average of 12 lines of text per page.</item><item>Script: Naskh (Arabic text), nast? liq (Persian text).</item><item>Decoration: Extensive, full-leaf illumination on leaves 1b, 2a, 2b, 105b, 106a, 201b, 202a, 292a, 293b, 374b, 375a, 448b, 449a, 518b, 519a, 604b, and 605a. Partial illumination throughout entire manuscript.</item><item>Binding: Red lacquer boards; red leather spine. Dense floral design on the outside covers, medallions on inside covers.</item><item>Additional description: Arabic text in black, interlinear Persian in red, and marginalia in black and red. The text is framed in a box with thin green, gold, red, white, and blue borders. Between this box and the edge of the paper, there is another gold border 13 × 16 mm. from the edge of the paper. Extensive marginalia in red and black ink.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref70_90v" level="item"><did><unittitle>/ [Calendar]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[1775]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_533fa414146a3406dcd14760017e9483" label="General Physical Description note">8 leaves : paper ; 244 × 155 mm. bound to 253 × 163 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_9ba473a0142d8ed8f5faf800626975fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0485c6ccd3bcdbfe64b6ca8dc9e0c7f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>A calendar of the year 1189-90 AH (1775-6 AD), completed under the reign of the Ottoman Sultan Abdulhamid I (r. 1774-89), who is mentioned in the opening statements (1b). Each page covers a month in the Islamic calendar. For each month there is a table listing the weeks, "Arabic" and "Roman" dates of the week, the houses of the zodiac, and suitable activities. The author mentions a day in April 1775 as the first day of Spring (Nowrooz/Nevruz) and the day when the year will change; therefore the composition must have been completed shortly before that time. Gilt stamp on cover reads "Universal calendar of 1190 for Sultan Abdulhamid I."</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Ottoman Turkish</item><item>Origin: Ottoman Empire</item><item>Layout: Average of 12-15 lines of text per page.</item><item>Binding: Half leather binding with decorative blue paper; red, green and gray botanical print endpapers.</item><item>Additional description: Text in black, orange, green, gold, and red ink. Ink-stained, chipped and frayed.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref73_hbf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Scrolls</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref74_wfl" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4ae3876312cb07439009c2ff7ab38fab" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (20 sheets) : paper, ill. ; ca. 680 cm. × 10 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_4b5f635e251dbfe99acf0d1b45e1fccf" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8d20257f3115c204e757cfbd2afe1d7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>8 rolls, mostly illustrated, glued together into a consecutive piece.</p><p>Decoration: Decorated with the following illustrations in order of appearance from top of the scroll to the bottom; <list type="simple"><item>A) brown cross with green wreath on top, planted into green earth; </item><item>B) Jesus dressed in red and blue, surrounded by three winged faces; </item><item>C) section historiated with three figures in same positions--an angel, a bear or lion, and a donkey or goat, each with a red fish-tale and holding a book; </item><item>D) black cross;</item><item>E) red and gold cross;</item><item>F) Jesus dressed in red and blue with his hand on the head of a man dressed in green, kneeling before him; </item><item>G) gold cross on red and black platform set on pink paper; </item><item>H) red cross with two angels hovering at the foot, set on yellow paper. </item></list> Occasional stains and tear drops. Handwritten note dated 1952, possibly regarding the scroll, wrapped with the item.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref77_90e" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_bbfdf812502a2c21b14af6db3bf11880" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (4 sheets) : paper, ill. ; 117.8 cm. × 10.5 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_da4b75899f6a996e0b92f2aa06d3dfa5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8d2a9c0ddfb02ac3485e9de33629418e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: Four small scrolls glued together. </item><item>Decoration: Painting at head of scroll of Jesus with a gold halo, dressed in red and blue. Watermark at head of scroll.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref80_n0i" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1835</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c31d2492dc4ebff82b8e688c60973d3d" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll : paper ; 106 cm. × 8.7 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_fd019d64b6697961753b7d5b5ebeebb8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d6f19d83bbb1aad2b9062108fe7f4a9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains Koranic and exegetical matters. Introduction torn away, with remaining text beginning with the middle of the 255th verse ("Aya al-Kursiyy" or the "Verse of the throne") of the second sira ("al-Baqara" or the "Cow"); ending at verse 257. This is followed by a phrase in red, "what is to follow after prayer," and then text in black ink, ending with an "invocation to Ali" prayer. Includes beginning of sira 97 or "al-Qadr" ("Power"). The tail of the scroll contains closing statements, verses in Persian, and a date mark. Layout: Ruled lines of text enclosed in a gold and blue text box. Paper is frayed and torn at head.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Arabic and Persian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref83_akk" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1842</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9d9c32fab9689af04fe061a918260eed" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll : paper ; 58.6 cm. × 12 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_2d84784eca2e57e65ec0ebfa0e21c895" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7dd4c23a4950c4f67a6377ce2f398732"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: Ruled text in black ink, framed in painted orange borders. Torn at the top and bottom; frayed around the edges.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref86_871" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1842</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_5d44e7764cbf0f89a3e2c42ff7ee324d" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll : paper, ill. ; 84.6 cm. × 7.8 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_b554f7ee15037a6d4fe330314c2d3291" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca42092b0e5fe510c9e1e62fa23e5ea9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Unruled text in brown ink, heading in red ink, framed in red borders. Green cross at head of scroll.</p><p><list type="simple"><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref89_hrc" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scrolls]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_791f2e7cabe5b3a734a592edd658c694" label="General Physical Description note">8 rolls : paper, ill. ; various sizes</physdesc><container id="aspace_3b25c0ca3154bc7bd54802c46408a1eb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1caa03c5aaed4c0797a2b83d9b6c7751"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: 8 separate scrolls, some illustrated.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref92_59z" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll and purse]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_8299d4677363aa39828b83d8bfcae45b" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll, 1 pouch : paper, ill., cloth : scroll of unknown length, 173 × 183 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_383169e69f0094fc5b4ec43d44ec134c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8540671b5aded50005d27b9f906b982"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: Black and red ink text in a red border. Cloth pouch of brightly colored fabric; small metal clasp. Scroll has fine and elaborate illustrations throughout. Scroll is fragile and light-sensitive. May not be handled without the express permission and supervision of the Manuscripts Librarian.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref95_7ud" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1848</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_29a1a294ebbd6d31fdc21a6ff24dc65c" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (2 sheets) : paper, ill. ; 86 cm. × 10.5 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_906ca89b19e69d3b53c950db2f7f51bd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61c3e6c0eb399444f423e130517a4d1e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: Scroll comprised of two pieces glued together. Decoration: Illustration of green and red cross at head of scroll. Text in black ink, with yellow borders. Watermark at head of scroll.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref98_bte" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0a9371445f0a10c92ae89a9fde1aab34" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (4 sheets) : paper, ill. ; ca. 10 × 125 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_0c653704dbd00df5fb5b5fb5821b6392" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d09769fd63a841c8e1f0bd8d5797a16"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>One scroll, divided into two fragments, comprised of two pieces glued together each. <list type="simple"><item>Decoration: Illustration of Jesus, dressed in red and blue. Text in black, framed in yellow borders.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref101_409" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1839</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ed54be03becd69c0724f496e18817723" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (2 sheets): paper, ill. ; 118.4 cm. × 9.6 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_f1cc62b6c07c320110cb0f771e16a3f2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67979201b2e27de078a7b075b70e2a86"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: Unruled text with section headings; ruled borders. Illustration of Jesus at head of scroll, dressed in blue and red with yellow halo. Text in black ink, with red or blue headings. Yellow and black borders. Undated notation, possibly regarding the scroll, wrapped around it.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref104_wf0" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--?]</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_85c97885f3a6f2f4713031f6ec69d825" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (2 sheets) : paper, ill. ; 133 cm. × 10.4 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_853e25cb216e2444dfc0001dd3c184fe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2e931b8157af52dc3ad8cc02e1b87261"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Scroll begins with God's name at the top, followed by fifteen circular and one square text box, containing Arabic text and number charts. The texts are prayers and spells with repetitive phrases, some of which are from the Koran (for example, the text of the ninth circle begins with a few word of the Sira al-Qalam "Chapter of the Pen"). <list type="simple"><item>Layout: Average of 10 lines of text within each circular frame; circles are approx. 8 cm. in diameter. Two pieces glued together to comprise one scroll.</item><item>Decoration: Painted circle borders enclose the text; green and pink floral motif painted in the margins. Red, black, green and blue ink. The scrolls appear to have been folded lengthwise before rolling; a tear has occurred along the top 16.5 cm. of the seam.</item><item>Language: Text in Arabic</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref107_0tp" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Scroll]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 32</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1833</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_49c14d8f3e03d80d343d1a2984ca9279" label="General Physical Description note">1 roll (2 sheets) : paper ; 84.4 cm. × 10.2 cm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_497b22471d53534812d3bd8a7050d37d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c924759322fc75f1973d7043ac1d48f0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="simple"><item>Layout: Unruled text on two fragments. Text in black, red, orange, green, and blue ink, framed in brown and yellow borders. At the head of the scroll, a piece has been torn from the margin to the inner edge of the border, measuring 14.7 × 1.9 cm.</item><item>Language: Text in Armenian</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref110_1nk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Book covers and artifacts</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref111_zq8" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Leather bag]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_216c746a1d4665bea090bc4bb4c07c8d" label="General Physical Description note">1 bag (accessory item) : leather ; 285 × 260 × 50 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_cd8fc7d10b49b9d03f6bd0530ca33302" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7eda9e706bad178d30e4266d1dab5538"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Leather bag with braided tassels for securing the flap; leather braided shoulder-strap. The flap is embroidered with green and brown leather in geometric designs.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref114_292" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 34</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_32e764ad9c62b79a9dafc7c97ad8c37e" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 220 × 133 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_a0a1ed98076aa7d532dbcde3b43d2bab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz00090qrk" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Lacquered book cover, front cover, painted flower motif " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Lacquered book cover, front cover, painted flower motif</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_45d012e7d5dc138d93360c72a3056531"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book cover with decorative floral ornamentation. Outside covers show a bouquet of various colors against a black background, framed in red and yellow floral borders; inside covers show red flowering plant framed in black and yellow floral borders. In black ink, "Part Eight; ?aji Mu?ammad ?aqi; ?aji Baba Tabrizi " on outside cover. Fly leaves attached.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref117_syv" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 35</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f81083f573f628686fd54447819e3999" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 193 × 120 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_371e8ea11f03744fb859a2ec8da6b75e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f868c1d21f15ea13e198191ee3d75baf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book cover (one board) with ornamental design. Recto shows three floral medallions over a yellow background with red borders; red framed in black border on verso. English writing in pencil on verso: "used as a cover for tax sheets [illegible] bound with a string."</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref120_ki5" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 36</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_cbcddbc8a5e94f8312433948b982e9f5" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 154 × 89 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_5ee90edc8d74580b591347eda1a23d54" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_012678d472269e7ce9910e9d42cf0529"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book cover with decorative floral ornamentation. Outside cover shows a floral design on red background, framed in gold and black borders; inside cover shows white flowering plant on orange background with blue and white borders.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref123_2s2" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 37</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6b0859c3a4b48d13f75d5a51e3c9ffb9" label="General Physical Description note">1 leather book cover : paper-mâché : 172 × 94 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_14856cc38eea7aea10ef96b8b802f4bb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23712caa0d9c4b07cc1ccabb308061d6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Red leather book cover (one board only) with painted cut-outs and gilt border.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref126_an4" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 38</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2d36d6e63691dcf2a3725cec675d5f88" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 108 × 65 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_ddef94825b0e4be7230bf351e5a1ca8e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cae9921644f898c0b1f0c5e255be9c74"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Black lacquered book cover with floral ornamentation and leather spine; flowers in a gilt border on recto, abstract floral design on verso.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref129_9eu" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 39</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_92c54cca78916eac990d1447805eff10" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 127 × 78 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_0dfcc74b58a7274193dcef49b1693284" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_46274169dd25e99210946917963fd261"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book cover with floral ornamentation and leather spine. Outside cover shows floral motif on a black background bordered in black and gold; inside cover shows flowering plant on red background bordered in black and gold.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref132_3ke" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 40</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ab5adfb44310e4c56f738a2c00359438" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover (one board only) : paper-mâché ; 217 × 141 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_e1b2d290313d4c79921795a584779025" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3ecb23d4f9aaf88a1548d2a53a7f15a1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Black lacquered book cover (one board only) with decorative floral ornamentation. Recto shows a dense flower design over a burgundy background, with black, gold, and floral borders; verso shows flowering plant on black background bordered in black and gold.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref135_5z4" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 41</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b04e75998ea88657a5bf241990b11d0d" label="General Physical Description note">1 leather book cover : paper-mâché : 151 × 76 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_8ccd7bae43fbc9b550fdeac55f85a1fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2783dd93f7f26d7c2ff18b7db76ae59a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Brown leather book cover with blue cloth inlays, gilt painting, and leather spine.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref138_6kd" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 42</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_244d2469261b813e7c60f2156fae9f97" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 176 × 100 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_2cf4175f59c762c223ef2368c02d5cee" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c3726ad5afbb155db3294b48ceb6c68"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book cover (two separate boards) with decorative floral ornamentation. Outside cover shows floral motif on a green background, with black and gold borders; inside cover shows a white flowering plant on a red background, bordered in gold.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref141_7zx" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 43</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_d06b99d0b2f5a941a6037cb9d1efcec1" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 337 × 210 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_29d28e0d0313fd3b7fe0c838dd120e05" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0b9cbe7aed413592a0ecabcce2daf1be"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book covers. Recto has a flower and bird illustration set inside a yellow circle against a green background with thin gilded borders. Verso has two illustrations, one on the top half of the board, and another on the bottom. These show a number of women in what seems to be sequences from a story. The figures are drawn in black outline, wearing green and red dresses, and are set against a dark yellow and green background with a red border. Both boards are in poor condition. There is badly faded text in red ink over one of the story illustrations; the first word of the text appears to be "majlis," meaning assembly, and the second word is "Zulaykha". The scene is probably from Jami's romance of Yisuf and Zulaykha (see ms. 1656/3), where Zulaykha and other women were so awestruck by Yisuf's beauty that they peel the skin of their hands instead of the fruits they are holding. The covers may have been designed to contain a version of Jami's versified romance (completed 1483 CE). Below these two words is the date 1043 AH (1633-4 CE).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref144_j60" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Book cover]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 44</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_fae1074c11a174663080bc47cbcc9430" label="General Physical Description note">1 lacquered book cover : paper-mâché ; 365 × 227 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_5e1ae6ec51f06853b1aca8631e9fffbb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93638de49de3986dd3af56c21a4097fb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lacquered book cover with decorative floral ornamentation and leather spine. Outside covers show a scene with three youths; inside covers show a white medallion design on a black background.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref147_g25" level="item"><did><unittitle>[Wallet]</unittitle><unitid>Manuscript no. 45</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">n.d.</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4f60d80cd1952f51bc4add137e4fb7c4" label="General Physical Description note">1 wallet (accessory item) : leather and velvet ; 78 × 140 × 35 mm.</physdesc><container id="aspace_e86806c5427695b339b4df4096682e34" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89cc9025bdba57fbc04be8ed207f4073"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Faded red velvet sewn over leather. Embroidered with floral and geometric ornamentation; green leather border. Gold clasp on flap.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
