<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4779p5bz/">farin668.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Farington family correspondence</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Farington Family Correspondence <num>LSC.0668</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Sara Torres with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), Spring 2008; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2009.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-22 14:56:09 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Farington family correspondence</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <famname rules="aacr" source="naf">Farington family</famname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.0668</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(6 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1702/1858" type="inclusive">circa 1702-1858</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_88e66d710314f6d7502e9e01a25b93fc" label="Abstract">This collection contains multigenerational correspondence and personal notes of the Farington family. Reverend William Farington (1704-1767) was the vicar of Leigh and rector of Warrington in Lancashire, England. His son, Joseph Farington, RA (1747-1821), was a landscape painter best known for two collections of engraved views of the English lakes. The collection consists of manuscript correspondence to and from the Reverend William Farington and his son Joseph Farington concerning Joseph's art studies with Richard Wilson and his work and life in London. The collection includes the personal notes of, and watercolors and a pen and ink caricature by, Joseph's younger brother and fellow artist George Farington. There are also letters to an older son, William, Jr., regarding his naval travels in the West Indies, as well as correspondence with other family members.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b1d33172197033e381dc08417efd887e">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9fafd6ffc3b2fc5f4aa28c2b4b60b3ec">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bd0115d34ec87b463b2ba9cab03e7d05">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3979afc59a7d3ad81b79a8231c177408">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_57998ccbfa8dcc219dd4bdd72ff217c0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Farington family correspondence (Collection Number 668). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_084ee632d44d60696cce3f1fa6e42438">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Purchase, 1951.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_105ef1ad67c67f587b9fee597fa093b7">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Sara Torres with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), Spring 2008.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_c6b3e86b09a19d78b4515eaac5a176a8">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID:<extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942330063606533">9942330063606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1558f3cb171376fbe1731ce0b0c95b59">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>This collection contains multigenerational correspondence and personal notes of the Farington family. Reverend William Farington (c.1704-1767), the second son of William Farington of Worden and Shaw Hall, Leyland, was educated at Brasenose College, Oxford, where he matriculated on 11 February 1723. In 1733 he became vicar of Leigh, near Manchester, a post he held for thirty-four years, and in 1766 he became rector of Warrington (a living that belonged to his relatives, the Athertons) in Lancashire, England. A collection of his Sermons was posthumously published in 1769.</p><p>Rev. William Farington's second of seven sons with his wife Esther (née Gilbody), Joseph Farington, was born November 21, 1747 at Leigh, Lancashire. Joseph became a pupil of landscape artist Richard Wilson in London in 1763 at the age of sixteen; the year after, 1764, as well as in 1765 and 1766, he gained a premium at the Society of Artists for landscape drawing. In 1765 was elected a member of the Society. He enrolled as a student at the newly established Royal Academy of Arts' (1768) school soon after it was established, though he still exhibited his work at the Society of Artists and became one of its directors in 1772 and 1773. Later, he became associated much more closely with the increasingly influential Royal Academy and eventually became an extremely active and influential member; he was elected A.R.A. (Associate of the Royal Academy) in 1783, and R.A. in 1785. Joseph Farington married Susan Mary Hammond (1750-1800) on March 19, 1776; their marriage was childless. In December 1780 Farington settled in London at 35 Upper Charlotte Street, Fitzroy Square. He produced his <title>Views of the Lakes etc. in Cumberland and Westmorland</title> in 1789, the first of a series of topographical works, followed by <title>Views of Cities and Towns in England and Wales</title> in 1790, and completed the illustrations to the two volumes of <title>An History of the River Thames in 1794 and 1796</title>. Joseph Farington was sent to the Netherlands by William Windham, M.P. for Norwich in 1793 to prepare illustrations of the siege of Valenciennes. He later traveled to Paris in 1802, and both trips contributed to his appreciation for continental art. Joseph Farington, R.A. is best known for two collections of engraved views of the English lakes; published <title>Views of cities and Towns in England and Wales</title> (1790) and 76 plates in <title>History of the River Thames</title> (1794). He wrote <title>A memoir of Sir Joshua Reynolds</title> for the fifth edition of Reynolds's literary works (1819); died December 30, 1821.</p><p>Joseph Farington's younger brother, George Farington (1752-1788) was a history painter, who in 1773 was employed with his brother in recording the Walpole painting collection a Houghton Hall, Norfolk. George studied with Benjamin West, and became a student at the Royal Academy. He sailed for India in 1782, and died at Murishdabad in 1788. Many of Joseph's other brothers pursued naval careers. His older brother William and two of his younger brothers, Henry (1750-1827) and Richard Atherton (1755-1822) were all employed in the naval service of the East India Company. His fifth brother Edward (1758-1790) died of yellow fever early in a naval career and his sixth brother, Robert (1760-1841) pursued a career in the Church. </p><p> Sources: <list type="marked"><item><title>The Diary of Joseph Farington</title> ed. Kenneth Garlick and Angus MacIntyre. Vol. 1 , Published for the Paul Mellon Centre for Studies in British Art by Yale University Press, New Haven and London, 1978.</item><item>Evelyn Newsby, 'Farington, Joseph (1747-1821)', <title>Oxford Dictionary of National Biography</title>, Oxford University Press [http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/9161, accessed 7 Feb 2008]</item></list> </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8b1e2b091029e115105be805dd358ed8">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection consists of multigenerational manuscript correspondence to and from several members of the Farington Family, spanning roughly 1702-1858. Important figures include, but are not limited to, the Reverend William Farington and his son Joseph Farington, R.A. William's letters to his son concern Joseph's art studies with Richard Wilson and his work and life in London. The collection also includes Joseph's brother George Farington's watercolors, a pen and ink caricature, and personal notes.</p><p>The correspondence to and from Joseph's brother William, Jr., regarding his naval travels in the West Indies, is one representative example of the correspondence in this collection regarding naval life. The correspondence in this collection includes letters addressed to naval men aboard several ships, including the HMS La Topaze, HMS Ruby, HMS Hibernia, HMS Plover, HMS Thunder, HMS Clio, and the Bombay Castle East Indiamen. </p><p>The collection includes Joseph Farington's letters to a nephew discussing a naval commission.</p><p>In addition to correspondence, the collection contains personal notes, largely in the form of transcriptions of religious and literary writing, including biblical verses, sermons, and the following authors/works: Jacob Duchè; "Lady Brook's Memoirs"; "Sherlock's Discourses"; "The Bishop of London Lecture"; James Thomson's "Summer"; Hannah More; Henry James Pye; John Milton; William Cowper and Frances Maria Cowper. The collection also includes administrative/legal materials, including the "Will of Thomas Armstriding" and a document related to the nomination of a schoolmaster for the grammar school at the Parish of Leigh.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_27f0a7f3b2d20b19941112ff1eb19658">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection was originally housed in 14 separate loose folios. The connection between the materials brought together in each folio was not always evident; however original order has been maintained. Each series is organized by folio.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Family papers.</genreform>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Landscape painters -- England -- Correspondence.</occupation>
    <persname source="naf">Farington, Joseph, 1747-1821--Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Farington, William, 1704 or 1705-1767--Correspondence.</persname>
    <famname source="naf">Farington family--Correspondence.</famname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Farington, Joseph</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref12_e21" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 1</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref13_pyw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Binder boards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_72735b469a45757c1381ab02178f3eb4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4a60249f0482ce5e14a6c0e8cf8438e0" parent="aspace_72735b469a45757c1381ab02178f3eb4" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref14_5hy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions of biblical verses from the Books of Job and Psalms</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a4b69f4456f13e498708521f6927780" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2087c039795c086f020e68b3e32361bc" parent="aspace_9a4b69f4456f13e498708521f6927780" type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref15_5s1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions of biblical verses from the Books of Proverbs Ecclesiastes, and Solomon</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_97e2066ff10c9ba0a9beae6389460d27" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2e64580330d98556cddc091595f711da" parent="aspace_97e2066ff10c9ba0a9beae6389460d27" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref16_iz1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions from religious and other writings originally placed within Box 1, Folder 3</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1800-1815 (one leaf has watermark of 1800; Southey's "Madoc" not published until 1805)</unitdate><container id="aspace_a439e246a6f488a4f88190b6b8879665" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_150619cc6ca9fd63df0aec85bc4e9eb8" parent="aspace_a439e246a6f488a4f88190b6b8879665" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27c66cdc1618d1560c4f6f9a8730f48b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Transcriptions of biblical passages as well as passages from other religious writing and the following works: <list type="marked"><item>"From Wogan-on the Lessons for the 4th and 5th</item><item>Sundays after Epiphany"; </item><item>"Orton's Letters 1 Vol"; </item><item>"From a discourse by Sir John Suckling-"An account of Religion by Reason"; </item><item>"Gilpin's Lectures on Catechism"; </item><item>Planta-Helo: Conf Vol 2; </item><item>"On the Sacrament", from Stonehouse's "Friendly advice to a patient",</item><item> and Robert Southey's "Madoc". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref18_xxj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions from religious prose and verse</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. November 2, 1793-December 5, 1802</unitdate><container id="aspace_17af4b5c1f5d31a03ad171913dbe4148" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cd5734147d37a9f78242cf82d95ef4eb" parent="aspace_17af4b5c1f5d31a03ad171913dbe4148" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_daa86ec57f3f7e6cc22bc71a59dd0f16"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Transcriptions from religious prose and verse (including of a poem by John and Charles Wesley entitled "Abba Father!") and correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref20_64v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_735fc9deb5d34d8ed1833ec841a36fff" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f3bee77cc3962416755344fca5ae5965" parent="aspace_735fc9deb5d34d8ed1833ec841a36fff" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bed9b5978b79d43ff802588eec40c0ed"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Heading on letters: "Hoddesdon" and "Clifton" and are addressed to Leut. William Farington, H.M.S. La Topaze Jamaica</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref22_v1z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions of religious writings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bd55d72360578afa44aba368e5cdce7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ac462e4e6d4b0ba2ffb23c431ef06ff6" parent="aspace_3bd55d72360578afa44aba368e5cdce7" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88701eceb2b6ce0d15a264880357a8b8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Subheadings: <list type="marked"><item>"By the Right Reverend Father in God. Thomas, Lord Bishop of Sadon and Man / Concerning Spiritual Communion"; </item><item>"St. Luke 23... Do this in Remembrance of me"; </item><item>"1 Thessalonians 5:18 / In every thing give Thanks; for this is the Will of God"; </item><item>"Hebrews 12: 1-2: Patience...that is set before us looking unto Jesus"; </item><item>"St. Matthew 26:41"; </item><item>"A Prayer Upon the Day of One's Birth"; </item><item>"Occasional Prayer"; </item><item>"An evening prayer". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref24_0ay" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions from Jacob Duchè and "Lady Brook's Memoirs"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1801-2</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e54b1a1a17402794bde3dd366a0e1b2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1864bf6df9618273ffc9bcb93cb348b4" parent="aspace_2e54b1a1a17402794bde3dd366a0e1b2" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf9bb88146a922b0a2c17646b06d1304"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Subheadings: <list type="marked"><item>"Extracts from Duchiè [sic] IX Discourses" (i.e. "Discourses on various subjects, by Jacob Duchè" (1779);</item><item> cf. ESTC # T116264; at end": "WF in September 1801!" and "Rules for Practice" copied from Lady Brook's Memoirs by William Farrington Rector of Warrington and Vicar of Leigh" at end: "Transcribed from Lady Brook's memoir's 1745. -by Wm Farrington. Rector of Warrington &amp; Vicar of Leigh, -- copied from his by A Harington-1802. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref26_7o6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3a026cdff7e9ff51ff9ba2aea908510" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_fb5432e38bfb0853516eaf88c4bdd121" parent="aspace_f3a026cdff7e9ff51ff9ba2aea908510" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_368df1322736117de08a96c6b9811893"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Addressed to "My Dear William"</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref28_5tz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions from "Sherlock's Discourses" and "The Bishop of London Lecture"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c19a72c8b00555ed71f4ebec6f6d9847" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_28b8bf660011e85ba73b4f78e6074d31" parent="aspace_c19a72c8b00555ed71f4ebec6f6d9847" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de072094ecd80923337294859b4ce7ad"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains transcriptions <list type="marked"><item>"from Sherlock's Discourses" (1772); </item><item>cf. William Sherlock, (1641?-1707); </item><item>and "from the Bishop of London lecture" </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref30_qo8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions of verse, prayers, correspondence, and personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a8cedb51e0cd07951eaadc25725fca7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_403c4ddbf6259f8cd5d3225cef7556da" parent="aspace_9a8cedb51e0cd07951eaadc25725fca7" type="folder">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref31_z68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcription of verses from James Thomson's "Summer" with heading, "Inscribed to the Memory of Miss B. of Kensington"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1775 May 05</unitdate><container id="aspace_863174bd54fb227c363216ec040c5b24" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c403a19c1b3b1e2d6e241e1b2a24d0d7" parent="aspace_863174bd54fb227c363216ec040c5b24" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21ad1a50bbb43792db909028167bc600"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These are lines 571 and forward of James Thomson's (1700-1748)"Summer"; cf. "The seasons, a poem" ESTC # N021182. On bottom half of page is "Sonnet", the first two lines of which are "Parental Fondess, with they pangs excuse / The soft affection of a voice unknown!" Signed "EB[G]: May 5th, 1775"</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref33_xwb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcription of verses from the Book of Isaiah as well as other religious writing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_20faf8e4f042e341a5686c59d0c78df0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1ac502b3bec0da0c087b8ef1b92b6d42" parent="aspace_20faf8e4f042e341a5686c59d0c78df0" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da8c756b6b2e8ba8f7b331ca3d2ddfb3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Transcriptions include <list type="marked"><item>quotes from Isaiah 57:13-15; </item><item>"Wogan on the 4th Sunday after Epiphany, Morn[ingsong] Lesson" and "Evensong Lesson", cf. William Wogan,</item><item> An essay on the proper lessons, appointed by the liturgy of the Church of England ..." ESTC T124235; from "Orton's Letters, Vol 1"; </item><item>from "From a discourse by Sir John Suckleing" and "An Account of Religion by Reason", cf. "The works of John Suckling" ESTC # T099811; </item><item>Henry Hunter's (1741-1802) "Sacred Biography" ESTC T098655; </item><item>Planta-Helo. Conf. Vol 2; </item><item>Sir James Stonehouse's (1716-1795) "Friendly advice to a patient: and spiritual directions for the uninstructed" ESTC # T086231 </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref35_t24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions of writings by Hannah More, Henry James Pye, and John Milton</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_54b02d2b0fb9cec79a905f75d4d06c0b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cea799ba532adf87f469a57b1994aa96" parent="aspace_54b02d2b0fb9cec79a905f75d4d06c0b" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5db2a9dee8bfcc1b39684aa56ed8279f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>On one side of the paper is the transcription of an unattributed quote from Hannah More's "Sensibility": "Since trifles make the sum of human things / and half our miseries from trifles springs..." and on the other side is a quote labeled as "Pye's Afred" (i.e. Henry James Pye, Poet Laureate 1790-1813's "Alfred; An Epic Poem" (1801)) and below that, a quote from Milton's Lycidas, lines 168 and forward.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref37_o8p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1807 September - October</unitdate><container id="aspace_7644a57e8501dcb0225ada0c1bfb27b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c445081d6f1055052089651e237c5bde" parent="aspace_7644a57e8501dcb0225ada0c1bfb27b6" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e313d487d562bc3cf40cc6b69c9520f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>On the first page is written,"On first viewing my Father's Picture"; signed "R.C. 28 Sept 1807. </item><item>On the second page, a copy or draft of correspondence, "To Mr. and Mrs.-on their Wedding-day. / Dear Brother and Sister...Your affectionate Brother and sincere Wellwisher, R. C. London 1807". </item><item>On the third and fourth pages, "On the meeting of Eight Brothers 18. October 1807, with the intention of forming an annual meeting"; signed "R. C. 16th Oct 07".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref39_42j" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcription of verses by William Cowper and Frances Maria Cowper</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_91918a2879316dafb31020a09d68f4cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_b599cdd48d0c2fdea9de0df7d2e2c594" parent="aspace_91918a2879316dafb31020a09d68f4cc" type="folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7189e71d81f50037c27fc3b1c57ef637"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First sheet of paper has heading "On receiving my Mother's picture" with continuous transcription of verse through page four. At bottom of pager for is written "Cowper" (i.e. William Cowper's poem "On Receipt of his Mother's Picture") </item><item>Second sheet of paper has "Cowper" written on top right corner of first page with a transcription of verses from William Cowper's poem "Conversation". </item><item>The third, quarto size, sheet of paper also contains transcriptions, including quotes from Frances Maria Cowper's "Worldly Anxiety".</item><item>The fourth sheet of paper has "Cowper" written in the upper right hand corner with a transcription of verses from William Cowper's "Task", beginning with, "The Lord of all, himself through all diffused, / Sustains, and is the life of all that lives..."</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref41_c71" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcription of religious writing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_828acbbe57e737338fc56c2c564c7211" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_aeb7fd0b3e9f7ac9389114aecb180cf0" parent="aspace_828acbbe57e737338fc56c2c564c7211" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6ea5d202f93ef7651414af4a989f78b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appear to be notes from and about religious and doctrinal treatises, including one by Mr. Tibbs, DD, Gray's Inn.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref43_d7i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 or after</unitdate><container id="aspace_619f15fac3ba5be2ab2c91c34b324508" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3a955d2cb5301754ef82b9b5796d5fa0" parent="aspace_619f15fac3ba5be2ab2c91c34b324508" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_776a9772ba225b051d1df9dc3120a0c7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The folio-size sheet of paper has the heading: "The following account of the last moments of [Mr. or Mrs?] Pitt, were related by Mrs. Tomlin's-Wife of the Bishop of Lincoln." and the smaller sheet of paper entitled "Life of the Happy Man" with writing below. Both items are undated.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref45_8zq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions from Bowdlor's Essays, Stonehouse, and Bowdler</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8637b3839c188e9177eec59fe9f48b1d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cfda4c582152107ec33911be2034ce46" parent="aspace_8637b3839c188e9177eec59fe9f48b1d" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_389a6218dddbb4b4b98ced1f5d697722"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Transcriptions from: <list type="marked"><item>"On the advantage of Affliction" from "Bowdlor's Essays"; </item><item>"On Christian Perfection. from the same" and "On Resignation. from the same";</item><item>"On time, not wasting it in needless amusements from Stonehouse's Spiritual Advice to the Uninstructed" cf. Sir James Stonhouse's (1716-1795) "Spiritual Directions for the Uninstructed" ESTC T054036;</item><item>"Poems and essays, by a lady lately deceased" cf.Miss Jane Bowdler (1743-1784). </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref47_c8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal notes and drafts of correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8dc6274c59fb185632cebf6e636458c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a70631a2442eb069243d07de6b600847" parent="aspace_a8dc6274c59fb185632cebf6e636458c" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ce9345b52fc1edd6e31d92fdf9c66b3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>On the single sheet of paper, the signatures W. Farington and Hammonds are sloppily written at bottom of page. The gathering of four pages indicates that it is a "copy of letter Mr[s?] Hammons Downy Park".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref49_19y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions from Augustus Charles Thompson, Hannah More, and other verse</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e99e3231f479f627b0666f999bcb4334" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_44f074a295f1bdb02d52fade0ca15723" parent="aspace_e99e3231f479f627b0666f999bcb4334" type="folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af2fd28096b66e565134a9e2274d8e6c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Transcription of verse entitled "Patience" by Augustus Charles Thompson from "Songs in the Night: Or, Hymns for the Sick and Suffering" (1845), at bottom of page initials "A.M.". This item is considerably later than the other materials in this binder. </item><item>Transcription of an unattributed quote from Hannah More's Sensibility beginning with "Since trifles make the sum of human things" at bottom of page in a different, less formal hand is written "Given by Amal[?]". </item><item>Transcription two poems, one beginning with "Ye who the sickly couch attend" and the other with "Oh! Power supreme to thee my thoughts I turn". </item><item>At bottom of last page the initials "A.M" and, in a different hand, "Given by A.Mal[?] August 13th: 02.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref51_r2j" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal notes, transcriptions of verse and religious writing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 March 12</unitdate><container id="aspace_4babb9c822d9f948f862c7c5f247ae8f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_8664ca06978ce0ce19d98be0100f4aed" parent="aspace_4babb9c822d9f948f862c7c5f247ae8f" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7625d66e6b71bf1b4d50b18323872426"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>One of the sheets is folded in half to produce 4 pages, and entitled, "Prayer answered by trials" and "Why art thou cast down"; </item><item>at bottom of page 3: "I send you two of my favorite Hymns-the first I feel is particularly applicable to my present situation" and signed Wm. Farington, March 12, 1802 </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref53_uyl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal notes and religious writing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 May 03</unitdate><container id="aspace_06f3d8b1366234a4130b12d9327bdd8a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_633b4ea028170b119228d8b410722f3c" parent="aspace_06f3d8b1366234a4130b12d9327bdd8a" type="folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_254262ccaf1300ff00e09b9f3918ae46"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The first of the papers is dated: "May 3rd 1802" in ink and in pencil "Cowper"</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref55_kf4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 2</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref56_g7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Binder boards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c59267791309a25778e280f4a1d40214" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_865ce7263d9cf26d1f6c8dbad491e408" parent="aspace_c59267791309a25778e280f4a1d40214" type="folder">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref57_vm1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Watercolors, pen and ink caricature, and personal notes of George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">174-?</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f587915444d9bf9d89b9bf82f1b6831" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_41ef389ec5f21eee677ee2460f3c267f" parent="aspace_6f587915444d9bf9d89b9bf82f1b6831" type="folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23d7ec3a2d78d1cc96d8d15e2dd7a3be"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Items consist of: <list type="marked"><item>a 13 × 19 cm watercolor on paper of a rural village or farm, with signature "G. Farington, July 10, 174[3?]" at bottom right of picture,</item><item>and verse &amp; signature on back of picture, "When this you see / Remember me/ Tho' many miles /We distant be. / G. Farington. July 10th 17[??]";</item><item>a 16.5 × 15cm watercolor on paper of ruins with initials G.F. on bottom left margin of page;</item><item>a 14.6 × 17.8 cm watercolor on paper of maritime or river scene; </item><item>a 3.5 × 3.7 pen and ink caricature of figure smoking a pipe pasted onto a 6 × 6.9 cm cardboard backing, </item><item>and a small sheet of paper folded in half to produce 4 pages, only the first of which is written on.: "I have a persuasion in my heart, that if God continues my life many years, many of these things will die. I shall be more cautious by them and more humbly seek that wisdom from God..." </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref59_pnv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcriptions of religious writing by William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1801-1802</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac086db6216b305ca98ea51ba57cc80a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_84a6c0c0fbc8de393916354e16852f3f" parent="aspace_ac086db6216b305ca98ea51ba57cc80a" type="folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_063839f08cad860e681888f21eed0ea9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Transcriptions mostly from writings of a religious nature. At least one page is dated at bottom: "Topaze September 15th 1801", i.e. HMS Topaze.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref61_gzq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from "A.K." to William Farington and personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1801-1802</unitdate><container id="aspace_90472c0945ad3a00671086caa16afd6c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f40883127358fb48b0811658a0f9a283" parent="aspace_90472c0945ad3a00671086caa16afd6c" type="folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_522091c3b6ac44d70819350fc1507fca"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First item is a bifolium folded in half to produce four pages; on first page, verses from Cowper, beginning with: "God moves in a mysterious way..." and on last page: "The above verses were written by a Lady a few days before her death, &amp; left in her husband's writing desk", with remnants of a red wax seal. </item><item>Second item is a letter addressed to Lieutenant W. Farington, H.M.S. Topaze, Jamaica, with circular hole where seal once was,with header "Clifton Nov. 3d" and signed, "Affectionate friend, A.K." Header; letter begins"I wish exceedingly to unite to you my dear &amp; highly valued friend, because I am sure your wounded mind needs consolation nearly as much as ours, &amp; I am the only one from whom you can hear by this packet after the receipt of your melancholy letters-my brother is now providentially I trust at Hoddesdon..." </item><item>Third item is a letter, addressed to Mr. Farington and signed "AK" with the header "Clifton Nov 30th",which begins, "I hardly know how to hope that you can be a survivor amidst the wasting pestilence by which you have been so long surrounded..."</item><item>Fourth item is a letter with the header Clifton, Feb[ruary] 2nd" and signed "your friend, A.K", "I feel so uncommonly deprest [sic] in spirits today that I hardly know how to write a letter that will not affect yours..."</item><item>Fifth item is a letter dated "June 15th, 1802" and signed "your friend AK" which begins: "Your sister seems to think that letters from this family..." </item><item>Sixth item is a letter addressed to "Lieut. Farington, H.M.S. Carnatic Plymoth" with two stamps, one "Cross Post 25 June" and the other, "Plymouth 218".</item><item>The seventh is a letter with the header "Clifton June 25th": "Your most welcome letter my dear friend was received by my brother last night..." </item><item>The eighth item is a letter dated "Sept 6th 1802" addressed to "W. Farington Jr. Esq., Hoddesdon" with the postal stamps "Bristol Sept6 02" and "1802": "The return of this eventful day naturally..." </item><item>The ninth and final item is a single piece of paper folded in half with name "Mr. Wm Farington on last page., and signed A.K. "I will not send the book without a line in my handwriting..." </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref63_xof" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from "M. Church" to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802</unitdate><container id="aspace_ccb818c3aea6e334eb68068ff61eac98" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7c044a087b47d3c833248aa8271151af" parent="aspace_ccb818c3aea6e334eb68068ff61eac98" type="folder">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f4fcfdfc07dcd98fe8ac7396db0f49fb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First letter has header "Clifton June 28th 1802" is addressed to Lieut. Farington H.M.Ship Canartic Plymouth, signed "M.C.", and postmarked, "Bristol June 28", and begins, "Not doubting that a letter from your afflicted friend will be most acceptable". </item><item>Second letter has header "Clifton, Monday, July 5th 1802", is addressed to Lieut. Farington H.M.Ship Canartic Plymouth, is signed "M.C.", and begins, "I scarce know what to do about writing to you my dear young friend..." </item><item>Third letter has header "Clifton, Saturday July 31, 1802", is addressed to "W. Farington Jun[ior], Esq., Hoddesdon", and is signed "M.C.", and begins: "When you said 'you will allow me to write to you..." </item><item>Fourth letter has header "Clifton Sep. [9th?] 1802", is addressed to "William Farrington Esqr. Pans Wood near Didsbury, Manchester" has postal stamp "Briston Sept 25" and begins, "I should be sorry to disappoint your expectations..."</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref65_4ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal notes &amp; transcription of verse entitled, " "Ode to the Memory of Wm Cowper"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f607d62e01bca826e4907b2a558ab87" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1b80e4f0597a480fcd0a252a5df6ec43" parent="aspace_1f607d62e01bca826e4907b2a558ab87" type="folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c9f63dcea2fdb8e6da957b54a456487c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Folded sheet of paper entitled "Ode to the Memory of Wm Cowper, Esq....By the Rev.d. T. Eisborne, M.A." and signed page 4: "M.C." Smaller piece of paper contains lines, "I lend you this Book also, which treats upon the same subject as Leslie..."</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref67_y3l" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from M. Church to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802-3</unitdate><container id="aspace_514a445f7072e172198938c9b964a078" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_12b8d2e2407f1461540d5df9565a1fa2" parent="aspace_514a445f7072e172198938c9b964a078" type="folder">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a082df350f04a4b4e61610ebd4dd48a2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Dates and headings of letters are: <list type="marked"><item>Clifton, [Oct?] 16th 1802; </item><item>Clifton, [Oct?] 28th 1802;</item><item>Clifton, Dec. 5th 1802;</item><item>Clifton Thursday Dec. 9th;</item><item>Clifton Dec. 14th 1802;</item><item>Dec. [10 or 16], 1802.</item></list> All letters are from "M.C" and addressed to William Farington at several addresses: <list type="marked"><item>Pans Woood, Didsbury, Manchester;</item><item>35 Upper Charlotte Street, Fitzroy Square, London;</item><item>Hoddesdon Herts.;</item><item>on board the Bombay Castle;</item><item>Indiaman, Downs.</item></list> Interspersed with letters are transcriptions of religious writings, including those by M. Hale.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref69_3jn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Maria Church to William Farington and personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c4a08358a01325778698688984ae7af" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_18174a03aeaf18d1dc585eb5eaf877e3" parent="aspace_4c4a08358a01325778698688984ae7af" type="folder">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_12c33969d63b696c743c621859532eb2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First letter (10 pages) is undated and is signed: "your very sincere friend, Maria Church"; it opens "Oh Farington! You have been called to [?] but painful, but sacred office-I have often wished it had been mine..." and discusses her husband's death.</item><item>The second letter (4 pages) is dated "Feb. 2nd 1802" and signed "your sincere friend M.C." but also contains the note over the address "from Mr. Ward, Chaplain, of the Canartic". </item><item>The third letter (4 pages) is possibly a transcript from an earlier correspondence, and contains the postscript "This letter was written by Capt. [Trevenner?] to his wife in June 1790 just before the battle between the Swiss and Russians in which action he was killed.-an English officer in the Russian service" <list type="marked"><item>Note about Capt. Trevennor in previous letter, possibly added later. </item><item>This letter is followed by 8 pages of transcriptions from biblical and religious texts. </item></list></item><item>After this is bound a one leaf (2 pages) transcription of a letter which begins with: "Your profession in its Exercise throws great light upon a beautiful part of the 107th Psalm, the whole of which..." at end: "Extract of a letter to the dear friend whose loss I must ever deplore, but who, I trust is now in the full enjoyment of the blessings above described and which..." </item><item>Last 10 pages contain 8 pages of transcriptions from texts mostly of a religious nature followed by a letter with header "Clifton June 15th 1802", addressed to Lieut. Farington and signed "your most true and sincere friend, M.C." that begins: "The extracts I have made are so [?] my dear friend &amp; have afforded me so much &amp; w[ell?] comfort in moments of the keenest anguish..."</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref71_h57" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript containing notes and transcriptions from religious writings given by M. Church to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_afd3ed0ef397baac123a028fa9df5837" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cb71f8c6cf0d8d2d3211eb75b2ffe6b1" parent="aspace_afd3ed0ef397baac123a028fa9df5837" type="folder">32</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f7d3103ce14b392769ada65de6e63935"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First 4 pages are composed of 2 small leaves containing verses in ink; in pencil at top: "This was written by a Lady a few days before her death &amp; addressed to her husband." </item><item>Next six pages contain verses entitled "Description of an Hermit", followed by 40 pages of prose, mostly of a religious nature, ending with the note, "Let every word that my hand has traced witness for me when you are far distant-how earnestly and affectionately I wish your happiness, brother here and hereafter. M.C., Clifton, July 19th 1802".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref73_n21" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 3</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref74_5wj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Binder Covers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_61362f37a3a8d43568c4f866144738b5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_bf7c2662bbb66fda8b95eab0a9055ca8" parent="aspace_61362f37a3a8d43568c4f866144738b5" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref75_ttu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1782-3, 1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_a276144dc9125bb272325b5e7390c64f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_7161b3d285c7b2cb38b589be78c7ed37" parent="aspace_a276144dc9125bb272325b5e7390c64f" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_419872dafb3c725f302bfed8325fbeff"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First letter addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton" with Postal stamp, "17 May 1831" and signed "Mund or Jack or [?] or whatever you choose to call me..." Caricature at bottom of final page, seems to be in juvenile script. </item><item>Second letter headed, "Madrass Roads 16th May 1783", with salutatory "My de[are?]st Life" and signed "Wm Farington"; discusses Brazil, China, and Bombay.</item><item>Third letter unsigned but in same hand and with same ink as previous letter, heading: "St. Salvador in the Bay of all Saints on the Coast of Brazil Lat. 13.00 South-Wednesday, 11th December, 1782" begins, "My wonderful love, This will be the first letter that it has been in my power to send to thee, for when Lord [?] left us, he to proceed to Gibraltar us to the East Indies, we had not the least previous notice..."</item><item>Following that is a section or draft of a letter, dated "Tuesday, 17th December 1782", signed vertically "of the most affectionate love of thy Husband, Wm Farington". Paper is folded in half over previous three items to produce an informal packet, and on the front of this piece of paper is written in pencil "Brazil".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref77_tgu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1784, 1814-1815, 1841</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4d1357435c6c997e7fa5de2845c0618" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_5d543485dad69ad3628a7ccbf57dab44" parent="aspace_e4d1357435c6c997e7fa5de2845c0618" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e0c9ba32f0c36bbb590c58f530f11ee"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First letter is from William Farington to his wife, header: "Ship General loot 5th February 178[4?]", and references China.</item><item>Second letter is cross-written and dated Oct. 19 with postal stamps for 1814, and is addressed to "Mrs. Farington, Post Office, Edinburgh, N. Britain". It contains remnants of a red wax seal and hole were seal was once affixed.</item><item>Third letter is headed "Br[?]lles, [Dec?] 29" with a postal stamp: "Jan W 7 M 1815". It is cross-written and addressed to "Mrs. Farington, Post Office, Edinburgh, N. Britain".</item><item>Fourth letter is cross-written, with header, "Br[?]lles, Dec. 13" and contains postal stamps: "DEC W 30 M 1814" and "DE A 27 1814". It is addressed to "Mrs. Farington, Post Office, Edinburgh, N. Britain" and a Red wax seal of a boar still affixed. </item><item>Fifth letter has header, Worden, March 18th 1841" and is signed "Yours very faithfully, [I/J?] Nowell Farington". It is addressed to "W. Farington, Esq., Woodvale, Cowes, Isle of Wight" and contains postal stamps: "Chorley: M 18, 184[?] and "19 MR 1841". The paper on which it is written contains the watermark "J Whatman 1838" and the remnants of a black wax seal is still attached. Letter shares condolences for the death of Farington's sister. Fifth letter is a single sheet of paper containing a letter or draft of a letter, signed "William Farrington" with the salutation "My dear love".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref79_wf1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington from his younger siblings Edmund, Richard, and Frances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1829, 1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_884f7307b3a715b0ce524fbc75c6a422" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_8d39b0f7ee065bcdcb8f8986779c98ca" parent="aspace_884f7307b3a715b0ce524fbc75c6a422" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb153324c458a4cb55ed611083e79180"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First letter has header, "Warfield Sunday 18th, 1829" and is addressed to "Mr. W. Farington, Commoners, Winton" with postal stamp "1829" and watermark "G &amp; R Turner 1826" and begins, "Dear William will you be so good as to send me a needle and mesh..." </item><item>Second letter has header, "Warfield, May 10 1829" and is addressed to "Mr. W Farington, Commoners Winchester", with watermark "G and R Turner 1827" and is signed: "believe me my Dearest Brother ever to remain yours affectionately, Edmund Farington". </item><item>Third letter is undated (though the paper has the watermark "1829"), is addressed to "William" and is signed "your most affectionate sister Frances Ann Farington". </item><item>The fourth letter has header "Warfield, Tues, Oct 4, 1831" and is addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton". It is signed "Ever yours, [E?] Farrington". In a second hand, which is large, within pencil ruling, juvenile, and calligraphic is written: "My dear William I hope you are quite well..." and is signed "your R A F." </item><item>The fifth letter has header "Warfield, Sunday, Sept 25 1831" with postal stamp "D. 27 Sept. 1831" and is addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton". It is written in two hands and signed by both "E. Farington" and "R.A.F".</item><item>The sixth letter has header, "Warfield, Sunday May 31st 1829, and is signed "Edmund Farington" and addressed to "Mr. William Farington, Commoners, Winchester"; </item><item>it is followed by a small note, signed "C. Faithfull" and addressed to "Master Farrington" and invites him to a birthday celebration. </item><item>The eighth letter has header "Warfield, Sund. Oct 15, 1831", is addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton" and is written in two hands, signed "[?].F. and R.A. Farington".</item><item>The ninth letter has header "Warfield, Sunday 8 1829", contains a list of names and red wax seal, and is addressed to "W. Farrington at the Rev. Dr. Williams, Commoners, Winchester" and is signed "E. Farington". The tenth letter has a black border and is signed your "very affectionate Sister, Frances Ann Farington". It is undated in the original ink hand, but in pencil is written, "Nov. 6 1829". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref81_s8q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington from younger siblings, Edmund, Frances Ann and Richard, his friend William Macgregor, and his mother</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1825, 1827-1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_56862cf8e6c661c5468a5c63fa156b77" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_7712b2add7063453ec8d9f2a5065b089" parent="aspace_56862cf8e6c661c5468a5c63fa156b77" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e215e8c1966e0ec09e646b412b6f18e6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First letter is written in a large, juvenile, calligraphic hand within pencil ruling to "My dear Willy" and is signed "your affect[ionate] brother Richard, Nov. 26, 1829". </item><item>The second letter is written to William from his sister Frances Ann Farrington and in a different hand and ink is headed "Wood Vale, October 21st 1829". </item><item>The third letter is has header, "14 Saville Row London" and, in pencil "July 1828" and is signed "Your affectionate schoolfellow, William Macgregor". </item><item>The fourth letter has header "Woodvale July 22 1827" and is addressed to William Farington at two different locations (Isle of Wight and Warfield) from his mother. It contains an ink sketch of a ship and sailing flag. </item><item>The fifth letter to William Farington from his mother, "J.A. Farington, Woodvale May 31, 1827". This is followed by a scrap of paper containing notes and a red seal.</item><item>Sixth letter has header "Woodvale February 24th '25" and is from Edmund; contains postal stamp "D 25FF25 1825" and red wax seal.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref83_pu9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from William Farington to his wife Fanny.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 May 02 - June 07</unitdate><container id="aspace_eadc0f4db0c94bb27599e5aa8e18338b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_925aba51e6c2ffd6697a45213f465e1e" parent="aspace_eadc0f4db0c94bb27599e5aa8e18338b" type="folder">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref84_i25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence of William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 July 06 - 17</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c3265d37472a544272279169a7020b3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_3c71b5cf58f3e62bb6c115d681135423" parent="aspace_8c3265d37472a544272279169a7020b3" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1bd7ef8bec52000b0cfba322e180755d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Though not signed, appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife. Contains entries for correspondence and verse. The scrap of paper intermingled with the pages contains the address "HMS Clio off [?] July 15th / [Mrs./Wm?]Farington" and a street address in [Edinbury?].</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref86_9wo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence of William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 July 17</unitdate><container id="aspace_5610e112032693478020fa7fa6aeb054" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f68a7b7fc544b69dc867d4ea84de59fd" parent="aspace_5610e112032693478020fa7fa6aeb054" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f634322f3e66183497dd202de4b0920"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appears to be a continuation of the correspondence in the previous folder. Contains both verse and prose, and one sheet contains the date "Sunday [Morn.?] July 17th 1814 and the address [Mrs.?] Farington / M[r/rs?] Me[?]'s Lodgings / Princess Street / Edinbu[ry?]".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref88_ug4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence of William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 July 28 - August 06</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5350ed7fdccfeda0d99f195df9bbe5c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_012f57af00c1a3277ec83506cd756ea6" parent="aspace_c5350ed7fdccfeda0d99f195df9bbe5c" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_876023f6b026d4987840322fb40b445c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife Fanny--contains both prose and verse addressed to her.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref90_u5r" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence of William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 September 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_78c6dcc0f394ae91cb52aff0685341c2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_09a4f8c41e8d34d86286f5535b6a63c0" parent="aspace_78c6dcc0f394ae91cb52aff0685341c2" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_622dc3f9bc7d2b1cbe22fe4627016bde"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife Fanny--contains both prose and verse addressed to her.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref92_8jx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence of William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1818</unitdate><container id="aspace_96715c4e6ba421f5774ecc2c183016dd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_5735e7e4c48f6ecc1609d5a392f74921" parent="aspace_96715c4e6ba421f5774ecc2c183016dd" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c421e6ecc71f14a391468705d42969d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife --contains both prose and verse addressed to her. Throughout the pages are small sketches.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref94_l8z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence of William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814-1815</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8246d88f78857edd84ec877b3ae4f2e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_e330e7bbe01c6cd7ae49159bd1e09a5b" parent="aspace_a8246d88f78857edd84ec877b3ae4f2e" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd952042c090728aa90d4c6796383f28"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondence from William Farington to his wife.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref96_2lq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 4</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref97_m30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster used as Binder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2e20432de026c82dcb4d44ca6701c7a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_316fe4877e3740f15b32d45f2b73c4b9" parent="aspace_f2e20432de026c82dcb4d44ca6701c7a" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa10a6ab0115fa883d9b726fe07632f0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Poster reproduction of 1892 painting "Bonnie Prince Charlie" by the Royal Academian John Pattie; <list type="marked"><item>at top margin, "Supplement to 'Holly Leaves,' The Christmas Number of 'The Illustrated Sporting and Dramatic news,' November 20, 1939." </item><item>Folded in two ad used as an informal binder for correspondence items. </item><item>On backside of poster is written in pencil, "To Joseph Farington from his father, Rev. W.F." (i.e. Rev. William Farington (d. 1767), not to be confused with his son William Farington (d. 1803), or his grandson of the same name, whose correspondences are also included in the collection).</item></list> </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref99_efx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1762 January 26; 1763 June 21 - November 29</unitdate><container id="aspace_4204899e6d76f0d80a41cad789fa9900" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_ad86abfa25fc0424bc5f317abfb4452d" parent="aspace_4204899e6d76f0d80a41cad789fa9900" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf31c7c93a6dd6c47d5102a853d9bd38"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, future Royal Academian, while he was studying art under Mr. Wilson in London. </item><item>The letters discuss personal expenses, London life, and Joseph's drawings, and impart fatherly advice. </item><item>Two letters (dated: October 6th 1763 and November 15th, 1763) discuss specific pieces of artwork Joseph had sent home, including sketches of Hercules, ruins, Christ, and St. Paul.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref101_2q1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1764 January 20 - December 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_709ce612563c6979c4dc4a84460bea34" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_a5ab2ec8a0770f66a3f2ab7cc8a6f870" parent="aspace_709ce612563c6979c4dc4a84460bea34" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f028986b0bfcfcc25e28ac65005dc2df"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, while he was studying art in London.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref103_dcr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1764 (October 25th?)</unitdate><container id="aspace_40c9328ce6cdcab006b519502f856f3f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_9227368220825849eb4bb02974ca54cd" parent="aspace_40c9328ce6cdcab006b519502f856f3f" type="folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_411679d1fd5079e3b8e0bc0020cc82d5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Personal correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref105_nw2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1764 June 16 - 1767 July 12</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2c7c6734a865c696cb0d149503d0336" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_505e0dfd528d2f32efdcc290ee91c599" parent="aspace_e2c7c6734a865c696cb0d149503d0336" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00cdfff892d9c5fecca76893b6ae8cbd"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Eleven letters, showing various degrees of wear and tearing, all but one of which are dated. These letters, which are from Rev. William Farington to his son Joseph, mostly date from the years 1766-1767 and are addressed to several locations: <list type="marked"><item>"The Rev. Mr. Jacobs in Long Acre, London",</item><item>"Mrs. Luthers in Thrift-Street, Soho, London",</item><item>"Mrs. Macquoy's in York Buildings, Strand,"</item><item>"Mr. Wilsons, Painter, the Great Piazza, Covent Garden, London". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref107_f69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1765 June 21 - December 19</unitdate><container id="aspace_b49910433d9ef53b75cee8d8a9309491" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c25d03a7ab8f6deb295093ecd2e43a67" parent="aspace_b49910433d9ef53b75cee8d8a9309491" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8168122a4e1040fbeb698f7c5352fb43"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Letters discuss personal affairs, finances, and art.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref109_k4y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Joseph Farington from father Rev. William Farington and brother George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1765</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1371120145585417b8d6b51db9a8329" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_057a9704541715a70d4f5ed3d412f281" parent="aspace_e1371120145585417b8d6b51db9a8329" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_54763e962e7302afb373cebcbba05800"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Personal correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref111_pt3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 5</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref112_6gk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster used as Binder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_f11b78df3a186cdf7f34f715bd6a274c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_acc07f0d15c07c6847d94174c7212859" parent="aspace_f11b78df3a186cdf7f34f715bd6a274c" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6e766adeebc9df40231a965f24d1a12a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Poster reproduction of 1892 painting "Bonnie Prince Charlie" by the Royal Academian John Pattie; <list type="marked"><item>at top margin, "Supplement to 'Holly Leaves,' The Christmas Number of 'The Illustrated Sporting and Dramatic news,' November 20, 1939." </item><item>Folded in two ad used as an informal binder for correspondence items. </item><item>On backside of poster is written in pencil, "To Will Farington from his father- Rev W.F." </item><item>To this poster was attached by paper clip a small piece of paper on which is written "Misc. Mss. 100/x8 Farington 4"</item></list> </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref114_jgt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to his son William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1762 March 16 - 1766 December 13</unitdate><container id="aspace_b56a2132e63f03c3909ff18e0959fede" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_1cdbe07f33f19d71e47499890577404a" parent="aspace_b56a2132e63f03c3909ff18e0959fede" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11df1a8a53dfc40a4ad0cf7f23811dd4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Mostly correspondence from Rev. William Farington to his son William Farington, addressed to several locations, including, Broad Street, London; </item><item>on board the Reward, Captain Richard Saunders, Outward Bound, at Falmouth;</item><item>on board the Neptune;</item><item>on board the Egmont.</item><item>In addition to Rev. Farington's letters to his son, there is a letter labeled by the younger William Farington, "Copy of a Letter from my Father to Mr. Jonathan Brideoake about my going to Sea, Leigh 3rd August 1762", as well as the draft of a letter, possibly to William's captain, dated 28 November 1762. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref116_n11" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 6</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref117_inb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster used as Binder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a10958382554fb495d09df32c8ffd297" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_70b3226fdb1a09a6cf6519308c6e3254" parent="aspace_a10958382554fb495d09df32c8ffd297" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_105258a3eb80cba6ff155c035c7d4847"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>In pencil, "Farrington Misc Letters not relating to Joseph F."</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref119_5ly" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between Rev. William Farington and his nephew William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1756 March 29 - 1772 January 10</unitdate><container id="aspace_d82f47f88c62947949b68d9b73e5ae94" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_f1d5ed4c883d799bc034bc7784d0b6b1" parent="aspace_d82f47f88c62947949b68d9b73e5ae94" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1b5d502824557c564cf49ed5b5a7fa3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Dates of letters are: <list type="marked"><item>Jan 31, 1761 (from nephew William Farington regarding his recommendation for the position of Sheriff); </item><item>March 29 1756; </item><item>August 6, 1765; </item><item>April 22, 1767; </item><item>Jan 10, 1772 (from uncle to nephew regarding his own serious illness); </item><item>and December 4, 1764.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref121_dof" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1773 November 08 - 1778 April 19</unitdate><container id="aspace_55cc582ee22967596f9d3cd084b5d987" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_38fe038c615c321d23b79a689b45e0de" parent="aspace_55cc582ee22967596f9d3cd084b5d987" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b89634b4c53ddafd5158aec2caf4e30"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Dates of letters are: <list type="marked"><item>September 7, 1777; </item><item>November 30, 1777; </item><item>April 19, 1778; </item><item>November 8, 1773.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref123_4bq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Farington Family Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1767 June 10 - 1785 January 29</unitdate><container id="aspace_18fb4bcc0a956f7b8533394c5e5bec11" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_01f69bfd03f315f935461bf92542b9b8" parent="aspace_18fb4bcc0a956f7b8533394c5e5bec11" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e3798dd85924e954e6688372ba9a2591"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Dates of letters are: <list type="marked"><item>July 30, 1769 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William);</item><item>November 28, 1777 (William Farington to cousin William Farington); </item><item>September 22, 1779 (William Farington to cousin William Farington); </item><item>May 28, 1780 (William Farington to cousin William Farington); </item><item>December 8, 1772 (William Farington to cousin William Farington);</item><item>June 5, 1774 (R.A. Farington to his mother);</item><item>June 10, 1767 (from Lucy Wright to her brother); </item><item>January 29 1785 (to Edward Farington from a brother?);</item><item>March 6, 1774 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William);</item><item>June 3, 1776 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William);</item><item>January 31 1773 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William);</item><item>and December 11, 1772 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William). </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref125_40m" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 7</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref126_gqa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster used as Binder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_87e41486108ce63bc78b4def6671e0df" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_e52f41f3ae690486f30c834c3efc6c84" parent="aspace_87e41486108ce63bc78b4def6671e0df" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_901b9df3583df5366bc270b11440bde1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Labeled at bottom "The Times. Map of the North-Eastern Theatre of War"; in pencil on back, "Will of Rev. W. Farington (Father of Joseph F.) and other papers, letters, etc. relating to him".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref128_ocr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health-related correspondence and personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1739 June 19 - 1750 September 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb279987d0a4c35aa313f492785ab95a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_d4eb168bfb149cf29ea5994fcb292f90" parent="aspace_bb279987d0a4c35aa313f492785ab95a" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e607158952a343c00a429595f479a18"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Three letters which are pasted together concern pharmaceutical remedies for vomiting and the gout, and are dated June 19, 1739; July 4, 1748; and Sept. 11 1750.</item><item>The 3 sheets of paper placed inside of this folded paper are undated and similarly discuss the gout. </item><item>One paper is labeled as "Cheyne's Essay on the Gout p. 15" (i.e. George Cheyne's 1719 publication). </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref130_zne" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington regarding the death of his relation William Farington and the execution of his will.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1747 July 10 - 1760 February 27</unitdate><container id="aspace_528493cdf340342bc96dd762ca9e77af" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_d5545c346f643579837b7914a0b0b778" parent="aspace_528493cdf340342bc96dd762ca9e77af" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ef1fca1269e2fdc0c7fe35ffcbbf392a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Despite the title of the paper binder, some of the correspondence predates or postdates 1781 significantly. The dates of the letters are: <list type="marked"><item>July 10, 1747 (to Rev. Farington from his nephew William Farington);</item><item>Sept. 28, 1753 (to Rev. Farington from his nephew William Farington); </item><item>June 26, 1857 (from Frederick Loch regarding the barring of an entail created by the wife of Sir William Farington); </item><item>Feb. 27, 1760 (to Rev. Farington from his nephew William Farington);</item><item>January 16, 1781 (addressed to Shaw Hall and regarding the execution of a will from Gill S[later?]); </item><item>and Jan. 15, 1781 also from Gill S[later?]. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref132_ode" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1702 December 25 - 1802 March 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fdfab48dfd652d371bb3564cd4b19e5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_d3c9b56a764543d3caccdd33c072a7dd" parent="aspace_5fdfab48dfd652d371bb3564cd4b19e5" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5115a9491ca4c8dbd4b6c58ca4f8a586"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Dates are: <list type="marked"><item>1702 December 25 (from Elizabeth Farington to her son Robert Farington in London); </item><item>1762 December 30 (to Rev. Farington); </item><item>April 23 1740; (to Rev. Farington);</item><item>Sept 14 1767;</item><item>July 15 1765 (to Rev. Farington from James Parr); </item><item>March 7 1763 (to Rev. Farington from James Parr);</item><item>November 17 1746 (to Rev. Farington from James Parr);</item><item>March 16, 1802; </item><item>small note dated July 1, 1803 regarding Rev. Robert Farington's candidacy for the degree of DD at Brasenose College, Oxford;</item><item>small note dated March 14, 1802;</item><item>July 15, 1760;</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref134_tie" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1738 October 09 - 1746 December 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_1cf92401a89c2144bb3e248a1f637a6d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_ee9c3349cc860a5ebfe895615d0b167a" parent="aspace_1cf92401a89c2144bb3e248a1f637a6d" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2e61f33fc2e6e9ede7db8963b19aa26"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>On first sheet of paper, one side contains correspondence to Rev. Farington from Eliz[abeth] [Gouldsmith?], and the opposite side contains correspondence dated Oct. 9, 1738 from "[your] most affectionate nephew Robert G[willym?]". </item><item>The second piece of paper is addressed to "William Farington Esq at Shaw Hall" from "John Whitley Oct. 5, 1745".</item><item>The third letter is addressed to "Rev. Mr. Farington, Vicar of Leigh" from J. Parr and is dated Dec. 16, 1746.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref136_hn8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Last Will and Testament of Rev. William Farington; Articles of Agreement between William Farington and George Farington; Personal Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1742 May 01 - 1848</unitdate><container id="aspace_0548d267fbd6360b5156277f8ce2fd5e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_5e6a5dfac513ae8505afb04737710c8f" parent="aspace_0548d267fbd6360b5156277f8ce2fd5e" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe4c75061e4d036e449d070cec41813a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>On front of paper binder, several sections of writing, in similar or identical hands, in pencil, brown ink, and black ink: <list type="marked"><item>"The Will of my Reverend Grandfather is here /</item><item> Cutting off the entail, by George Farington and his son William afterwards (des Wm: [Kh?]) [?] George Farington (Eldest Brother of my Grandfather William) and his eldest son William - 1 May 1742 / </item><item>and a letter from James Farington, younger brother of the said William and father of the late William the father of James Noel Farington (who died in 1837) to his uncle my Grandfather William - the letter dated May 17th 1755 [?] strange proof of the State she [a lot?] respectable family here [addressed?] to Wm Farington Capt. R.A. August 3rd 1848 / </item><item>Also a letter from Bradshaw ["Bradshaw" here crossed out with pencil and "James" inserted] FF to his uncle my grandfather WF 1857 /</item><item>NB: The will which Sir William made he entails it, naming Each of his cousins my uncles and father-- is in our paper safe or box." William Farington's will is signed by himself, John Lowe, and Bradley [?] and is dated July 4, 1765. </item><item>The Articles of Agreement "between William Farington, son and heir apparent of George Farington of Shaw Hall in the county of Lancaster" is dated May 1, 1742 and contains William Farington and E. Farington's signatures. </item><item>An expense sheet is included and is dated June 17th, 1748 and also contains the date Jan. 24th 1749: "cashe in Mr. Tho[mas] Whittaker's hand to be divided betwixt him and me". </item><item>A letter dated May 17, 1755 from James Farington is pasted onto the stiff paper board which forms a binder for the materials. </item><item>At the bottom of the letter a different hand writes, "The original on the other side from James brother of Sir William, nephew to my good Grandfather Rev. William, and father of the late Grandfather of the present owner of Worden [that] Hall [?] of our family, W. Farington Capt. Aug, 1846". </item><item>This note continues on the stiff paper board: "His (James') brother cast him out of the estate, settling it upon his (James) son William, entailing it upon his uncle the Rev. William [son] in succession. William with his son James Noel cast [off?] the [entail?] from -- -- 1813 / James Noel [married?] Oct 28th 1847, [died?] 6 June 1848." </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref138_sms" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal correspondence, notes, and legal document</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1737 May 5 - 1779 April 26</unitdate><container id="aspace_470c6c89a3869623b250166b2de845c4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_177721dd2b6d72a28929306e25be2e2a" parent="aspace_470c6c89a3869623b250166b2de845c4" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ab950356845ff51ea8475167c9d9abc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>A page labeled April 26, 1779 discusses an incident of forced braking and entering at the writer's residence.</item><item>There are two pieces of correspondence, the first is dated December 7, 1766 and is addressed to Rev. Mr. Farington from his nephew R.V.A [Gwillym?] and the second is dated November 27, 1766 and is addressed to the Rev. Mr. Farington from J. Whitakker. </item><item>There is also a copy of a letter dated November 25, 1760 addressed to the soon-to-be-coronated King (i.e. George III) congratulating him, bearing the names of several local vicars.</item><item>Also included is a notarized document signed by Elizabeth Gouldsmyth, widow of Richard Atherton, Esq., granting her brother Rev. William Farington power of attorney and instituting an annuity, signed May 5, 1737. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref140_tne" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal correspondence, notes, and expense records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1750 August 06 - 1765 April 01</unitdate><container id="aspace_d085c5809a6b97dd033c3845fc78c583" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_1b2db039a59d98cb28936545639dd381" parent="aspace_d085c5809a6b97dd033c3845fc78c583" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2b6386bdf2843f0d864fc30f529ae65"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>Included is a letter labeled "Copy of Sr. Wm Farington's Letter from Rome" with heading "Rome April 1, 1765" and signed William Farington. </item><item>The second letter contains a record of expenses and bears date Aug 6, 1750. </item><item>The third sheet of paper is a chart of expenses and events for March 16th - July 3rd 1763.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref142_uma" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between Sir William Meredith and G. Kendal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1761 March 7</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bd01a956cab23656d852aa72be04f09" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_809682c191a3eb6cffd0b10f009b408a" parent="aspace_2bd01a956cab23656d852aa72be04f09" type="folder">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref143_3y8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence and personal notes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1749 June 24 - 1853 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_27456a1f7bfacbc1bc48fa73c6f26be0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_2351e89fc4b16cd6d9274c38db6c4998" parent="aspace_27456a1f7bfacbc1bc48fa73c6f26be0" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd39c725dfb25d24f81ac913f1d4987b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First item is a single page, undated of personal notes related to the vicarage of Leigh.</item><item>The second item is a sheet of paper folded in half to produce four pages, on which are written a verse entitled "Thanks for [?] Huswife, addressed to Miss Dolly Grandwell".</item><item>The third item is a single page of notes dated "June 24, 17[4?]7".</item><item>The fourth item is a letter (it is unclear whom the writer or addressee are) reinforced on the backside with rag paper. Because the writing continues onto the second side, it is partially obscured by the transparent rag paper, but the date "23 July 1750" is visible. </item><item>The fifth item is correspondence between Rev. William Farington and his nephew William Farington dated Oct. 3, 1766.</item><item>The sixth item is undated, unsigned correspondence.</item><item>The seventh item consists of two letters, one smaller and one larger contained within a small, transparent paper wrapper on which is written "Copy of a letter from Sir William Farington to my father William Farington his first cousin. This was copied and sent to me by Susan Farington sister [Noel?] Farington". Inside this wrapper is a small letter dated 1772 with the note "This was copied and sent to me (WF) March 1853" in the inner margin. Also pasted inside this wrapper is a larger letter from William Farington dated 14 Dec. 1762.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref145_s9n" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 8</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref146_bzk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrap paper used as binder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2741c401140061df192af3aa6b85813b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_333e7b68bbf0dac74b8e5acf2db980de" parent="aspace_2741c401140061df192af3aa6b85813b" type="folder">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref147_duw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes relating to the North Briton periodical, Church History, and a "Meditation for Christmas Day"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7ed5a45cac1880840da2c3423a3ca44" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_ac3e24b2b1fb23fbb26c8961f2517a24" parent="aspace_b7ed5a45cac1880840da2c3423a3ca44" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25f2eaadefd135266201264a5d46f357"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The first paper is entitled "The Pope's Introduction of those Realms began the first Sunday after Easter 1208" and contains notes on Church history and excommunication.</item><item>The second, third, fourth, and fifth papers contain transcriptions of, or notes relating to, the North Briton periodical (known for its radicalism) issues 50 and 51 and contain the dates June 9, 1768 and May 28, 1768. </item><item>There is also an undated paper entitled "Meditation for Christmas Day". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref149_j4e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Notes and Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1738 June 20 -July 08</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b38cce5d809dd88dcc7b44164ff884a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_0f63f8eb452531b4f640447c505d62db" parent="aspace_0b38cce5d809dd88dcc7b44164ff884a" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_62e64af28cecef67a5b3442b79cef295"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The first paper is a letter dated "August 20", addressed "Dear Madam" and signed "Mr. Hall". </item><item>The second and third papers have personal notes of a religious nature.</item><item>The fourth paper is folded in half to produce four pages, on which are written "On the Chorus of the Ancient Drama". </item><item>The fifth paper contains notes in Latin, </item><item>the sixth contains a selection entitled "Written in a window of the Saracen's Head in [C]oventry...",</item><item>the seventh contains a transcription of "A Pastoral by Mr. Broome, Astrophel and Daphne", </item><item>the eight contains writing followed by the note, "This is put over an effigy of Dr. Radclif in the new building of University College,</item><item>the ninth contains a "Scotch song" on one side and astronomical data on the other, </item><item>and the tenth is a sheet of paper folded in half with several dates and sections of notes, ranging from May 4, 1675 to February 3, 1731. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref151_bj2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document related to the Nomination of a Schoolmaster for the Grammar School at the Parish of Leigh</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a4a991576b92723b73b00af29e95f93" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_30f06ef3aae07cfcb288f198135af2e6" parent="aspace_4a4a991576b92723b73b00af29e95f93" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba7ae4c73706cb4e3724f17f0d8f4888"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Entitled: "The Case of the Vicar and Parish [?] of the Parish of Leigh relating to the Nomination of a Schoolmaster of the School in the Tower and Parish of Leigh aforsaid". At bottom of first page lists four dates of relevance for the history of the grammar school: 18 Sept 1694, 1704, 1726 Nov 2, 1735 April 23</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref153_2gb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Will of Thomas Armstriding</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_0089b720667e13ab21a4f05769dbd9e2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_aa713071cade60f8548a01fa58e83f1a" parent="aspace_0089b720667e13ab21a4f05769dbd9e2" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1724df4e5aedc87d5ea9ac98fbe3f322"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Will or draft of will of Thomas Armstriding, "Vicar of the parish and the parish Church of [Loy?]land in the County of Lancaster".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref155_fyn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Notes and Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1734 May 18 - June 25 1767</unitdate><container id="aspace_810fc092437c2c0123037bcce1dbb5a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_4d86143bec9869db44c208dc6a3ba611" parent="aspace_810fc092437c2c0123037bcce1dbb5a8" type="folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd685cf7a7eb0ca3310fe4cd13b2188c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First item is a small note dated May 18, 1734;</item><item>second item is a small note dated June 25, 1767 with heading "Rec'd this paper from Mr Hartley" regarding "income from the school". </item><item>Third item is a small expense sheet with date 1767 and name "Mr. Whittacker" written on it. </item><item>Fourth item is an oblong sheet of paper pasted on top of another sheet, also with writing on it and barely visible through upper layer; the top sheet of paper has heading, "A Paraphrase on Charity the 13th Ch.1 Ep. To the Corinthians". </item><item>Fifth item contains religious verses,</item><item>sixth item is an undated latter from Edward Brailsford to Mrs. Allen at Cookham. </item><item>Seventh item is a remedy/treatment protocol for a medical ailment dated May 26, 1740.</item><item>Eighth item is an undated bifolium-size sheet of paper folded in half to make 4 pages, with writing in Latin. </item><item>Ninth item is a bifolium-size sheet of paper folded in half to make 4 pages, the first two of which are written on; it is undated, has heading "Government of the Thoughts Archbishop of York" and contains writing of a religious nature.</item><item>Tenth item is a folium- sized sheet of paper containing verses which begin with "Conduct the steps of my unguarded youth..." </item><item>Eleventh item is a single sheet of paper with writing on both sides; first side begins, "Sacred to the Remains of Lady Herietta Beard, Only Daughter of [the?] late Earl of Waldegrave in the Year 1734" and date 31 May 1753 at bottom of page. On opposite page is written another eulogy, this one for Mary Basnett, "Daughter of Thomas &amp; Ann Basnett of this Parish died the 10th of Feb. 1756 aged 23." </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref157_wwd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 9</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref158_ky8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1775 March 29 - 1779 March 30</unitdate><container id="aspace_be2f8c45dc59e742e67f298540f8d8d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_7d935b1c7f285912ed1a8d52e1b5584b" parent="aspace_be2f8c45dc59e742e67f298540f8d8d6" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6eac4affd6874c408dac0aa781ff037"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These papers were not contained in a binder as are most of the other items in this collection. <list type="marked"><item>On final page, the address "Mr. Geo Farington [?] at Mr. Boydell's Cheapside London". </item><item>The items are partially bound together and consist of letters dated 1775, 1776, and 1779. </item><item>The salutations are simply "Sir" and the letters are signed [Oxford?].</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref160_xgm" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 10</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref161_o1x" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster used as binder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_45771f3dadcfbaa489c8f7b7f3e3a705" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_19e27267368cf1778536aa36ad9fddbc" parent="aspace_45771f3dadcfbaa489c8f7b7f3e3a705" type="folder">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref162_8xd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Joseph Farington to his relative William Farington and his father Rev. William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1767 May - 1821 September 3</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d0bdd7272b180c23354986380871f10" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_1273a028c4eab59a9fac0777ec29d4b5" parent="aspace_5d0bdd7272b180c23354986380871f10" type="folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61c7f4686ce6bc8e2c2dcf4105cfa8f9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>First item is a label-sized slip of paper on which is written "Joseph Farington R.A. / Letter to, and from." All other items are letters of correspondence. </item><item>The second item is a letter on a single sheet of paper dated September 3, 1821 from Joseph Farington to William Farington regarding travel plans. </item><item>The third item is a letter on a single page dated Sept. 20, 1815 from Joseph Farington to "Mrs. Farington", presumably William's wife, informing her of her husband's promotion to the rank of Port Captain. </item><item>The fourth through eighteenth items are all letters from Joseph Farington to William Farington with the following dates: <list type="marked"><item>August 2, 1815; </item><item>June 28 1820 (attached to this letter with a black seal is an invitation dated March 27, 1820); </item><item>March 30, 1815;</item><item>March 10, 1815;</item><item>January 28, 1815;</item><item>March 24, 1808;</item><item>February 20, 1808;</item><item>January 11, 1808;</item><item>July 2, 1807;</item><item>July 22, 1807;</item><item>October 6, 1806;</item><item>June 9, 1806;</item><item>December 1805;</item><item>September 1799 (a different page of the same letter is a "Copy of a letter from Sir Alan Gardiner" dated September 26, 1799).</item></list> </item><item>Also included are a letter dated may 1767 from Joseph Farington to his father Rev. William Farington and a letter from Joseph Farington to Lieutenant William Farington dated May 3, 1808.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref164_1kh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bookseller's note</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_58e90e1fd53a96ed26bacc32128909a7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_a1025e5e6145f4861eae6badc1926646" parent="aspace_58e90e1fd53a96ed26bacc32128909a7" type="folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c258f68c748107527403ae86edb021da"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>"Myer's &amp; Co. (BOOKSELLERS) LTD. / 80, New Bond Street, London, W.1, England." In pen: "In this folder...3 letters from Lord Oxford (Walpole) 1775-79, Letters from Shaw Hall re house parties, references to Lady Derby, [Coka?], Jerningham, etc."</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref166_ibo" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 11</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref167_uv2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leather and cardboard binder with string and</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_565d1cc040998dcccec15beca218954d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_b39e3e63f3396f0a2555093a29713c6a" parent="aspace_565d1cc040998dcccec15beca218954d" type="folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_352734e78062f1e94548ad0dafa47d24"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Labeled: "William Farington 8 folders / Early juvenile letters circa 1783 / Very large lettering / Nautical Travels 1783 as far apart as Madras and Brazil".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref169_dmp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Farington Family Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1832 March 19 - 1855 April 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_0da133aae4730dee0ae5600340b2ecd9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_11f642dd71a64d8b99c0c60538688601" parent="aspace_0da133aae4730dee0ae5600340b2ecd9" type="folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5cd71792a8ec99206affec9ca844802d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Most of the correspondence is addressed to Mrs. Fanny Farington, wife of Captain William Farington. <list type="marked"><item>The first item is a letter from William Farington to Fanny dated April 27, [?];</item><item>the second item is a letter to Captain Farington from "Syd: S[?]ke"; </item><item>the third item is an undated letter from William Farington to his wife Fanny in which he discusses the loss of a ship that makes "Father a ruined man";</item><item>the fourth item is a letter of consolation to Captain Farington from a friend dated March 19, 1832;</item><item>the fifth item is a letter to Mrs. Farington from P. Watson dated February 24, 1832;</item><item>the sixth letter is undated and addressed to Mrs. Farington; </item><item>the seventh letter is dated December 12, 1832 and is from Capt. Farington to his wife;</item><item>the eighth letter is dated September 3, 1833 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington;</item><item>the ninth letter is dated July 1834 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from G. Dickenson; </item><item>the tenth letter is dated April 18, 1855 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from Maria Love Robertson;</item><item>the eleventh letter is addressed to Mrs. Farington and dated September 25, 1835; </item><item>the twelfth letter is dated May 11, 1836 and is from Capt. Farington to his wife; </item><item>the thirteenth letter is dated November 8, 1837 and is addressed to William Farington, "To my dear Godson";</item><item>the fourteenth letter is dated November 4, 1839 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from "A.M. S[?]th";</item><item>the fifteenth letter is dated november 1839 and is addressed to Mrs. Farington from "[?] Gardener";</item><item>the sixteenth letter is dated March 5, 1833 and is from J.A. Farington to E. Farington. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref171_2zp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Farington Family Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 June 27 - 1858 February 25</unitdate><container id="aspace_54a9d87b9026610981e771a6435f7f0a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_efa9dfa4b12f5d79de46dc8839a55de3" parent="aspace_54a9d87b9026610981e771a6435f7f0a" type="folder">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49d22073dfb757da6ee342b72f9dd33c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>All but two of the letters are addressed to William Farington from his father, mother, and sister Frances Ann and other correspondents. These other two are addressed to Edmund Farington). The dates of the letters are: June 27, 1814; August 1, 18[??]; 1838; November 30, 1838; December 20, 1838; April 25, 1838; October 22, 1830; Easter Day, 1839; November 1, 1838; October 26, 1830; 1839; February 25, 1858; September 30, 1838; September 18, 1838; March 18 [????]; October 5, 1838; January 5, 1837; M[?] 29, 1837; October 11, 1838; August 29, 1839; July 25, 1839; December 27, 1839; March 7, 1834; May 13, 1840; March 13, 1840; March 28 [????]; January 13, 1837; March 25, 1840.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref173_y14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1830 May 04 - 1840 May 08</unitdate><container id="aspace_4349dbbdf8483384f8f79b78624159fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_b4a20e1cbf6bb513dcaad17cfa5cb6fb" parent="aspace_4349dbbdf8483384f8f79b78624159fd" type="folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b91a69b55dee8d8a77801ba2bd227263"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother F.A. Farington, sister Frances Ann and brother Edmund. The dates of the letters are almost all between the years of 1838-1840.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref175_90z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1827 November 08 - 1831 December 15</unitdate><container id="aspace_5655377f1d676d4cb1b031db025b6292" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_252b0731934b1951fe527e83b6fb7463" parent="aspace_5655377f1d676d4cb1b031db025b6292" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a4fe7c4ba770a4ab144af6d82f722d42"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Frances A. Farington, brother Richard, brother Edmund, and schoolmate William Macgregor. A letter dated only "July 3" has pencil cartoon sketches of naval figures and a latter dated only "December 9" has Greek writing on it.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref177_llk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1814 February 05 - 1840 May 10</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec245d181e9801b4d35ab90cabceb0f7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_aa8df6c6aaac0deecee062a6e20744ed" parent="aspace_ec245d181e9801b4d35ab90cabceb0f7" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fc352b9133653a762e5e8f5307160940"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Frances A. Farington, brother Edmund, sister Frances Ann and brother Joseph Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref179_iwc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 12</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref180_3l6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Binder boards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4df6cf231f4e39171ea0a898d4c40065" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_de4d5ea4cfd91dc23d50d2dc93ae90a3" parent="aspace_4df6cf231f4e39171ea0a898d4c40065" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref181_8lo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1799 November 25 - 1806 January 1806</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a1f1ca02e2e49585a36b68cc4a3ffb8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_4047e418212cb1a1a47e402eb454e8fb" parent="aspace_2a1f1ca02e2e49585a36b68cc4a3ffb8" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0185dd4b0ddd7643311b7cef5eafc756"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are all addressed to William Farington and are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Ann Frances Farington, brother George, sister [E.F.], and brother [E.F].</item><item>Often, a single letter will contain correspondence from multiple family members to William Farington. </item><item>All but one of the letters is written between November 25, 1799 and February 27, 1800. </item><item>A letter dated only "February 27" has a note at top: "Copy of a letter from Captn. [Barlow?] to Admiral Kingsmile at Co[?]". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref183_p7p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800 March 02 - 1808 January 20</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a9bae7e233619d956ac5926d9d94b7c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_76ef758176403aa543d018a7e8835ac8" parent="aspace_7a9bae7e233619d956ac5926d9d94b7c" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63b02e9300ae2652e5d15d9da44f3e5e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed to William Farington and George Farington, and some single letters contain correspondence addressed to each.</item><item>The letters are mostly from his father, William Farington, mother Ann Francis Farington and sister [E.F.]. </item><item>A letter dated February 6, 1806 has a black wax seal with possible Arabic writing, and a letter dated March 2, 1800 has rough sketches of the Union Jack design.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref185_tam" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1803 January 09 - 1804 January 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_76ef42761c5e488592981c30bcfd6443" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_48a6aa5554db475da875d4e96cf49a11" parent="aspace_76ef42761c5e488592981c30bcfd6443" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_62f7a76e0b02fcd265f20c42190fa033"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are all addressed to William Farington from his mother Ann Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref187_lqo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1804 August 08 - 1806 May 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_29c621b0fc39ce607b36bc13193ff48a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_ab08c892c67eaeaefcef6814f6524fda" parent="aspace_29c621b0fc39ce607b36bc13193ff48a" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5bdafee60b00fffb2dc9b1352e6bce8c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are all addressed to William Farington from his mother Ann Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington and sister Frances Farington. The letter dated August 26 has a possible Arabic seal in red wax.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref189_ra0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 January 17 - July 10</unitdate><container id="aspace_792341562aec00dff62d280a66f3ac5f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_607f915f5fadc1226b8affbcb33e4254" parent="aspace_792341562aec00dff62d280a66f3ac5f" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_624ec60695308c5a2c4c59c36af380fe"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are all addressed to William Farington from his father, William Farington, mother Anne F. Farington, brother Edmund, and sister E. F. Farington. </item><item>All the letters are bound with string except for a letter dated January 18, 1802 from Edmund Farington which was tucked loose between the first and second bound letters. </item><item>Under the signature of this letter "E. F. Farington" is written in a different hand, "10 years old".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref191_x9m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and Henry Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1798 January 11 - 1800 October 14</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d7638cc7408a9e05e97ddb0304e6d11" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_62edfd4937816101bdf69d6ec957789f" parent="aspace_2d7638cc7408a9e05e97ddb0304e6d11" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25f3c5945bb6bd8f37d1606c507a2bcf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The first letter is addressed to Lieutenant William Farington from E.F. Farington (this part of the letter is written in juvenile script), sister E.F. Farington (mature hand), and mother Ann Farington, and is dated October 14, 1800.</item><item>The second letter is addressed to Henry Farington from his sister E.F. Farington brother George Farington. </item><item>This letter contains the date Jan. 11, 1798, under which is written in a different hand "79 / 19"; in other words, calculating the years between 1798 and 1779. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref193_hi6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 June 26 - July 14</unitdate><container id="aspace_163eed9d7535d61db5a61fe155c323a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_ab8311ed8cad73c60f2d4fa2a13c888d" parent="aspace_163eed9d7535d61db5a61fe155c323a8" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a7c880d83e084e1b862598720e3a04e1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are addressed to William Farington from his father, William Farington, mother Anne F. Farington, sister E. F. Farington, and godson. All the letters are bound with fine string.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref195_uyf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1790 August 20 - 1808 January 12</unitdate><container id="aspace_3faaa200b8b10e9fb8a25c3dc741a5d7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_86485893197f4a45c04c4b956755033b" parent="aspace_3faaa200b8b10e9fb8a25c3dc741a5d7" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_328e31fa936e3ebeb50df625ff0eb858"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are addressed to William Farington from his mother Anne F. Farington, sister E. Frances Farington, sister "Frances Farington", and a friend, Ann [Delamott].</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref197_cbj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1807 January 27 - December 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d5e5391011ffb2b777c7d88352cf366" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_247e474910855e5b0d126f807366f0a6" parent="aspace_7d5e5391011ffb2b777c7d88352cf366" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2a3e9326c1477eb70000d56b707f9f4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed to William Farington from his mother Anne F. Farington, sister "E.F.L.", brother "E.F.F" and sister "Frances Farington". </item><item>In the letter dated January 27, 1807, in a different hand above a sibling's note is written "Poor Edward, Aged 15".</item><item>The letter with the postal stamp for July 6, 1807 contains the signature "[J?]L."</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref199_x1x" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 November 16 - 1807 September 13</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f941510698a5df0daac3c014975dae9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_d1bcbc02e6fc8a080d8159ba6d56fa38" parent="aspace_2f941510698a5df0daac3c014975dae9" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9338f7538e7641c0bb4eb3f1ad99fde8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Both letters are addressed to Lieutenant Farington, RN aboard La Topaze in Jamaica from his sister E.F. Farington. <list type="marked"><item>The November 16, 1802 letter discusses family matters, including the recent death of their brother George. </item><item>The September 13, 1807 letter discusses personal and family matters as well as literature. In particular, she discusses her enjoyment of Tasso's "Jerusalem Delivered" as well as Cowper and Voltaire. She quotes Voltaire in French in the letter. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref201_ro3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800 December 1 - 1802</unitdate><container id="aspace_65ecfa68abf8b17e0b5ea6316d0fd35f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_8e0619b5398d659ed50e8d3a033560a5" parent="aspace_65ecfa68abf8b17e0b5ea6316d0fd35f" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_546277789fe9826583450a13ecca2ecf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington, father William Farington, and sister E.F. Farington.</item><item>All but one of the letters is dated between December 1, 1800 and December 16, 1800. </item><item>The letter dated December 11, 1800 contains rough sketches.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref203_aqt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1789 December 14 - 1801 January 07</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e11522ee5a15b3227bd9e97ddc91f65" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_926461996ddb50d196ab2c241dbea7fb" parent="aspace_9e11522ee5a15b3227bd9e97ddc91f65" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23cde97172b67d4560440f905a2dfba4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington, brother Edmund Farington, sister Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington. </item><item>The letter dated January 7, 180[1?] is addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze, but seems to be addressed to both George and William, who may have both held a commission upon that ship. </item><item>The letter dated 1790 from sister E.F. Farington is written in French in a juvenile hand.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref205_807" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1790 July 01 - 29</unitdate><container id="aspace_404d3c62a5380a3b67628de8bb1b2731" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_0b35859faf369eee12eaa980ce8ebfa5" parent="aspace_404d3c62a5380a3b67628de8bb1b2731" type="folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f274bfbed80476874b015ef097ef6ec"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are all addressed to William Farington, Jr. at Mr. Lane's Academy in Kent. From his mother, Ann Farington. The letter dated July 6, 1790 also contains writing in juvenile hands from two siblings, Henry Farington (7 years old) and sister E.F. Farington (12 years old).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref207_lbi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1801 August 18 - 1809 December 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_03a7cfd27aea53d01e6d5f59927d92d0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_290c439bf30c835866ee5895e4312617" parent="aspace_03a7cfd27aea53d01e6d5f59927d92d0" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e9f651135ebb194062aba4649972085"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington and/or sister Frances Farington and sister E.F. Farington. </item><item>The letters dated August 18, 1801, August 31, 1801 (there are two), and September 15, 1801 are addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, but contain "William" in the salutation.</item><item>The letter dated August 18, 1801 is headed "August 18, 1800" but has a postal stamp for 1801. </item><item>The letter dated August 16, 1807 has continuous writing for 8 pages (across 2 sheets of paper). </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref209_sle" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 13</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref210_er4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Binder boards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_42d2efde40542d15a75b8873ea6e98fb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_a04f6730d66600a381c59c967fd54757" parent="aspace_42d2efde40542d15a75b8873ea6e98fb" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref211_vk7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1801 March 24 - 1805 June 17</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2beeee204f4039c1974fe363e2fe3d7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_2689520f2c18a57b252b5fda19f3513c" parent="aspace_b2beeee204f4039c1974fe363e2fe3d7" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2ebb3238df5632071b302bbdc8be5ce"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington and/or sister Frances Farington or brother E. Farington. </item><item>Most of the letters are addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, although one occasionally will include a salutation such as "Dear children" from mother Ann Farington, indicating that it is meant for both George and William Farington.</item><item>Many of the letters to George Farington are part of a series of letters written by his sister E.F.F and are numbered in the upper right-hand corner sequentially;</item><item>the letter dated March 42, 1801 explains her system of arranging them. </item><item>There is a somewhat later included in this folder that not part of this sequence--it is dated June 17, 1805 and to William Farington aboard the HMS Hibernia from his younger brother E. Farington. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref213_n3g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800 November 21 - 1802 December 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_5aff1c8dcaf69e0b2f12793285cda54c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_e98dfafca367506a4ae4df0034f31ab3" parent="aspace_5aff1c8dcaf69e0b2f12793285cda54c" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_148913680671b04951198184f49fda9a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their father William Farington, mother Ann Farington and/or sister E.F. Farington. </item><item>The letter dated May 5, 1801 is are addressed to George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, but contains "William" in the salutation, it also contains "Copies of the letters from Mr. Marsden and Captn. Peddar dated March 180[1?] regarding the HMS La Topaze.</item><item>There are two undated letter fragments from sister E.F. Farington which each contain transcriptions of literary or religious texts, including "A friendly visit to the House of Mourning", Cowper's "Prayer for Patience" and Milton's Lycidas: "So sinks the day-star in the Ocean bed, /And yet anon repairs his drooping head, / And tricks his beams, and with new spangled Ore, / Flames in the forehead of the morning sky." The letter dated December 12, 1802 to William Farington from his father contains an itemized expense list.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref215_ysb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 December 05 - 12</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a8465eac9acbb61c240ca33b2594798" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_5a89017ff69fc582f1fb9b445cd45225" parent="aspace_1a8465eac9acbb61c240ca33b2594798" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_892a013fee30cf0e7a66eeb576cdd375"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This folder contains three letters and an undated letter fragment to William Farington aboard the Bombay Castle from his mother Ann Farington and sister E.F. Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref217_a7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1801 December 15 - 1802 January 06</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b37fa158b852fc7dd53793ab3c9ff7b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_043dc35393594ca8f39c6dcd1ff02ade" parent="aspace_1b37fa158b852fc7dd53793ab3c9ff7b" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcce9b87eefafcc03d2e2b735ff714b3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>This folder contains 6 letters, most of which contain correspondence from more than one family member to William Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica.</item><item>The correspondence is from William Farington's father William Farington, mother Ann Farington, sister E.F. Farington, and brother E.F. Farington. </item><item>A letter dated December 15, 1801 from "E.F. Farington" contains the following note: "The fate of my Brother George has afflicted us very much, but it has been a great consolation to us, that you have escaped the horrid fever." </item><item>A letter dated January 5, 1802 contains a transcription of a letter from James Coffin addressed to a "Madam". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref219_svu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800 June 17 - 1805 November 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_c98e6ed4491f76ae94cccfbd4f2c7c4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_3cd35e2576df02a6ae3dd97cf10dfd55" parent="aspace_c98e6ed4491f76ae94cccfbd4f2c7c4e" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0d5b3c45ae3e347cd692d25b003fe2b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>This folder contains 12 letters and letter fragments, most of which contain correspondence from more than one family member to William Farington aboard either the Bombay Castle East Indiamen or the HMS Hibernia (there is also one letter dated October 4, 1802 addressed to William at "Parrs Wood, Didsbury near Manchester"). </item><item>The correspondence is from William Farington's father William Farington, mother Ann Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances Farington, and brother/godson E.F. Farington.</item><item>The letter dated December 28, 1802 contains transcriptions of religious verse. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref221_utr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1803 January 23 -1804 October 26</unitdate><container id="aspace_c94c8ba0ff82f23aaa7c57381727a8b5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_5b9155a96d2de0dd097d14e3beea176f" parent="aspace_c94c8ba0ff82f23aaa7c57381727a8b5" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_64c473c69ce97bccc419823e55249364"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>This folder contains 17 letters and letter fragments to William Farington on board the Bombay Castle in China and Bombay from the following members of his family: father William Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances Farington, and mother Ann Farington.</item><item>The letters dated February 26, 1803; April 3; April 7, 1803 (there are two with this date); April 21, 1803; and April 18, 1803 are bound together with black string. </item><item>The letter dated May 4, 1803 contains, in a different hand, the note: "The last letter from my poor Father / he died on the 30th of July this year 1803 / the date of this is 4 May". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref223_2b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1802 June 12 - 15</unitdate><container id="aspace_aaa49a638c5bcf25ff1f686bb1342932" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_525ccdf9c7703bb6ffd3c71ab993ca97" parent="aspace_aaa49a638c5bcf25ff1f686bb1342932" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f9a8539e8da1bf866d5291d2d1b73b5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The first letter is to William Farington from his mother Ann Farington and is six pages long.</item><item>The second letter is to William Farington aboard HMS La Topaze in Jamaica from his sister E.F. Farington and is 14 pages long.</item><item>This letter includes transcription of letters informing the family of the death abroad of Henry Farington.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref225_er0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800 March 09 - 1805 April 05</unitdate><container id="aspace_565372d45673cee8c5c1f62ad0fff82f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_b5d4e5deccaeaa445f64803241f9f3b9" parent="aspace_565372d45673cee8c5c1f62ad0fff82f" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bcf3441c79b0ccc5f22ed050f226ebe2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The letters are mostly addressed to William Farington from his mother A. Farington and sister E.F. Farington, except for the letter fragment with the postal stamp May 6, 1801, which is addressed to Mr. George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica (this letter is paginated at the right upper corner of each page from 5-8) from E.F. Farington. </item><item>Several of the letters are addressed to Lieut. [William] Farington aboard the HMS Plover. </item><item>The letters dated May 19, 1800 and May 21-22, 1800 appear to have been used for scrap paper on which to write drafts of other letters. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref227_9gg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1780 May 20 - 1805 June 01</unitdate><container id="aspace_390d081f9f98bfd694a84c8b5a4d8b99" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_61ccb5849f6604c6830c793e536af4d1" parent="aspace_390d081f9f98bfd694a84c8b5a4d8b99" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92b4f7e0d3cbe5d4477a891ad7d4baa0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The letters in this folder are all to William Farington (most letters are addressed to him aboard either the HMS Plover or HMS Hibernia).</item><item>With the exception of a letter dated May 20, 1780 from his mother Ann, all of the letters are from the years 1800 and 1805.</item><item>The letters are from his father William Farington, mother Ann Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances, and brother E.F. Farington.</item><item>The letter dated October 14, 1800 is addressed to William aboard the HMS Plover, but this name is crossed out in red ink and replaced with "Resolution". </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref229_iao" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800 June 17 - 1805 March 19</unitdate><container id="aspace_f51a99e1c468638b35cf8d66e553d9f7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_162942599c7778b45a6b10758913e49e" parent="aspace_f51a99e1c468638b35cf8d66e553d9f7" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2dd347424e3f57a77a99919319676a5e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The letters are addressed to Lieut. William Farington from his mother A. Farington, sister E.F. Farington, sister Frances Farington and father William Farington. </item><item>The letters all fall into one of two dating periods: from June 17, 1800 to October 3, 1800 (when he was aboard the HMS Plover) or from February 24, 1805 to March 19, 1805 (when he was aboard the HMS Thunderer and the HMS Hibernia). </item><item>The letter dated September 28, 1800 has two pencil sketches of ships on it. </item><item>The letter dated Sept. 2, 1800 contains a transcription of the French "Chanson Clara" by William's sister E.F. Farington. </item><item>The letter dated Sept. 19, 1800 contains writing in both red and brown ink, at top of first page in red ink is written: "Au Lieutenant sans chemise" and a short note in French from his sister E.F. </item><item>The letter dated August 8, 1800, in addition to being crosswritten, contains interlinear writing oriented upside down from the original writing which begins: "My Father tells me, I had better transcribe Hals letter &amp; I think so too, so [once?] more patience brother William / Phoebe at Sea 18 July / My dear father, I am very happy to write to you..." </item><item>The letter fragment dated March 3, 1805 from sister Frances Farington was probably originally part of the same correspondence as the next item, a fragment with the postal stamp March 5, 1805. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref231_t2g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1790 September 03 - 1811 January 07</unitdate><container id="aspace_e714d3bc523396d1ce4a3f0cf202aacb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_f06cdb401f309d433432c7bdde19dfd6" parent="aspace_e714d3bc523396d1ce4a3f0cf202aacb" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4caf3df8866e2d0ba236047dfb063492"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The letters are mostly addressed to William Farington from father William Farington, his mother A. Farington, brother and godson E. Farington, and sister E.F. Farington, except for the letter dated August 3, 1801, which is addressed to Mr. George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, but contains correspondence to both George and, presumably, William, since the salutation from their mother is: "My Dear god Children". </item><item>The letter dated January 7, 1811 to Lieut. Farington aboard the HMS Clio is partially torn, but contains a note from [P.?] Hughes in addition to correspondence from William's mother Ann Farington. </item><item>The letters in this folder date to the following years: 1790 (when William Farington was a student at Mr. Lane's Academy), 1800-1801, 1805, 1808-1809, and 1811.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref233_qgt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1791 January 28 - 1800 February 02</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a348b84859f48fb2a2c09cb94d2bbea" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_d0dce49ae0ec79a134583c838c705230" parent="aspace_7a348b84859f48fb2a2c09cb94d2bbea" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e613c8a430a5f5bc095135b7b3e009fd"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed to William Farington (mostly aboard the HMS Boddam, HMS Plover, or HMS Ruby) from father William Farington, his mother A. Farington, brothers George Farington and Henry Farington, and sister E.F. Farington.</item><item>The letters fall into two groups: those dated from January 28, 1791 to December 5, 1791, and those dated from December 7, 1798 to February 2, 1800.</item><item>The letter dated November 13, 1799 also contains a transcription: "Copy of a letter from Sir Allan Gardner / Royal Sovereign Torbay Nov. 10 " expressing congratulations on William Farrington's promotion to Lieutenant in the Navy.</item><item>The letter dated January 21, 1800 from William's sister E.F. Farington contains a transcription of a French poem "Jeune filles".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref235_y1z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1799 November 08 - 1801 May 31</unitdate><container id="aspace_eff555ecbeb8a7e3b66674c26959bfe9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_0469b7afb0c032dc8bda54b603ec8e5f" parent="aspace_eff555ecbeb8a7e3b66674c26959bfe9" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d5627e83e7ccd505cdae127ece94ae9d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed either to William Farington or to George Farington, from their mother Ann Farington and/or sister Frances Farington.</item><item>Many of the letters are addressed to either William or George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, or to William aboard the HMS Plover.</item><item>Some letters will include a salutation such as "Dear children" from mother Ann Farington, indicating that it is meant for both George and William Farington.</item><item>The letter dated March 28, 1801 from sister E.F. Farington to George contains transcriptions of two poems, one entitled "Ho[p?] Garden" (which begins with "what sounds of mirth / Burst from that tavern, o'er whose ample gate / The portrait of celebrious naval chief...") and the second a selection from Robert Southey's "St. Juan Gualberto" (1800) which begins with the line "Slow sunk the glorious sun, a roseate light". </item><item>The letter dated May 31, 1801 from sister E.F. Farington to George contains a transcription of a poem entitled "Mamma Mia".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref237_7qh" level="series"><did><unittitle>Folio 14</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ref238_62t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Binder Boards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_49d39cebf6f132b055271a4772875203" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_633057d2013e4920ee6814bf52453bf8" parent="aspace_49d39cebf6f132b055271a4772875203" type="folder">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref239_2ok" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roster of Warfield School</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1833 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_d598f8ee01796b55a68b46b570db1f86" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_aa45d7a8d9ea6c7550f1fe90273612c9" parent="aspace_d598f8ee01796b55a68b46b570db1f86" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d6e418347d805c8d501e21cc32a71e1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>"A List of the boys of Warfield School, March 1833", divided into four classes. R. Farington is in the Fourth Class.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref241_4q5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Richard A. Farington while at Rev. R. Faithfull's in Warfield</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1833 January 25</unitdate><container id="aspace_74edec84b43a3f0fc1a78605ba31a58e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_2b381d7fef83df217b1edacb432b5899" parent="aspace_74edec84b43a3f0fc1a78605ba31a58e" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bfa9d0010867795c34798203b800105f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Two letters to Richard A. Farington while at Rev. R. Faithfull's in Warfield, one from a young sibling, [Edward?] Farington, and the other from Richard's mother as well as a sibling.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref243_8i0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1829 November 30</unitdate><container id="aspace_201ade69c7dc9503f02f71194e273340" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_4e39b8d1e5b2bda1f59400d663303cfc" parent="aspace_201ade69c7dc9503f02f71194e273340" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc71b677d7cbdce1fb152463b93969b7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>A small piece of correspondence addressed to Edmund Farington from his friend P. [?]asson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref245_6ws" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1832 November 17 - 1840 June 26</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac2f1f492eb63e1affa98678a8fab343" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_6a1c5428dcd55d2210cf0aad4516f613" parent="aspace_ac2f1f492eb63e1affa98678a8fab343" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4fc29e018185dc971188b14dae080371"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>11 letters or letter fragments addressed to William Farington from his brother Edmund Francis Farington, and mother Frances Anne Faringon, (father?) William Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref247_49p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1834 March 20 - 1837 August 31</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9f7c7f309f0728909a9230b7b61e6bd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_4a1e3000e418da3e15e1701c50cadd6d" parent="aspace_d9f7c7f309f0728909a9230b7b61e6bd" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_309d76028d8272de4faa7a0d89169f00"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>13 letters or letter fragments addressed to William Farington from his mother, Frances Anne Farington, brother Edmund Farington, and father William Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref249_dxz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1831 January 27</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f8d35b7ab00365e9635a141808ff7fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_95c764a694e7e9a4a2059a315f4afb77" parent="aspace_2f8d35b7ab00365e9635a141808ff7fc" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b5c9f396ea39a16f1cf4cc206c99deb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The letter dated January 27, 1831 is from Edmund Farington's mother Frances A. Farington, and the undated later is from William Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref251_tyf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Richard Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1833 February 13 - June 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd8bc6b8a4e119861c3ee01176014272" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_e9d7dc2c656fb1941305d27eb52f9d9e" parent="aspace_dd8bc6b8a4e119861c3ee01176014272" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d06bf377d79459100a177e1eb54b7777"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The letter dated February 13, 1833 is from Richard's mother Frances A. Farington, sister F.A. Farington, and William Farington. The letter dated June 11, 1833 is from Richard's father William Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref253_jjd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1835 March 28 - April 02</unitdate><container id="aspace_501831f9c5ed1f28602e1c2fc8ccb553" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_a32de0a60358631fed4ff365c69af81a" parent="aspace_501831f9c5ed1f28602e1c2fc8ccb553" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_65f9148990b3600687a7b1f2ab114717"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The letter fragment dated March 28, 1835 is from William Farington's father, William, and the letter dated April 2, 1835 is from William Farington's mother, Frances A. Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref255_jp5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1831 November 07</unitdate><container id="aspace_090bf3b9b07795a47ca21653eb78172b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_4534e65ad91204be5f96fa280fc07f29" parent="aspace_090bf3b9b07795a47ca21653eb78172b" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c1cb833700565b558b2b5f427c3fa6b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This letter is addressed to Richard Farington from William Farington, and also contains a note to Edmund Farington from his grandmother "C. Green".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref257_ngl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1835 May 12 - 1840 July 21</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d2193675aab7ef7620c95cd6801e23b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_87b66365cc01ca683043d0bcbe824b6c" parent="aspace_9d2193675aab7ef7620c95cd6801e23b" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9100bfaba33238631bb80b4f8577a937"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The letters are addressed to William Farington from his father William Farington, mother Frances Ann Farington, sister Frances Ann Farington, brother Richard A. Farington, and brother Edmund Farington.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref259_pbq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1830 November 30 - 1831 November 30</unitdate><container id="aspace_22cd23f480f485fe6db10ab31b11de31" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_06cb66d5a007557df8e62367ced06d4f" parent="aspace_22cd23f480f485fe6db10ab31b11de31" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee708974f1bb67655ab78ab12685e651"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>These letters are addressed to Edmund Farington from his father William Farington, mother Frances Ann Farington, sister Frances Ann Farington and brother William Farington. </item><item>The letter dated September 28, 1831 contains a note to Richard Farington ("Dicky")from their mother Frances Ann Farington, and the letter dated November 30, 1831 contains a note from father William Farington to Richard as well.</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref261_jtg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to William Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_09f77a4bd789503ec719037d1f738116" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_581412d0fefcca79424fe83fbc78c14b" parent="aspace_09f77a4bd789503ec719037d1f738116" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e98724ed8b130eac2417a828b192bc70"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Both letters are to William Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington. One letter is dated "Oct. 18" and the other is dated "Oct."</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref263_9pm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Richard Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1833 March 13 - May 22</unitdate><container id="aspace_61bd2800113842f8351c37c260bd90d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_03b69ef2df09b9632a2881788f4d5f50" parent="aspace_61bd2800113842f8351c37c260bd90d6" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a860b3429aadbbc3986ca30a9b39c4be"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are to Richard "Dick" Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington, brother Edmund, and sister Frances Ann.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref265_a5g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1830 July 23 - October 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9c662ca322b1470fc87c3046d186c5d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_d64d421eadfdc5bff7c034ad7ae04880" parent="aspace_c9c662ca322b1470fc87c3046d186c5d" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af226608ddc8e1798038f7d53cfb0b13"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letters are to Edmund Farington from his mother, Frances Ann Farington and possibly his father, William Farington (the signature on the letter dated September 24, 1830 is unclear).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref267_dl3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1830 November 12 - 1834 October 15</unitdate><container id="aspace_186c98247dbdd2e17e5c733c75227b78" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_7bd8aa015e4c5b3c4bf88509c8937c77" parent="aspace_186c98247dbdd2e17e5c733c75227b78" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50bfc4526b5ebbd81feead0da6eeed66"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>The letter dated November 12, 1830 is to Edmund Farington from his father William Farington.</item><item>The letter dated October 19, 1831 contains correspondence to Richard Farington from his sister Frances Ann Farington and to Edmund Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington.</item><item>The letter dated October 15, 1834 is to Richard Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref269_fiz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1833 June 14 - September 9</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce68da0149fab8f80c5c5a62f276f641" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_cf11b4f3a42894d3ccce7a8458140ee2" parent="aspace_ce68da0149fab8f80c5c5a62f276f641" type="folder">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref270_0ch" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard A. Farington Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1837 November 13 - 1838 May 17</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3f0038e16c45a2d9f880404b6b72b0d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_b0545b5a5bb9a217caffd6a1625fc90f" parent="aspace_c3f0038e16c45a2d9f880404b6b72b0d" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7e2ae2da208ecfc7bf6b0e0aea11aa6b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>These letter are all addressed to Richard A. Farington from his mother, Frances A. Farington, sister Frances A. Farington, and father William Farington, except for a letter dated November 13, 1837, which is from Richard A. Farington to his father, Capt. Farington. The small note is from mother Frances A. Farington recommending to her son the use of a dictionary to correct his spelling.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref272_zu1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Capt. Farington, RN and Edmund Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1837 May 03 - August 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6c59afd4a8c0fdfcfccd4f90e6b5bee" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_e3e85f5cf65fa561c993e7096a5f519a" parent="aspace_a6c59afd4a8c0fdfcfccd4f90e6b5bee" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d864cee0eb1543cf0b5bde16c6cab738"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The letter dated May 3, 1837 is addressed to Capt. Farington, RN from F.A. Farington; the letter with the postal stamp August 18, 1837 is addressed to Edmund Farington from his father William Farington and probably also from his mother.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref274_ihz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Richard A. "Dick" Farington and Francis Ann "Fanny" Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1835 April [?]6 - September 10</unitdate><container id="aspace_acf40b8c747aaf226db035dd768bf91f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_0fddc55b7df4de3372d09e2584c76dad" parent="aspace_acf40b8c747aaf226db035dd768bf91f" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_52e2e1ca5ea279a18d8af904c6907ef6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The folder contains 4 letters to Dick Farington: <list type="marked"><item>one dated Sept. 10, 1835 from father William, </item><item>one dated April [?]6, 18[3?]5 from Edmund Farington, </item><item>and two undated letters, one from sister Frances and one from mother Frances Farington. Tucked inside of the letter dated April [?]6, 18[3?]5 is a letter to Fanny Farington ("Mrs. Farington") from "brother" Edmund dated July [10?], [1835?]. </item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref276_sib" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Capt. Farington, RN</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1839 July 28 - September 28</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ba72db9c5844b6eae698c72b2882cca" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_7f6c96d65e40af86b2498a480a854ae1" parent="aspace_5ba72db9c5844b6eae698c72b2882cca" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_10e08ae5c25670c58bca5c1bf4d8c336"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The letter dated September 10, 1839 is from his friend [J.?] Ba[?]; the letter dated July 28, 1839 is from L.F. Ball.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref278_f4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1828 November 11 - 1829 May 29</unitdate><container id="aspace_267d72bcf77431122b5c79210dc1bc0a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_dced63245748d48babe2f411e6e0559c" parent="aspace_267d72bcf77431122b5c79210dc1bc0a" type="folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_760bd263d4ed8ded92245ee13fd5957f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>All of the letters are addressed to Edmund Farington from the following family members: brother William, sister Frances Ann "Fanny", mother Frances Ann Farington, and father William Farington. The letter dated May 25, 1829 includes a note from sister Fanny to both "Edmund and Dick".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref280_vak" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Richard A. Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1833 June 08 - 1835 December 10</unitdate><container id="aspace_9cc0d13cda09197140dba46bd99c17c6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_a1e995c8411e4cac0cdc1677b0887b28" parent="aspace_9cc0d13cda09197140dba46bd99c17c6" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_244e13f60ce35fb2e8c30ae7548aa396"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p><list type="marked"><item>All of the 21 letters in this folder are addressed to Richard A. Farington ("Dick") from one or more of the following family members: brother Edmund, brother William, sister Fanny, mother Frances Ann Farington, and father William Farington.</item><item>Two letters (March 22, 1835 and undated) are tucked inside the letter dated "March 22", and one letter (March 1, 1835) is tucked inside the letter from Richard's mother Frances, also dated March 1, 1835.</item><item>In addition to these letters, there is also a single sheet of pencil-ruled paper containing a school exercise entitled "On the instinct of animals".</item></list></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref282_y3y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Richard A. Farington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1836 February 23 - 1837 December 08</unitdate><container id="aspace_69d017960118d42c8d96db568ee6054f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_851de25dd1c2f2cd316deab36c7c1e56" parent="aspace_69d017960118d42c8d96db568ee6054f" type="folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f74298d6874a32894fdb3e7f3bab25c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>All 32 of the letters in this folder are addressed to Richard A. Farington ("Dick") from one or more of the following family members: brother Edmund, brother William, sister Fanny, mother Frances Ann Farington, and father William Farington. The letter dated September 28, 1837 has a rough sketch of a guard in it.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref284_2ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Farington Family Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_34158d2fca88696db2e6956bca117952" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_352abd434d3effbeaae7ea43098a5754" parent="aspace_34158d2fca88696db2e6956bca117952" type="folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b37319d6d98f1ad877fa7994ccf6e629"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>One undated letter from William Farington to his "Sons" that has no address or postal stamp.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
