<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt896nb4nb/">farme771.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Farmer (Moses G.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Moses G. Farmer Papers <num>LSC.0771</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Manuscripts Division staff; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2002.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-22 15:00:25 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Moses G. Farmer papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Farmer, Moses G. (Moses Gerrish)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.0771</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(5 boxes and 1 oversize box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1893" type="inclusive">1830-1893</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ea1cad2b8098124ce991162d5baf1ed0" label="Abstract">Moses Gerrish Farmer (1820-1893) was born in Boxcawen, New Hampshire. While he was a school principal in Dover, New Hampshire, he invented a machine to print paper window shades. He invented what became the first electric fire alarm system in the U.S., discovered means for duplex and quadruplex telegraph, invented an incandescent electric lamp and in 1866, he patented a self-exciting dynamo. The collection contains correspondence to and from Moses G. Farmer, account books, diaries, clippings, photographs, and other memorabilia. The collection also contains legal and business papers regarding Farmer's patents and inventions, especially the electric railroad and fire alarm system.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_083e9bd526e227c6b5c1a0ae90e38d77">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a209243132280a1e1fb2010aba67e45e">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4ac1436a5d93b7cd23ce13732a0b52c0">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fa93748099a16cf9b291cfff1ef7f045">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_16a07ef3f1e7a70479dada4151b862aa">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Charles Scribner's Sons, purchase, 1962.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5aede259948e051efe3fefe2c791757d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Moses G. Farmer Papers (Collection 771). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b7fd121eae825025ffed8d70cf44cbd9">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>Processed by Manuscripts Division staff.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_5ec63012d97018794ea3b80a1ce2deb9">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9912180543606533">9912180543606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1b1c66c27c4981d3a0e98a09718cb472">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Moses Gerrish Farmer was born February 9, 1820 in Boxcawen, New Hampshire; entered preparatory school at Andover in 1832; attended Dartmouth, but withdrew because of ill health; he worked briefly in a civil engineer's office and was affiliated with various private schools in New England; married Hannah Tobey Shapleigh in 1844; while he was a school principal in Dover, New Hampshire, he invented a machine to print paper window shades; began work with the electric telegraph, eventually taking charge of the telegraph line between Boston and Newburyport,Massachusetts in 1848 he invented what became the first electric fire alarm system in the U.S.; discovered means for duplex and quadruplex telegraph; in 1858-59 invented an incandescent electric lamp; in 1866 he patented a self-exciting dynamo; appointed as electrician of U.S. Torpedo Station at Newport, Rhode Island; consulting electrician, U.S. Electric Light Company of New York; died in 1893.</p>  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bb53381e14b00c36cabfc58d3eed5d08">
    <head>Biographical Narrative</head>
<p>Moses Gerrish Farmer, inventor and pioneer electrician was born on February 9, 1820 in Boxcawen, New Hampshire to Colonel John and Sally (Gerrish) Farmer. He died at the World's Fair in Chicago on May 25, 1893.</p><p>In 1832 Moses Farmer entered the preparatory school at Andover, Massachusetts. He also attended Dartmouth College, but had to give up his studies due to ill health. After a brief period of employment in a civil engineer's office, Farmer was affiliated with various private schools in New England including Eliot Academy, Eliot Maine. While in Eliot, Farmer married Hannah Tobey Shapleigh on December 25, 1844. They had one daughter, Sarah Jane Farmer.</p><p>Moses Farmer's career as an inventor began while he was principal of a school in Dover, New Hampshire. At that time he devised a machine to print paper window shades. In 1845 he became enthusiastic about electricity. His first project was to construct a miniature electric train which was first exhibited on July 26, 1847. By December of that year he had accepted a position as wire examiner of the new electric telegraph line between Boston and Worcester, Massachusetts. During this time he learned telegraphy and July 1848 was appointed operator in the office at Salem, Massachussetts. Farmer later took charge of the telegraph between Boston and Newburyport, Massachusetts and undertook opening telegraph offices along this line.</p><p>In the meantime, Moses Farmer continued his electrical experimentation at home. In 1848 he invented an electric-striking aparatus for a fire-alarm service which he developed with Dr. William F. Channing. This system was installed in the City of Boston in 1851. Farmer became the superintendent of the system. This was the first electric fire-alarm system in the United States.</p><p>Farmer resigned the superintendency in 1853 and worked on his various electrical ideas. In 1855, he discovered the means for duplex and quadruplex telegraph. Succeeding in depositing aluminum electrolytically in 1856, he went into the electrotyping business with several other men. The business failed in the panic of 1857.</p><p>After the business failure, Moses Farmer experimented with electricity as a source of light and in 1858-59 he invented an incandescent electric lamp. Becoming the superintendent of a tobacco-extracting manufactory in Somerville, Massachusetts, allowed Farmer to do further experiments. In 1866 he patented, a self-exciting dynamo. His attention was then concentrated more and more upon electric power generation and distribution.</p><p>In 1872 Farmer was appointed to the office of electrician at the United States Torpedo Station at Newport, Rhode Island. For a period of nine years he greatly advanced torpedo warfare until his health made his resignation imperative. As far as his health permitted, he then acted as consulting electrician for the United States Electric Light Company of New York. After several years he retired with his family to their summer home at Eliot, Maine, where he established a public library.</p><p>Moses Gerrish Farmer led the way by thirty years in many applications of electric current. His electrical patents rivalled Thomas A. Edison's. He received less fame and less profit because of his constant impulse to plunge into the unknown rather than to develop and perfect a marketable invention. Farmer's patents were purchased by the United States Electric Light Company and were later sold to Westinghouse.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5b6edfc1f8190c78e16a170b857aca55">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection contains correspondence to and from Moses G. Farmer, account books, diaries, clippings, photographs, and other memorabilia. Correspondents include inventors Joseph Henry and William Francis Channing. Also contains legal and business papers regarding Farmer's patents and inventions, especially the electric railroad and fire alarm system. Includes correspondence and papers of members of the Farmer, Shapleigh, and Little families.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d7ddea7904279dd33c13dbc64efa24e9">
    <head>Expanded Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Moses Gerrish Farmer collection was purchased in July 1962. The collection contains correspondence to and from Moses Gerrish Farmer and papers regarding his patents and inventions, especially the electric railroad and fire-alarm system. There is some biographical material in the collection including an autobiography of Farmer. Various other writings by Farmer are also present. The remainder of the collection is composed of correspondence and papers of members of the Farmer, Shapleigh and Little families, including legal papers, diaries and photographs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_afb070c9b307d38ea4297fd906390396">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in the following series: <list type="ordered"><item>Correspondence of Moses G. Farmer (Box 1).</item><item>Correspondence of other family members (Box 2).</item><item>Legal papers of Richard Shapleigh, Sally Gerrish Farmer's diaries, photographs (Box 2).</item><item>Autobiography, biography, and biographical materials on Moses G. Farmer (Box 2).</item><item>Various writings of Moses G. Farmer, insurance policies, and legal papers (Box 3).</item><item>Notes re: inventions, electric railway, fire alarm system (Box 3).</item><item>List of patents, patent applications and agreements, published patents (Box 4).</item><item>Letters of Moses G. Farmer and miscellaneous material (Box 5).</item><item>Journal of Hannah Farmer, 1844-53 (Box 6).</item></list></p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Diaries.</genreform>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Inventors -- United States -- Archives.</occupation>
    <persname source="naf">Farmer, Moses G. (Moses Gerrish), 1820-1893--Archives.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref14_i1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer as a young man during and mainly during his college years from his family, relatives, and friends--in particular Jacob H. Little.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1835-1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_93d32ba2e7085c642523d33813dde3e1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f465e893d3ed88dbd6e94d925c466b3e" parent="aspace_93d32ba2e7085c642523d33813dde3e1" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_2wb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer from concerning replies from the U.S. Patent Office and personal letters.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1851-1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_2210a12c607e5273bdb141970bc63079" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_100ccccf63202369dd466f246ac4c013" parent="aspace_2210a12c607e5273bdb141970bc63079" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref16_8aq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer from concerning business between him and William F. Channing, and replies from the U.S. Patent Office.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1860-1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_55cae0ab1cbbc59a9cf6ddaa56a3249d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7b59d2655a62cd5d3a768d4a2f1f8bc5" parent="aspace_55cae0ab1cbbc59a9cf6ddaa56a3249d" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_qka" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer from mainly from William F. Channing concerning inventions and patents.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1870-1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_47d396a22a92a86238e3eed47049588c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_44d6017792fb6fa917d74a055dc4f7c1" parent="aspace_47d396a22a92a86238e3eed47049588c" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref18_xl0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer from concerning business with Frank L. Pope (his patent attorney) and the U.S. Electric Lighting Company.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1880-1881</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf4970ba17c814f51cb91fcf28db459d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_06200d3bf875a87155411906f1e9beec" parent="aspace_cf4970ba17c814f51cb91fcf28db459d" type="folder">5</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_1vw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer from concerning his inventions with Frank L. Pope, Parker W. Page, Attorney at Law, and Charles C. Coffin.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1882-1886</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c2787032699960a9f0ec0aab7e3aa08" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_82b6961659b443f0f64101321e659a30" parent="aspace_8c2787032699960a9f0ec0aab7e3aa08" type="folder">6</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref20_67e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters received by Moses G. Farmer from concerning business with Page, Pope, and others.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1887-1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_56246373e2ba59217302feb594d316ab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_11cb6d75322260ff7a45b8529087b968" parent="aspace_56246373e2ba59217302feb594d316ab" type="folder">7</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_eu5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters sent by Moses G. Farmer from to Joseph M. Batchelder concerning his patents on inventions.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1853-1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f559a84a3900ca6c22b30b39e4f8055" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a7609718bad32818a74fdd56518a7fed" parent="aspace_4f559a84a3900ca6c22b30b39e4f8055" type="folder">8</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref22_i43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters sent by Moses G. Farmer from to Charles Stowell concerning an invention referred to as machines D and B.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1874-1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_6781ba7e4b4f103f453aefa54792259c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_31a6baeb55ccaf1b68478cc98bbdef32" parent="aspace_6781ba7e4b4f103f453aefa54792259c" type="folder">9</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref23_rse" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters sent by Moses G. Farmer from to Charles Stowell, Pope, etc. dealing mainly with the electric light invention.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1880-1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d61b93f7e6c4bc12918e4e0bf6d3724" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4c4adddb82500901a1572a7f2df77b30" parent="aspace_5d61b93f7e6c4bc12918e4e0bf6d3724" type="folder">10</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref24_aku" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence received and sent by Hannah (Shapleigh) Farmer, wife of Moses Farmer from and undated. Included are her poems under the name of Mabelle. Many of the letters concern miscredit given to Farmer's invention of the Fire Alarm Telegraph.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1851-1883</unitdate><container id="aspace_18234d1994bafe2b6e9a13cdcfad5dac" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_22ccfe7dfa6b11d58e2cc04b7ae1e6ea" parent="aspace_18234d1994bafe2b6e9a13cdcfad5dac" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref25_wm5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence received and sent by Sarah J. Farmer, daughter of Moses G. Farmer from concerning replies received on invitations she sent out commemorating her father's electric train invention at the Electrical Convention in Also a phrenology on her, and her last will and testament of 1893 and 1902.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1880-1904 1897.</unitdate><container id="aspace_75e599b21b221554dd35581753ba6673" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_2ce370f141ee9e17bf0adbada34eb0db" parent="aspace_75e599b21b221554dd35581753ba6673" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref26_qkr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence received and sent by John and Sally (Gerrish) Farmer, mother and father of Moses G. Farmer, from concerning in particular letters to Mrs. Farmer from her son Moses who was at Andover attending school.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1825-1848</unitdate><container id="aspace_466061437eef7fb8ea3b1ac89483f0ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_320bb383ef6bd33b16f2133348a8997d" parent="aspace_466061437eef7fb8ea3b1ac89483f0ff" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref27_06s" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence received and sent by various members of the Shapleigh and Little families between 1816 and 1861.</unittitle><container id="aspace_77d3519e8c85e10ac25f127b26ed1642" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c5d01aa880426025d9d4a55d3c1bfeec" parent="aspace_77d3519e8c85e10ac25f127b26ed1642" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref28_of7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal papers of Richard Shapleigh between containing a series of land deeds under his name.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1822-1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_24452a95fef4a0991c845472b163cfa1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b6bbd9ca078b00fdad1ffb7314498f8b" parent="aspace_24452a95fef4a0991c845472b163cfa1" type="folder">5</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref29_c3i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sally Gerrish Farmer's diaries--complete years 1813, 1815, 1831, and 1844 at the ages of 23, 25, 41, and 54 respectively; and partial diaries for the years 1848, 1852, and 1856 including a set of recipes and medicants.</unittitle><container id="aspace_991bf073e3fe7df44b3dbefd9d7e488b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_40bf6d8b173e335feeaebb7f9ff38422" parent="aspace_991bf073e3fe7df44b3dbefd9d7e488b" type="folder">6</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref30_3ds" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs--two of Moses G. Farmer, one of their home in Eliot, Maine, two of their home in Torpedo Station, Newport, Rhode Island, a picture of Hannah S. Farmer and an unknown woman.</unittitle><container id="aspace_7d0e148cf31f55dff8be42fc917d4cca" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_8a063b1e48732443e80debaf0616ca77" parent="aspace_7d0e148cf31f55dff8be42fc917d4cca" type="folder">7</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref31_6dv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Autobiography of Moses G. Farmer. The first written in and covers the first sixteen years of his life (to 1836). The second began in and ended in The third one is a brief summary of his inventions up to 1849.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1885 1826 1848.</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b894719564779c5b13dfa326fd339cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_e7101bec4affacb929d23f88d2920557" parent="aspace_6b894719564779c5b13dfa326fd339cc" type="folder">8</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref32_b0r" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biography of Moses G. Farmer's life from his birth to 1848 with many extracts taken from Farmer's autobiography.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f10a983e0589df19c7894d0b44a0d480" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_38f2f30e110f89791d8c53092eece42f" parent="aspace_f10a983e0589df19c7894d0b44a0d480" type="folder">9</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref33_1om" level="file"><did><unittitle>Partial biographical material on Moses G. Farmer's life including an extract from a book; an account of his inventions up to ; a phrenology of his character; a biography of his life up to 1877; a medical report of his health in later years; and miscellaneous--certificate of admittance into school, his marriage certificate, his obituary notice, and two newspapers items on his accomplishments.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1852</unitdate><container id="aspace_415c7991135f7cd83b3529e8548edc08" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_dcaf367f0ad3bcfa91b4e6cbbc36d773" parent="aspace_415c7991135f7cd83b3529e8548edc08" type="folder">10</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref34_20p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biography of Moses G. Farmer in a bound book with notes and dates of discoveries made by him but not written by him; also a list of names and dates.</unittitle><container id="aspace_8268016dcf21b207cb90cae9af151672" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_3f9312cbe411c9b8f570dfcbe3fd3a9f" parent="aspace_8268016dcf21b207cb90cae9af151672" type="folder">11</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref35_d37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various writings of Moses G. Farmer including school compositions of his youth and part of a paper on predictions into the future of transportation.</unittitle><container id="aspace_87927df57ded57cbc397cafc3b5ea6d5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_eb7da3f4cd394ae7e62a65d99d4a1856" parent="aspace_87927df57ded57cbc397cafc3b5ea6d5" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref36_1hr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Insurance policies on fire protection and the life of Moses G. Farmer between</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1856 and 1859.</unitdate><container id="aspace_561f7e2d7aac25111861692448d1b67f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_0d5d6e1d8acf22a21ff97b55404cdaca" parent="aspace_561f7e2d7aac25111861692448d1b67f" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref37_qzl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal papers of Moses G. Farmer concerning claims of debt or damage during</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1857 and 1861.</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e263ecb245b3cc649f7ebafb7b058a3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_cf579fd1c9d545d12d38f7aa336e4f85" parent="aspace_8e263ecb245b3cc649f7ebafb7b058a3" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref38_p5f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous notes, drawings, and calculations of Moses G. Farmer regarding his inventions.</unittitle><container id="aspace_d7a03dad4c418150ed4a928832042b18" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_fa839dab549f3280d25974f72257b4b3" parent="aspace_d7a03dad4c418150ed4a928832042b18" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref39_erh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous accounts of Farmer's construction materials used in his invention from including a bound ledger for the years</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1856-1889 1852-1855.</unitdate><container id="aspace_f74e19e8c5e36ffe97775a270421b6fe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_115f71ca5a5ed0b96d6060d6dfd5b8d0" parent="aspace_f74e19e8c5e36ffe97775a270421b6fe" type="folder">5</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref40_qgu" level="file"><did><unittitle>The electric railway invention of Moses G. Farmer including newspaper clippings, a pamphlet, notes, drawings, and a picture of the invention.</unittitle><container id="aspace_ca8877594cee1e80075f7c99b0b50765" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_f32651a54f05b7e5fe6244d08577cbf5" parent="aspace_ca8877594cee1e80075f7c99b0b50765" type="folder">6</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref41_ixw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fire Alarm System invention by Moses G. Farmer with articles concerning who was the real inventor by Charles C. Coffin and others; also published patents and notes.</unittitle><container id="aspace_a890bd67ce5193a45dd52f89e09ad230" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_3db618f0c4570d3ad64fc5b4e00dc2c9" parent="aspace_a890bd67ce5193a45dd52f89e09ad230" type="folder">7</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref42_4w7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fire Alarm System continued with pamphlets and a Record of Proceedings of the U.S. Patent Office regarding the extention of the patent; included are articles on William F. Channing.</unittitle><container id="aspace_8a27bcdd136d59f645c4d653e935b017" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_fdacd355fecdc66e8bc99a429026728d" parent="aspace_8a27bcdd136d59f645c4d653e935b017" type="folder">8</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref43_ttg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lists of patents issued to Moses G. Farmer from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1852 to 1888.</unitdate><container id="aspace_ddf5c7e8d1abb612c17b5bfb74d1f8cf" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_baec6186856af311148b1f91e8f959f5" parent="aspace_ddf5c7e8d1abb612c17b5bfb74d1f8cf" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref44_hye" level="file"><did><unittitle>Original patents of three of Farmer's inventions-- Magneto-Electric Machines Repeaters for Submarine Cables and Electric Cable Recorders 1885.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1875, 1885,</unitdate><container id="aspace_43dc42a200ce69b5cfd0b8b3799a9255" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_be33ee37f976f7b811427a3052f4f4f4" parent="aspace_43dc42a200ce69b5cfd0b8b3799a9255" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref45_5n5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Applications for patents by Moses G. Farmer consisting of both written and typed copies and the originals from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1854-1891.</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb06a738ca9088581ffaedea5885522e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_d7c4b826989216d750710918a331f8ba" parent="aspace_eb06a738ca9088581ffaedea5885522e" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref46_lxx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Agreements regarding patents of Moses G. Farmer with associates like J.M. Batchelder, J.F. Boynton, Charles C. Coffin, etc. in original and copied forms from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1851-1859.</unitdate><container id="aspace_860b084f4923cecfde9da3331948ecbb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_aa82d1e137a381ccb3f5d81f59568618" parent="aspace_860b084f4923cecfde9da3331948ecbb" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref47_a9m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Agreements regarding patents by Moses Farmer continued from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1880 to 1889.</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2bfd434fdcd627a202fb8b909f5b947" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_79b9b2ed6526b7d79aee68252e8f2b83" parent="aspace_a2bfd434fdcd627a202fb8b909f5b947" type="folder">5</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref48_8fv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Published patents of Moses G. Farmer's inventions from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1852-1879.</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d724012cb05c10448e007f811fce789" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_a474c2e4cfc7cc678c3ebe4938ffb5ab" parent="aspace_1d724012cb05c10448e007f811fce789" type="folder">6</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref49_b7g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Published patents of Moses G. Farmer's inventions from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1881-1891.</unitdate><container id="aspace_47ed975be27be9584ce769e5cf65adda" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_5d572deadc3f327caf5ef20efd92e680" parent="aspace_47ed975be27be9584ce769e5cf65adda" type="folder">7</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref50_jgm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Published patents of Thomas A. Edison's inventions from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1878-1881</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfcd23fb27345d720feb466c8840edf5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_2e4a021def8f4257fc8ec2acb2e51b24" parent="aspace_bfcd23fb27345d720feb466c8840edf5" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref51_2lp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Published patents of other inventors in alphabetical order such as Amos E. Dolbear, A.W. Hall, C.J. Kintner, Ernst W. Siemens, H.C. Spalding, J.C. Swan, and others.</unittitle><container id="aspace_0af8f4c162a4065703abe86a7f01c8b8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_ead130581eaa5454992e026b4a8e0bf4" parent="aspace_0af8f4c162a4065703abe86a7f01c8b8" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref52_y9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Copies of letters, applications and original patents of inventors other than Mosses G. Farmer from</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1855-1878.</unitdate><container id="aspace_e629f0144f4a0fb6d3c79587c4b293fb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_c56502227f34db1c33359c987971f5c8" parent="aspace_e629f0144f4a0fb6d3c79587c4b293fb" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref53_sn0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous material regarding the field of electricity in general including newspapers, pamphlets, and clippings with emphasis on the electric light, the telephone, and the electromagnetic telegraph invented by Joseph Henry.</unittitle><container id="aspace_1fdef7cd8d883133006c2c0bad8d5e6d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_e8d065777ad85ba5cc36a40dca61ed87" parent="aspace_1fdef7cd8d883133006c2c0bad8d5e6d" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref54_3dx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Journal of Hannah Farmer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">December 25, 1844-May 9, 1845.</unitdate><container id="aspace_22d0cbe0331c7fbd3d4cb6b94b596309" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
