<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1g5025qk/">garem453.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Garemani Family collection of Persian and Arabic manuscripts and books</titleproper><titleproper>Garemani Family Collection of Persian and Arabic Manuscripts and Books <num>LSC.0453</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared Ali Anooshahr with assistance from Laurel McPhee in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), Winter 2005; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé and edited by Caroline Cubé, Laurel McPhee Kelley Wolfe Bachli and Amy Shung-Gee Wong.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2006.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-02 13:17:26 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Garemani Family collection of Persian and Arabic manuscripts and books</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.0453</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1514/1899" type="inclusive">circa 1514-1899</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ad9e8fdb19522d8380ace1bee11a14a0" label="Abstract">The collection consists of Persian and Arabic printed works and manuscripts dating from approximately 1514-1899. Subjects include history, literature, medicine, mathematics, diplomatics, theology, and poetry.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_4264e8e0d6946eca88705a9709d27777">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b2e7a75d717668263ef25bbc7d3cee06">Materials are in Arabic and Persian.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_91d00e67feef18cc6a4e2d54fa057639">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_824fe38cf8205c9e96f2a6d2307e0c1e">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_15c264989e2c91c54c9ea5e9794d404b">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Noyan and Homa Garemani, 2004.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_90d61f5d9c5b0f26aefbfa9697c256e3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Garemani Family collection of Persian and Arabic manuscripts and books (Collection 453). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f6dee7afd6cf37210237504e21500e6f">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Ali Anooshahr with assistance from Laurel McPhee in the Center for Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), Winter 2005.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_616bba08545380e092bc25d63c2ede9d">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9953992723606533">9953992723606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0d9fa4e824e542a2511508640b96a201">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection consists of nineteen Iranian manuscripts and three rare printed works, dating from the late Safawid to the late Qajar periods. The subjects of the items vary from science and medicine to history, literature, religion, and grammar. Of particular scholarly interest is a rare Persian translation of an unidentified Turkish commentary on Maulana Jalal al-Din Rumi's Ma&amp;#x1E63;nav&amp;#x1FD1;, and an original Persian-language biography on Napolean Bonaparte. Published works have been included in the finding aid; in addition, full catalog records for these books can be found in the UCLA Library online catalog by performing a keyword search on the phrase, "Noyan Garemani collection" in the UCLA Library catalog.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_dba9e20875755d3fdc147315012a37b3">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in the following series:
 <list type="ordered">
 <item>Books, 1873-1911 (Box 1).</item>
 <item>Manuscripts, ca. 1514-1899 (Boxes 1-3).</item>
</list></p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civilization, Arab -- Archives.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arabic literature -- 1801 -- Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arabic literature -- 1258-1800 -- Archives.</subject>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Jalal al-Din Rumi, Maulana</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref6_ijf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1873-1911</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_ref10_823" level="item"><did><unittitle> To the high and mighty sovereign, the Shah of Persia ... [Hertford, England: Stephen Austin and Sons, Printers, 1873]. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1873</unitdate><container id="aspace_c880ab738c2e69a71669a8ebe0e39b3d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2defdb0a7face144c0e028c0ea07dc42" parent="aspace_c880ab738c2e69a71669a8ebe0e39b3d" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7e25234d4076bb072d79f7bf923da62e"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Correspondent: Anglo-Jewish Association.</p><p>Physical Description: 1 item.</p><p>Physical Description: Bound in red morocco, with gilt edges.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Petition to the Shah of Persia by the Anglo Jewish Association, requesting "an equal measure of justice to all ... subjects" on behalf of the Jews of Persia.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref12_cqg" level="item"><did><unittitle> [Tehran]: Dar karkhana-I ustad ?aj ?Abd al-Ra?im ?urat al-?iba paziruft, 1335 [1911]. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1911.</unitdate><container id="aspace_2881f13e98e586e7488e4104bb5aaed6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_dad1e64af5466eb1c0f19967ca7a37eb" parent="aspace_2881f13e98e586e7488e4104bb5aaed6" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e7696fe0baf1c6352a00a42850b9928"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondent: Munsha ?at-I Mi?bah. Kitab-I munsha ?at-I Mi?bah.</p><p>Physical Description: 1 item.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Letter-writing manual, in Persian. Quarter blue cloth, brown marbled wrappers over boards. Inscribed in Persian on front endpapers: "This book belongs to Mahdi Ma?rashi." With the stamp of the Ministery of Cultural Affairs.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref14_7af" level="item"><did><unittitle>The bronze statue, or, The virgin's kiss = Bushe-yi ?a?o?a ([Tehran]: Dar al-?ibaa-I Farus, 1326 [1908]).  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1908.</unitdate><container id="aspace_24363701ddb8f64796bbd598128fce02" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9bdc454b5039b46f029f76d7bbbd90f7" parent="aspace_24363701ddb8f64796bbd598128fce02" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21406f7edc5f4604e3a6bf0179bcba4e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondent: Reynolds, George W. M. (George William MacArthur).
Physical Description: 1 item.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Rare Persian translation of Reynold's, The bronze statue.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Letter-writing manual, in Persian. Quarter blue cloth, brown marbled wrappers over boards. Inscribed in Persian on front endpapers: "This book belongs to Mahdi Ma?rashi." With the stamp of the Ministery of Cultural Affairs.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_dww" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1514-1899</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_ref17_p69" level="item"><did><unittitle>1  Risalah dar fann-i ?ibb  (Treatise in the art of medicine).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1804</unitdate><container id="aspace_82163c4a37d9d79fbda76e04b83df37b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_de5cf1bcc2ee4e2102c6cf9ee3968b35" parent="aspace_82163c4a37d9d79fbda76e04b83df37b" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5060e8e48ee314a927f5b330118472e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: ?Ali al-Ri?a ibn Musá, d. 818 or 19.</p><p>Physical Description: 64 leaves : paper ; 164 x 103 mm. bound to 164 x 107 mm.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Interlinear Persian translation of a treatise on medicine by the eighth Shiite Imam ?Ali al-Ri?a ibn Musá. It is also known as Risalah al-dhahabiyah, or "The golden." The translator's name is Mu?ammad ibn al-?asan al-Mashhadi (possibly also the scribe). The content covers a variety of diseases and the cures, and develops a theory of physiognomy. The body is compared to a kingdom whose king is the soul, and the agents of the king are the limbs and the veins. The home of the king is the heart; and his treasury, the intestine and the stomach. The text recommends good food and drink to maintain health and cure ailments. The manuscript also discusses the four humors, general hygiene, and recommendations for sleep and brushing teeth. The manuscript concludes with a summary of the stages of life (the final stage beginning at age forty), and rules for bathing, bowel movements, traveling, and copulation.</p><p>Layout: Average of 16 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh.</p><p>Binding: Stiff red leather, with brown leather spine.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Arabic terms and phrases in blue, Persian text in black; marginalia in several hands.</p><p>Text in Arabic and Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref19_nyk" level="item"><did><unittitle>2  Atishkadah Fire altar.  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1804-1805</unitdate><container id="aspace_9441f4add92a1c31eaca43222d023119" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0f317883bc2520ac6ff0c9964215483d" parent="aspace_9441f4add92a1c31eaca43222d023119" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a5891ae10d11918750db5eda86b56e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: [Bafqi, Mu?ammad Mufid ibn Ma?mud, 17th cent.]</p><p>Scribe: Aman Allah ibn Mu?ammad Taqi [Zanganah?] Na?ir.</p><p>Physical Description: 66 leaves : paper ; 175 x 105 mm. bound to 178 x 111 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
A?ar Baygdili's anthology of several hundred Persian poets from all regions of Iran and present-day Afganistan. This version is contemporary with the third-oldest manuscript used by ?asan Sadat Na?iri in his 1958-1962 partial critical edition.</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1b-5b: Opening and table of contents.
    * ff. 5b-179b: First censer: older poets.
    * ff. 5b-14a: First flame: poetry of kings.
    * ff. 14a-151b: First ember: the poets of Iran.
    * ff. 14a-28b: First flare: Azerbayjan.
    * ff. 28b-77b: Second flare: Khurasan.
    * ff. 77b-85b: Third flare: Caspian region.
    * ff. 85b-132b: Fourth flare: the two Iraqs.
    * ff. 85b-86a: First ray: Persian poetry of Arab Iraq.
    * ff. 86a-132b: Second ray: Persian poetry of Persian Iraq.
    * ff. 132b-151b: Fifth flare: Fars.
    * ff. 151b-175a: Second Ember: the poets of Turan.
    * ff. 175a-177b: Third Ember: the poets of India (Deccan, Delhi, and Kashmir).
    * ff. 177b-179b: Light: the poetesses.
    * ff. 179b-239a: Second censer: contemporary poets.
    * ff. 179b-215a: First beam: contemporaries of the author.
    * ff. 215a-239a: Second beam: the author.</p><p>Layout: 25 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Black leather blind stamped binding.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink with headings in red. Occasional staining. Notes in pencil and ink, in several hands, on pastedowns and endpapers.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref21_e3i" level="item"><did><unittitle>3  Jam?-I Mufidi mujallid-i siyyum The third volume of the beneficial collection.  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1860</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a0318bf3fbda316f85f58c35fbd4d79" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7d22d4f804ff1c9a95a04b051bd4faef" parent="aspace_3a0318bf3fbda316f85f58c35fbd4d79" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db0a6e8c60fa131d48d4466d538b2761"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: [Bafqi, Mu?ammad Mufid ibn Ma?mud, 17th cent.]</p><p>Physical Description: 66 leaves : paper ; 175 x 105 mm. bound to 178 x 111 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Selection from Bafqi's Jam?-I Mufidi (History of Yazd, or Iran), consisting of a biography of 14th century Shiite Sufi master Ni ?mat Allah Vali. In the introduction, Bafqi states that he consulted a number of contemporary texts on his subject (f. 5). The narrative begins with the master's birth in Aleppo, and then relates his travels, pilgrimages, encounters with important personages, and arrival in the city of Kirman (f. 23a). The biography concludes with a lengthy list of the central figures of the order, following Ni ?mat Allah Vali's death. The last date mentioned in the text is 1655 December 12, well within the author's lifetime.</p><p>Layout: 15 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft dark green leather, blind stamped.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink with headings, or the first few words of each section, in red.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref23_g2e" level="item"><did><unittitle>4 [Biography of Napoleon Bonaparte]. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[ca. 1808?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_3917a924aaa2b30aeb8e303e63d79a3d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_531bd8fb007edfdfdcd131005cb1fbd8" parent="aspace_3917a924aaa2b30aeb8e303e63d79a3d" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_28d9ad129e37e1c42a17a9891bbc2b21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Physical Description: 79 leaves : paper ; 214 x 160 mm. bound to 217 x 165 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Original biographical composition on Napoleon Bonaparte; possibly incomplete, or lacking pages towards the end. Continuous narrative, without chapter divisions, except for three breaks on 38a, 39b, and 60b. After each break the author writes "thus says the author" or "the narrator narrates," thereafter resuming his story. The author refers to his subject as "General Napoleon," and the last dated reference is 1796. However, the biography was clearly composed at a later date, as author mentions an event which occurred in 1808 (f. 25a), when Bonaparte was First Consul and Emperor of France. The historical context for this biography reflects the political and nationalistic tensions during the reign of King Fat?-?Ali Shah Qajar (r. 1797-1834), who courted the French for military assistance to offset the Russian threat to the north, and the British expansion in India and modern Afghanistan in the east and southeast.</p><p>Layout: Average 21 lines of text per page (in columns).</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Decoration: First two pages gilt.</p><p>Binding: Soft black leather.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, framed in a red, gold, and blue border. Occasional stains and smears.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref25_ibd" level="item"><did><unittitle>5  ?Ayn al-bakka? Weeper's eye.  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[18--]</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3e0e25a2e6710241f5c4fb17ffc6cb1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_e92f0c610de939eedbc2e68a9f8f418a" parent="aspace_d3e0e25a2e6710241f5c4fb17ffc6cb1" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_18b01af1013a3cf73b459c423f09842d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Burujirdi, Sayyid ?Ali Naqi.</p><p>Scribe: Mu?ammad ?usayn ibn Mu?ammad Ja? far.</p><p>Physical Description: 263 leaves : paper ; 210 x 130 mm. bound to 210 x 136 mm.</p><p>Origin: Iran/Iraq.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Collection of stories about the death or martyrdom of Shiite holy figures, with special emphasis on the events surrounding the death of the third Imam, ?usayn ibn ?Ali (see Storey I, p. 219). The manuscript immediately opens with a narrative, instead of the typical introductory paragraphs. It begins with ?usayn's march from Medina towards Kufa, where he was met by an opposing army, followed by an account of the martyrdom of several of his companions. This section also tells the story of Za? far the genie, who volunteers to die for the Imam. Next, ?usayn gives the final speech to his family before the 10th of Mu?arram (the day of his martyrdom), and the author includes accounts of the deaths of ?usayn's grandfather (the prophet Mu?ammad), mother (Fa?ima ?ahra?, Mu?ammad's daughter), and father (Imam ?Ali).
The narrative shortly reverts to the martyrdom of the eighth Imam (?Ali al-Ri?a) before returning to the subject of ?usayn, specifically ?usayn's severed head, which prompts fantastic occurrences en route to Syria. The manuscript also covers the battle of ?iffin, where ?usayn's father ?Ali had been betrayed by his companions; it then diverts to the story of Abraham's near sacrifice of Ishmael (as opposed to Isaac, in Genesis). The author concludes with accounts of the martyrdom of ?usayn's other male relatives.</p><p>Layout: 14 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Brown leather, blind stamped; light blue pastedowns.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Chapter headings and punctuations in red ink, text in black. The text is bordered by a red box for the first eight leaves; the final chapter headings are blank.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref27_qdg" level="item"><did><unittitle>6 [Correspondence, et. al]. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[ca. 1827?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_502b93ce17e7d9277aafe3837ec86122" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_cdb16a7f56fab55f864353a6510892d1" parent="aspace_502b93ce17e7d9277aafe3837ec86122" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_05ba4f09d2e9e07cc2aa3cdc6846958d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Physical Description: 56 leaves : paper ; 278 x 189 mm. bound to 280 x 193 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Persian translation of a draft report on the province of ?Iraq-I ?Ajam (in modern-day central and western Iran), and copies of translated correspondence between the Qajar ruling elite and various European powers, especially Imperial Russia. In 1826, Russia had defeated the Qajars a second time, and annexed additional territory in the Caucasus. Fat? ?Ali Shah was rumored to harbor plans to construct a city in the province of ?Iraq-I ?Ajam, as the road between Azerbayjan and the capital Tehran was unprotected. The correspondence, report, and assorted documents probably relate to these events, as the scribe dedicates the manuscript to Fat? ?Ali Shah Qajar (r. 1797-1834) and writes that the people of Iran have been subjected to much cruelty of late. The last letter is dated 1827 January 6.</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1b-4b: Opening.
    * ff. 4b-13b: Provincial survey of ?Iraq-I ?Ajam.
    * ff. 13b-18a: Blank.
    * ff. 18a-36b: Translation of papers documenting diplomatic exchange with Britain (1823 November 20).
    * ff. 37a-39a: Blank.
    * ff. 39a-44b: Correspondence documenting Russian and Austrian affairs.
    * ff. 45a-46a: Blank.
    * ff. 46b-50a: Correspondence documenting Russian and French affairs (some written by Qajar official in Istanbul).
    * ff. 50b-51a: Blank.
    * ff. 51b-56a: Report of diplomatic mission to Istanbul.</p><p>Layout: 12 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft green leather.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, except for the geographical indicators in the report, which are in red. Occasional staining and separation of leaves.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref29_grr" level="item"><did><unittitle>7  Mirqat al-?u? ud fi taw?id al-wujud Ladder of ascension in the unity of existence. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c349141c9d69ab5a37555ad8ee950b3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_33e1da0c40cdefe3eb0340838c06409a" parent="aspace_9c349141c9d69ab5a37555ad8ee950b3" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c316bd215a27afab4632a05289d773d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Imam-i Jum?a, al-?aj Mulla Mu?ammad ?Ali.</p><p>Scribe: ?Abd Allah Tabrizi Qazvini.</p><p>Physical Description: 65 leaves : paper ; 180 x 101 mm. bound to 165 x 111 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Religio-philosophical treatise. Each section discusses a theme, or an exegesis, on verses from the Koran or Hadith. The author begins by rebuking those who see only appearances, followers of opinions and whims; thus establishing the binary opposition of appearance/essence. Manuscript includes several sections on desire, followed by relevant exegetical passages. Also contains numerous discussions on aspects of the soul.</p><p>Layout: 14 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Bound in cats-paw calf, stamped in gilt, with marbled endpapers. The text block is entirely detached from its binding, and extends 15 milimeters above the top of the boards.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, with occasional page stains. Sparse marginalia, including a few Russian notations in pencil.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref31_vvi" level="item"><did><unittitle>8  al-?Awamil fi al-na?w The elements of grammar.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1824</unitdate><container id="aspace_09945202d6531d28a0bf6b8bbfa76219" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_9e933d483c55a5430a946085ce5edc6b" parent="aspace_09945202d6531d28a0bf6b8bbfa76219" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ad2878eec7040600718e5376a0694a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Jurjanii, ?Abd al-Qahir ibn ?Abd al-Ra?man, d. 1078?</p><p>Physical Description: 27 leaves : paper ; 215 x 164 mm. bound to 217 x 165 mm.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Jurjani's 11th century grammatical treatise on Arabic, ?Awamil al-mi ?ah. A second title, written in red ink on f. 1b, reads "hadha kit?b al-?awamil al-Jurjani," or "this is Jurjani's book of elements." The manuscript begins with divisions of words into "sound and sense," or pronunciation and meaning. The concept of "sound" is further subdivided into acoustic and modal categories; the first consisting of 91 additional subdivisions, and the second, 7. These subdivisions, plus the two major divisions of sense or meaning, add up to Jurjani's one hundred elements of grammar.</p><p>Layout: 12 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh.</p><p>Binding: Soft black leather, blind stamped, with golden paper pastdowns.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink on blue paper, with some headings and underlining in red, and extensive marginalia. Occasional staining and holes.</p><p>Text in Arabic.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref33_3ni" level="item"><did><unittitle>9  [Divan-i Manuchihri Damghani] [Poems of Manuchihri Damghani].</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c3f716f1bd4de450e6a0b13a8e585d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4765f663b8681c34772187b47cb6caa9" parent="aspace_0c3f716f1bd4de450e6a0b13a8e585d3" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a21ee0bc3f3c70a0b71b074ccb19bda0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: [Manuchihri Damghani, Abu Najm Mirza Ma?mud Hakim.</p><p>Scribe: A?mad ibn Qaw?].</p><p>Physical Description: 34 leaves : paper ; 208 x 125 mm. bound to 210 x 130 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Selected poetry by 11th century Persian poet Manuchihri Damghani. The manuscript contains six of Manuchihri Damghani's "qa?idas," panegyrics to the Ghaznawid dynasty court elite, and a number of "tarji? bands," poems with refrain.</p><p>Layout: Average 13 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft brown leather, blind stamped.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink on blue paper. ff. 30-34 are stained.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref35_du7" level="item"><did><unittitle>10  [Siraj al-munir, va Divan-i Sabzavari] [The luminous light beam, and Poems of Sabzavari].</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_08f30a8376fcee9fe852c8db70d4b609" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4b0e1a8116582c4cb8c72340189081a6" parent="aspace_08f30a8376fcee9fe852c8db70d4b609" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a77aae93ab47b6f5cd8530adf8b7511"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Mu?ammad Sharif ibn Shams al-Din Mu?ammad ; Sabzavari, Hadi ibn Mahdi, b. 1797 or 8.</p><p>Scribe: ?afi? ibn ?Abd al-Karim al-?Aqili al-Kirmani.</p><p>Physical Description: 130 leaves : paper ; 117 x 110 mm. bound to 181 x 115 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
The manuscript contains two works. Siraj al-munir (ff. 1-66) is a 17th century work by Mu?ammad Sharif ibn Shams al-Din Mu?ammad. The second work (ff. 67-130) is a collection of poems by Hadi ibn Mahdi Sabzavari (b. 1797 or 8). The title of the second work, as given in the manuscript, is Divan-i ta ?lifat va ghazaliyyat-i afkar-i abkar-i fakhr al-?arifin jinab-i ?aji Mulla Hadi-yi Sabzavari al-mutikhalli? bi Asrar, which translates to "The anthology of the compositions and sonnets of the unprecedented ideas of the glory of Gnostics, his grace the pilgrim Mulla Hadi of Sabzavar, with the nom-de-plume 'Mysteries'." The scribe has written some dedicatory lines to the Qajar prince Amid al-Dawlah (66a).</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1b-65a: The luminous light beams.
    * ff. 1b-4b: Table of contents.
    * ff. 4b-8a: The first flash: courtesy.
    * ff. 8a-11a: The second flash: shame.
    * ff. 11a-13b: The third flash: restraint.
    * ff. 13b-16a: The fourth flash: justice.
    * ff. 16a-19a: The fifth flash: benevolence.
    * ff. 19a-22b: The sixth flash: patience.
    * ff. 22b-26b: The seventh flash: love.
    * ff. 26b-29b: The eighth flash: kindness.
    * ff. 29b-32b: The ninth flash: generosity.
    * ff. 32b-37b: The tenth flash: bravery.
    * ff. 37b-41a: The eleventh flash: conversation.
    * ff. 41a-45a: The twelfth flash: reversal of fortune.
    * ff. 45a-47b: The thirteenth flash: silence.
    * ff. 47b-50b: The fourteenth flash: the ability to live without.
    * ff. 50b-52a: The fifteenth flash: coveting.
    * ff. 52a-54a: The sixteenth flash: youngmanliness (chivalry).
    * ff. 54a-56b: The seventeenth flash: foresight.
    * ff. 56b-59a: The eighteenth flash: oppression.
    * ff. 59a-61b: The nineteenth flash: fraud.
    * ff. 61b-64b: The twentieth flash: jealousy.
    * ff. 64b-65a: Closing.
    * ff. 66a-66b: Dedication.
    * ff. 67a-130a: The anthology of Sabzavari.</p><p>Layout: Average 15 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft black leather, blind stamped.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink on blue paper, with headings, some names, verse markers, and some punctuation in red. Title of second work on fore-edge.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref37_ba3" level="item"><did><unittitle>11  ?iya? al-?amir The glow of comprehension.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1730</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfea9fa925d782ac8500c3620eb41190" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_d0660f6ddb9eb690413855bae5f44344" parent="aspace_bfea9fa925d782ac8500c3620eb41190" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a23e1e64211d896100d79b0ed9be6a04"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Mullá ?Ali.</p><p>Scribe: ShAmlu, Murta?á Quli.</p><p>Physical Description: 56 leaves : paper ; 183 x 109 mm. bound to 183 x 109 mm.</p><p>Origin: Persia.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Mathematical treatise covering basic arithmetic functions, including radicals, fractions, functions and uses, sample problems, and basic geometry. The target audience is probably those who use the information for practical matters, specifically small business accounting. For example, the first two sample problems deal with calculating wages; the third with buying produce; and the fourth and the fifth with the volume of water in cisterns.</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1b-3a: Opening.
    * ff. 3a-4b: Addition.
    * ff. 4b-5a: Halving.
    * ff. 5a-6a: Subtractions.
    * ff. 6a-15a: Multiplications.
    * ff. 15a-17b: Divisions.
    * ff. 17b-23b: Radicals.
    * ff. 23b-28b: Fractions.
    * ff. 28b-29a: Adding fractions.
    * ff. 29a-30a: Halving fractions.
    * ff. 30a-32b: Multiplying fractions.
    * ff. 32b-41a: Dividing fractions and other points.
    * ff. 41a-43a: Uses (accounting).
    * ff. 43a-49a: Sample problems.
    * ff. 49a-56b: Geometry (measuring area).</p><p>Layout: Average 9 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft red morocco.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, with charts, numbers, and headings in red. Staining and damage at the bottom right fore-edge; occasional marginalia. Extended title on the spine.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref39_tf8" level="item"><did><unittitle>12 [Prayer book]. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[ca. 18--?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_3195d831afce04aa7e31b8c486196156" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4fa33290a7036a5873238379d8697774" parent="aspace_3195d831afce04aa7e31b8c486196156" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_52387f8b22e06d937cb6a957d3ff6fbc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Physical Description: 135 leaves : paper ; 133 x 98 mm. bound to 135 x 103 mm.</p><p>Origin: Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Shiite prayer book of Koran verses, in addition to Arabic prayers accompanying instructions in Persian.</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1b: Chapter 1 and 117 of the Koran (al-IkhlA? &amp; al-Fati?a).
    * ff. 2a-11b: The prayer of Kumayl.
    * ff. 11b-15a: The prayer of "surrendering abundantly" (Tasliman Kathiran).
    * ff. 15a-19a: The prayer of "those who pardon" (al-Ra?imin).
    * ff. 19a-20a: The prayer of ending a visitation to the prophet and his family.
    * ff. 20a-32a: The prayer of twelve Imams by Na?ir al-Din al-?usi.
    * ff. 32a-33a: The prayer of Ali in the bed (Firash).
    * ff. 33b: The prayer after the Morning Prayer.
    * ff. 34a: The prayer after praising Fa?ima al-Zahra?.
    * ff. 34b: The prayer for after every required Prayer (namaz).
    * ff. 34b-35a: After the Morning Prayer.
    * ff. 35a-36a: After the Noon Prayer.
    * ff. 36a-37a: After the Afternoon Prayer.
    * ff. 37a-37b: After the Sunset Prayer.
    * ff. 37b-39a: Also after the Sunset Prayer.
    * ff. 39a-40a: Prayers to be recited after the required Prayers during holy months.
    * ff. 40a-42b: Prayer for the pre-dawn (sa?ar) during Rama?an.
    * ff. 42b-46a: Prayer for the night of the nineteenth of Rama?an.
    * ff. 46a-47b: Prayer for the night of the twenty-first of the same month.
    * ff. 47b-49a: Prayers for the festival of breaking the fast (?d al-fi?r).
    * ff. 49a-60a: Prayers for the pilgrimage to great shrines.
    * ff. 60a-64b: Prayer for the tenth of Mu?arram.
    * ff. 64b-67a: How to visit Imam al-Ri?a.
    * ff. 67a-91a: Prayers for solving problems.
    * ff. 91a-94a: The prayer for deflecting adversity.
    * ff. 94a-: The prayer of the tens (?asharat).
    * ff. 101a-119a: The prayer of the small coat of mail (jawshan-i ?aghir).
    * ff. 119b-121a: Prayers (in a different hand).
    * ff. 121a-135: Blank.</p><p>Layout: Average of 15 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh (Arabic) and nasta? liq. (Persian).</p><p>Binding: Brown leather, blind stamped.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink on blue, yellow, green, or pink paper, with headings and underlines in red.</p><p>Text in Arabic and Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref41_ccg" level="item"><did><unittitle>13  A?adith Hadiths.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[between 1514 and 1558]</unitdate><container id="aspace_34c0040aa4c139c9f35171f23e7254f1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_f564fc5dd992dcb4fd47b38fad05b4e9" parent="aspace_34c0040aa4c139c9f35171f23e7254f1" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3ea85eb125483b55de15fd0b436e8f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Qummi, Mu?ammad ibn A?mad, 10th/11th cent.</p><p>Scribe: Mashhadi, Abu ?alib ibn Abu al-Fat? al-?usayni.</p><p>Physical Description: 58 leaves : paper, ill. ; 199 x 123 mm. bound to 208 x 140 mm.</p><p>Origin: [Persia].</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Illuminated collection of Shiite Hadiths, or sayings of holy figures, translated into Persian. Mashhadi, the compiler, translator and calligrapher of the manuscript, writes that it was created for non-Arabic readers in ?afawid Persia. The major, but not exclusive source for selections is the work of 9th century scholar Mu?ammad ibn A?mad Qummi. The manuscript is dedicated to Shah ?ahmasb ?afawid (r. 1524-1576).</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1b-4a: Opening.
    * ff. 4a-7b: First hadith.
    * ff. 7b-11a: Second hadith.
    * ff. 11a-13a: Third hadith.
    * ff. 13a-15a: Fourth hadith.
    * ff. 15a-16a: Fifth hadith.
    * ff. 16a-17b: Sixth hadith.
    * ff. 18a-19b: Seventh hadith.
    * ff. 19b-20b: Eighth hadith.
    * ff. 20b-22b: Ninth hadith.
    * ff. 22b-25a: Tenth hadith.
    * ff. 25a-26a: Eleventh hadith.
    * ff. 26a-27b:Twelfth hadith.
    * ff. 27b-29a:Thirteenth hadith.
    * ff. 29a-31b: Fourteenth hadith.
    * ff. 31b-32b: First story.
    * ff. 32b-37b: Second story.
    * ff. 37b-39a: Third story.
    * ff. 39a-40b: Fourth story.
    * ff. 40b-42b: Twelve hadiths of Moses.
    * ff. 43a: blank.
    * ff. 43b-58a: Prayer and closing.</p><p>Layout: Average of 11 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh; from 40b-42b Arabic text in naskh, Persian text in nasta? liq.</p><p>Decoration: Illuminated throughout.</p><p>Binding: Black lacquer boards, painted in gold and black, with a red leather spine.</p><p>Additional description: Text in black, red, green, and blue, framed a thin green, gold, red, white, and blue decorative border.</p><p>Text in Persian and Arabic.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref43_5t8" level="item"><did><unittitle>14  Kitab-i ?ibb-i ?akim-i Ma?i mawsum bih si bakhiyah The medical book of the former sage known as the thirty stitches.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1866.</unitdate><container id="aspace_35c94e748bd932afcc279c9531e42b4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_3a7d38746a774598428c80e30d162759" parent="aspace_35c94e748bd932afcc279c9531e42b4e" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3967508f0f6f6a32f5c5d99f4cd60df4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: [Shamlu, Murta?á Quli].</p><p>Scribe: ?imni.</p><p>Physical Description: 66 leaves : paper ; 182 x 106 mm. bound to 186 x 112 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Medical text commonly attributed to author and calligrapher Murta?á Quli (Khan) Shamlu, son of ?asan Shamlu, 17th century ?afawid governor of Heart, in modern Afghanistan (Storey II, 263). The work is also known as the Khirqah. The scribe refers to himself as a descendant of the author's family, and dedicates the book to "the second ?a?ib Qiran," probably the Qajar king Na?ir al-Din Shah (r. 1848-96). The text covers topics of sexual health and reproduction, including infertility, manners and timing for copulation, determining the gender of fetuses, increasing sperm count, erectile function and enlargement, female sexuality (based on physical appearance of women), and curing a variety of ailments and discomforts. The recommendations almost always include the use of various potions, to be applied to the body or ingested.</p><p>Layout: 12 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft brown leather, blind stamped.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Chapter headings and other divisions in red ink, text in black. The name "?akim-I Ma?i" is signed in ink on the spine, fore-edge, and front endpapers. On leaf 39b, next to chapter 13, a note in the margin reads "the description of the 13th chapter was not there and therefore was not written."</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref45_v27" level="item"><did><unittitle>15  Tarikh-i padshahan-i ?Ajam ... az ... Kiyumars ilá ... Fat? ?Ali Shah-i Qajar The history of Persian kings ... from ... Kiyumars to ... Fat? ?Ali Shah-i Qajar.  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[between 1797 and 1834]</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d60dd4be3289db374bab544fb0d4dc5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_aa4976cc2740d2456d3be6e3e0f4e64e" parent="aspace_8d60dd4be3289db374bab544fb0d4dc5" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5af385fe9a5b34786d060f6d36a4b898"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Physical Description: 175 leaves : paper ; 217 x 114 mm. bound to 216 x 127 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Dynastic history of Iran, written during the reign of Fat? ?Ali Shah-I Qajar (r. 1797-1834). The manuscript includes a list of kings for each dynasty, and a brief summary of their most famous deeds. Possibly written by a member of the court elite, for use as a reference tool.</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 2a-4b: List of kings and dynasties.
    * ff.4b-15b: The Pishdadids (Kiyumarth to Alexander).
    * ff.16a-18a: The Party kings (From Alexander to Ardashir the Sasanian).
    * ff.18a-28b: Sasanians (Ardashir to Yazdgird III).
    * ff.28b-38a: The Arabs of Iraq and Syria (Banu Tamim, the Ghassanids, and the Himyarites).
    * ff.38b: Blank.
    * ff.39a-40b: List of kings from Mu?ammad to Fat?-?Ali Shah.
    * ff.41a-48b: From Mu?ammad to ?asan ibn ?Ali.
    * ff.49a-55a: The descendants of Mu?ammad (?usayn to Mu?ammad ibn al-?asan al-Mahdi).
    * ff.55b-: Blank.
    * ff.56a-59b: The Umayyids (Yazid to Marwan).
    * ff.60a-68b: Abbasids (Saffa? to al-Musta?sim).
    * ff.69a-90b: Kings contemporary with the Abbasids (?ahirids, ?affarids, Samanids, Ghaznawids, Ghurids, Buyids, Saljuqids.
    * ff.Khwarazm-Shahs, Ata Begs, Isma? ilis, Ayyubids, Qara Khi?a).
    * ff.90b-96b: The Mongols (Genghis Khan to Malik Ashraf).
    * ff.97a-106b: The party kings contemporary with the Mongols and after (Chupanids, Ilkayids, Amir Shaykh Abu al-?asan, Mu?affarids, Karts, Sarbadarids).
    * ff.107a-118b: The Gurakanids and Turcoman kings (Tamerlane and his descendants as well as Qara Quyunlu, Aq Quyunlu, Uzbeks).
    * ff.118b-134b: The ?afawids and Afghans.
    * ff.134b-148b: The Afsharids.
    * ff.149a-155b: The Zandids.
    * ff.155b-173b: The Qajars.</p><p>Layout: Average 20 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Red leather binding, stamped in black and gilt.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, in a red, gold, blue and black border.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref47_2kx" level="item"><did><unittitle>16  Tarjumah-i Farsi min la?ayif-i ma? navi The Persian translation of the spiritual pleasantries.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1761.</unitdate><container id="aspace_af2f3a60f2c47836cc3da62ae94e4986" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_29410805811f84df3b476155732ac050" parent="aspace_af2f3a60f2c47836cc3da62ae94e4986" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be686e55891063eb77163b22df3d69a6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Physical Description: 129 leaves : paper ; 180 x 110 mm. bound to 192 x 157 mm.</p><p>Origin: Persia.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Persian translation of an unidentified Turkish commentary on Maulana Jalal al-Din Rumi's Mas?avi. The manuscript begins well into Book 1, with the story of "The lion and the games" (verse 1186 of Nicholson's edition). The commentary does not follow the Mas?avi verse-to-verse, but proceeds selectively through the text. The final commentary is on verse 563 of Book 5, or the story of "The wise man and the peacock."</p><p>Contents:</p><p>    * ff. 1a-28a: Book One.
    * ff. 28b-60b: Book Two.
    * ff. 60b-94b: Book Three.
    * ff. 94b-125a: Book Four.
    * ff. 125a-129b: Book Five.</p><p>Layout: Average 21 lines of text per page, mostly diagonal.</p><p>Script: Nasta? liq.</p><p>Binding: Soft black leather, blind stamped. The text block is entirely detached from its binding.
Additional descriptive data: 16 quires, probably lacking quires from the beginning and end. Text in black ink, with verses and underlining often in red. Occasional staining and marginalia.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref49_m1o" level="item"><did><unittitle>17  Davazdah imam Twelve imams.  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[1897-1899]</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa1bc95fbfe8740c9fed36c371bf5df0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_1e283f0da17a30a20e1b13cac43231ab" parent="aspace_fa1bc95fbfe8740c9fed36c371bf5df0" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc280e5f522cf46af7b8b7606d8c698c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Tu?i, Na?ir al-Din Mu?ammad ibn Mu?ammad, 1201-1274.</p><p>Scribe: Mirza Mu?ammad ?Ali al-Arzinjani.</p><p>Physical Description: 16 leaves : paper ; 122 x 76 mm. bound to 126 x 80 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Short prayer by thirteenth-century Shiite scholar Na?ir al-Din Tusi, in an exemplary Naskh script. Dedicated by the scribe to the governor of Fars, ?Abd al-?usayn Mirza Farmanfarma.</p><p>Layout: Average 20 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh.</p><p>Decoration: Gilt applied to space between lines of text and borders (ff. 1b-2a.)</p><p>Binding: Brown leather binding, stamped in green, with blue and yellow pastedowns.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Exquisite calligraphy, with most of the text in black ink. The name of God appears in red or blue, and the word "praise," followed by the name of the prophet or an imam in red ink. Dedication in red and blue ink.</p><p>Text in Arabic and Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref51_slo" level="item"><did><unittitle>18  Zij Astronomical tables.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1827.</unitdate><container id="aspace_f317d2f584beb508cc041f404750abf1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_254a52b4ba7c736bb7447112efff57d6" parent="aspace_f317d2f584beb508cc041f404750abf1" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6c3c93220b5996bc09de246688e0d7d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: Tusi, Na?ir al-Din Mu?ammad ibn Mu?ammad, 1201-1274.</p><p>Scribe: ?Ali ibn ?Abd al-Razzaq al-Tabrizi.</p><p>Physical Description: 62 leaves : paper ; 243 x 186 mm. bound to 247 x 189 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
The manuscript contains three separate works, as indicated by a spine label stating, "Three books in one." The three texts are contained within seven parallel columns on each page, alternatively narrow (in red ink), and wide (in black ink). The two narrow columns set along the outer border of the pages contain single letters, and occasional pairs of letters; the two narrow internal columns consist of individual words. The text in the wider columns consists of complete sentences. The three compositions are written linearly within these columns throughout the extent of the manuscript, proceeding from page to page; one in the wider, black-ink columns, one in the outer narrow columns, and one in the inner narrow columns. A second hand, probably a former owner, has written the title "Tarikh dawlat rasuli" on the first leaf. The same title, in a different hand, is found on the fore-edge.</p><p>Layout: Average 17 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh.</p><p>Binding: Soft black leather with blue pastedowns.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Text in black, red, and orange ink; occasional stains.</p><p>Text in Arabic.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref53_fxt" level="item"><did><unittitle>19  [Tarikh-i Va??af] [Va??af's history].</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1843.</unitdate><container id="aspace_14aeb29872a72f5f380200fd1c47b0d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_5ba27a273cb0c16da62ceab6c5d7ff49" parent="aspace_14aeb29872a72f5f380200fd1c47b0d2" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2527bd5a2e92df6445e01729a8349ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Author: [Va??af al-?a??rat, ?Abd Allah ibn Fa?? Allah, 1264 or 5-1329?].</p><p>Physical Description: 261 leaves : paper ; 334 x 206 mm. bound to 350 x 212 mm.</p><p>Origin: Qajar Iran.</p><p>Scope and Content Note
Volumes 1 and 2 from Va??af's 5-volume history of the Mongols, including histories of the Hülegu, Qublai and Arghun, in addition to the Salghurids of Fars. Incomplete, with missing quires.</p><p>Layout: 17 lines of text per page.</p><p>Script: Naskh.</p><p>Additional descriptive data: Persian text in black, Arabic verses in red. Occasional marginalia and stains.</p><p>Text in Persian.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
