<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8qr51fr/">gord2270.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Gordon, Jr. (Walter L. )/Beverly, Jr. (William C.) collection</titleproper><titleproper>Finding aid for the Walter L. Gordon, Jr./William C. Beverly, Jr. collection <num>LSC.2270</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by UCLA Library Special Collections staff; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>©2015 The Regents of the University of California. All rights reserved.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-02 13:57:42 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Walter L. Gordon, Jr./William C. Beverly, Jr. collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.2270</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(5 boxes and 3 oversized flat boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1940/1949" type="inclusive">1940s</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3cfb3dd49039a94811d875cb91161e11" label="Abstract">Collection of approximately 800 digitized photographs and other items collected by Walter L. Gordon, Jr. and given to William C. Beverly, Jr., who donated the collection to UCLA. Collection includes photos given to Walter by his former boss, Charlotta Bass, publisher of the California Eagle, as well as other photos he collected. Photos largely depict African American social life and family life in 1940s Los Angeles and feature celebrities, athletes, politicians, lawyers, and other notable people of the era.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_23fa0e9ae63f292e4f38962683c453ed">Held at UCLA Library Special Collections. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://digital.library.ucla.edu/catalog/ark:/21198/zz002311rn" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Walter L. Gordon, Jr./William C. Beverly, Jr. Collection on the UCLA Digital Library" xlink:type="simple">
    <daodesc><p>Walter L. Gordon, Jr./William C. Beverly, Jr. Collection on the UCLA Digital Library</p></daodesc>
  </dao>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0bb7fb133637f10bf6d568f51b3889c9">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_137e68a28f9c45c5a57bf48df332bf01">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1717789f5b11f4dc12337204e16c7bbe">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Walter L. Gordon and William C. Beverly.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_216a98f15f22886241bda9a109e0325c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Walter L. Gordon, Jr./William C. Beverly, Jr. Collection (Collection 2270). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0c78979a97b5a86845799938775b29e6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_206154c0676cb043ec1726f7445fc6ed">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9967766733606533">9967766733606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4027c5e5b96e352f11554541d23475b5">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>The approximately 800 photographs in this collection represent the lifelong interest of Los Angeles African American attorney, Walter L. Gordon, in documenting little known aspects of African American history and culture through the first half the 20th century. Los Angeles and the legal profession were plagued by racial discrimination, but these photographs display a range of people, places and institutions who successfully defied society's limited expectations.</p><p>In 2002, the entire collection was given to William C. Beverly, Jr., who loaned them to Eighth &amp; Wall (an organization promoting the preservation of the history of the African American community of Los Angeles). In 2010, the collection was donated to UCLA. More information about Eighth &amp; Wall is available here: <extref xlink:href="http://www.eighthandwall.org" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">http://www.eighthandwall.org</extref></p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4aefebe2d8c9fb05820656baf8cd4267">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Materials include photographs given to Mr. Gordon by California Eagle newspaper publisher Charlotta Bass; photos Mr. Gordon collected of images of black resorts such as Val Verde; well-known political figures; sophisticated night life and social club functions; performing artists such as Count Basie, Louis Armstrong and Billie Holiday. Mr. Gordon established his law practice in 1936; he retired in 2004, after nearly seventy years practicing law.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
