<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf7f59p1p3/">gruenv93.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Gruen (Victor) collection</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Victor Gruen Collection <num>LSC.0093</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Manuscripts Division staff, 1998; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2002.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-21 15:19:05 -0800</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Victor Gruen collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Gruen, Victor</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.0093</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1968" type="inclusive">1952-1968</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ab5b2ab7273e4da373bf5de1c1c1ff78" label="Abstract">Victor Gruen (1903-1980) was an architect. He established Victor Gruen Associates in Los Angeles (1951) and designed shopping centers, including Northland Center in Detroit, Southdale Center in Minneapolis, The Mall in Fresno, California and Midtown Plaza in Rochester, New York (1962), the first inner-city enclosed mall. The collection consists of published articles by and about Victor Gruen.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_bc36d76372aead86df9238bf27626a11">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_46897ad51924292add7e8ebe5349d6ed">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1d524750e1d776168c9eba2e171690a7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d48f4bb50f428e4d7b36b12f4245da0c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <odd id="aspace_1055643910e7b193db29ad8dcfa6fad7">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942330993606533">9942330993606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_430e3bc6e9c510154283f64f2b69cce8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Victor Gruen Collection (Collection 93). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_49c63866a5b557205819a4b56a98d884">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Manuscripts Division staff, 1998.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's Library Collections and Archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8fd0492bd3b34afc4070545d3457b18c">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Victor Gruen was born Victor David Grünbaum in 1903 in Vienna, Austria; attended the Architectural School and the Academy of Arts in Vienna, where he developed a private practice; moved to New York in 1938, working for the Ivels Corporation and in the office of Norman Bel Geddes; formed a design partnership with Elsie Krummeck (1940-48); settled in Los Angeles, where he established Victor Gruen Associates in 1951; designed shopping centers, including Northland Center in Detroit and Southdale Center in Minneapolis; also designed The Mall in Fresno, California and Midtown Plaza, Rochester, New York (1962), the first inner-city enclosed mall, and Sea World, San Diego (1968); Fellow, American Institute of Architects; he died on February 14, 1980.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_009ad0fd6f0545de012f3f6748b9532b">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection consists of published articles by and about architect Victor Gruen.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <odd id="aspace_48a6494398f9c6d397f798e47dd12a56">
    <head>General note</head>
<p><emph render="italic">Description derived from in-house card file.</emph></p>  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Architects -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives</occupation>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Gruen, Victor</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref10_i9n" level="collection"><did><unittitle>Published Articles by and about Architect Victor Gruen</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1952-1968</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a2cb79d4162e89c941122c6366b88072" label="General Physical Description note">(1 box)</physdesc></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
