<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8f47qbr/">hend2118.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hendrix (Kathleen) collection on Paul Monette</titleproper><titleproper>Finding aid for the Kathleen Hendrix collection on Paul Monette, 1985-1995 <num>LSC.2118</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Gloria Gonzalez with assistance from Kelley Wolfe Bachli, October 2012; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>©2013 The Regents of the University of California. All rights reserved.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-02 15:08:54 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English.</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kathleen Hendrix collection on Paul Monette</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="local">Hendrix, Kathleen</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.2118</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 half document box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1995" type="inclusive">1985-1995</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bc219f2bd38b2f97f07fc0feb928e75c" label="Abstract">Kathleen Hendrix, humanitarian and former Los Angeles Times journalist, was a friend of both Paul Monette (1945-1995) and his partner in later life, Winston Wilde. Monette is best known for his contributions to contemporary gay American literature as a novelist and poet. The Kathleen Hendrix collection on Paul Monette includes materials gifted to Hendrix by Monette, including a limited edition two volume set of essays and poems, as well as items collected by Hendirx related to Monette and his work. The collection contains photographs, greeting cards, newspaper clippings, and ephemera.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_70094a47e383f6e3915217bb4c9c356b">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_99078b817e91e8a9ad557dda2680e9ba">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_36c7b6a1fc3925a803902b1e35d81d42">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_69919598cd853d9a13815159eb45bda5">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a81513f4fa5159dee4f6862e8e4a5a7a">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Kathleen Hendrix, 2012.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e6afb373ae883734520914b89af42e68">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Kathleen Hendrix collection on Paul Monette (Collection 2118). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_730a06b4afd9c48ce408053ab8647aa9">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_620fc322918307e1e91a590e92a66f8e">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9971053143606533">9971053143606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ec89e49f256ce6ba310f1069791bf6c6">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Kathleen Hendrix was a friend of both Paul Monette (1945-1995) and his partner in later life Winston Wilde. From 1974-1993 Hendrix worked as a journalist for the Los Angeles Times, reporting on a variety of social and political issues in America and abroad including feminism, activism, the Vietnam War, and globalization. Hendrix also worked for the United States Department of State where she focused on human rights issues and assisted in planning the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women in 1995. Paul Monette is known for his work as a novelist and poet in the genre of contemporary gay American literature. His work includes <emph render="italic">Borrowed Time: An AIDS Memoir</emph> (1988); <emph render="italic">Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story</emph> (1992), which won the National Book Award for nonfiction the same year; and <emph render="italic">Last Watch of the Night: a collection of essays</emph> (1994). The Hendrix Collection on Paul Monette contains materials acquired by Hendrix during their friendship, including a gifted limited edition collection of essays and poems by Monette, photographs, correspondence, newspaper clippings and ephemera.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_09223c35d761d9b3b1bd6543816b8d6c">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Kathleen Hendrix collection on Paul Monette contains greeting cards, photographs, newspaper clippings and other ephemera, a limited edition set of essays and poems, and documents related to Monette and his work. Newspaper clippings include author interviews with Monette from the Los Angeles Times and New York Times, as well as award announcements, obituaries, and memorial pieces. Documents include Monette's descriptions of arrangements for the Monette/Horowitz Trust and the Kolzak Prizes after his death; also included in the collection are three items written by Monette for Stephen Kolzak, a variety of handwritten notes from Monette to Hendrix inscribed on the title pages of novel manuscripts, and a program from Paul's memorial service in 1995.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_0c8c04e7f9f54c4102d39b2fb0fa568d">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Paul Monette papers (Collection 1707). UCLA Library Special Collections. <extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf1870042q/"  xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Finding aid available on the Online Archive of California.</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <persname role="wam" rules="rda" source="naf">Monette, Paul -- Archives</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="local">Hendrix, Kathleen</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref12_f7m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Limited edition two volume set of essays and poems titled <emph render="italic">Last Watch of the Night</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa early 1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e7d277c6309931be3c6bfb9e10ce5a48" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_166b7a30643ff9930ee2e891072b3a2c"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Contains handwritten inscriptions to Hendrix inside Volume I from Wilde and Monette. Paul's note says, "A Limited edition of these essays has been prepared for the author's friends, 25 copies in all. This is copy #5."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref14_wlf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs, greeting cards, newspaper clippings, documents and ephemera</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1995" type="inclusive">1985-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_534e83690dadea523d6873bded1febdc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d04aa956745d8f3ce76a6bf2d5e32e4f"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Photographs include a page of descriptions written by Hendrix. Newspaper clippings include author interviews with Monette, award announcements, book reviews, obituaries, and memorial pieces. Documents are Monette's descriptions of arrangements for the Monette/Horowitz Trust and the Kolzak Prizes after his death; ephemera includes items written by Monette for Stephen Kolzak, a variety of handwritten notes from Monette to Hendrix inscribed on the title pages of novel manuscripts, a Monette memorial button, and a program Paul's memorial service in 1995.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
