<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8h99c41/">ines2365.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Inesita papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Inesita Papers <num>LSC.2365</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Carolina Meneses, 2019.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2021 October 07.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-06-06 14:13:24 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Inesita papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Inesita</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.2365</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(12 boxes, 3 flat boxes, 1 carton)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18.92 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(11 digital files)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/2018" type="inclusive">1913-2018</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3403dd5bb09fce3c08972d6e0edba667">Inesita (1921-) is a Los Angeles-based dancer whose work and oeuvre is devoted to traditional forms of Spanish dance, including flamenco, the Bolero School of Dance of the 18th century, and other regional dances of Spain. Since the age of fourteen, she has performed in cabaret; film; television; musical theater; and as a soloist since the early 1950s in venues throughout Los Angeles, San Francisco, New York City, Mexico City, Madrid, Paris, London, Liverpool, and Valletta. The papers are a reflection of an eight decade career and include business and personal correspondence, contracts, programs, posters, press clippings, photographs, scripts, notes, ephemera, memorabilia, and a manuscript of Inesita's autobiography <title>A Dancer's Life</title>. The collection also contains digital and audiovisual materials, which include various audio and video recordings of performances or fragments of dance shows.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_d8821d8297091daf6f5e22804e294f56">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_237e20d803d8ea86646aafae8e7d5f7e">Materials are primarily in English, with some materials in Spanish and French.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bb3ed5488fb09e9f8bf20e2ae6b4ec96">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_ce8de5ff7f69e5aeb0a9209a53e66e80">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_ce49c5035577472c8a57d34c673a1ae3">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_7f9b13681c3f945e95e3a7d37b2f66a2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Copyright to portions of this collection has been assigned to the UCLA Library Special Collections. The library can grant permission to publish for materials to which it holds the copyright. All requests for permission to publish must be submitted in writing to Library Special Collections. Credit shall be given as follows: The Regents of the University of California on behalf of the UCLA Library Special Collections.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5b8ac2f4e704030a39e953d550247a44">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Inesita, 2018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_f489d5d3eeb1428e2e515d652c9d6c49">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9989156753606533">9989156753606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3ecedf735236fb693480dd298a0e7de4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Inesita papers (Collection 2365). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4d2fb04dd91c31665e0ffff7375f0515">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Carolina Meneses, under the supervision of Courtney Dean and Shira Peltzman in 2019.</p><p>The original arrangement was retained in most series. Inesita grouped materials by venue, city, state, and/or country. Portions of folder titles provided by her were retained but expanded upon by the archivist for ease of access.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's Library Collections and Archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_47e3d4914873e343c2334c25a263cf80">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Anice Mignon (née Stahl) Dworkin, best known as Inesita, was born on July 11, 1921 in New York City to parents who were classically trained musicians. She first studied violin and piano at an early age. Inesita's career as a Spanish dance artist began at the age of fourteen, not long after moving to Los Angeles, CA. Her work is devoted to traditional forms of Spanish dance, including flamenco, the Bolero School of Dance of the 18th century, and the regional dances of Spain's autonomous communities. Her studies began in Los Angeles and Mexico with Michael Brigante, Jose Fernandez, Janet Riesenfeld, Oscar Tarriba, and Antonio Triana; and then inevitably in Spain where she trained under the flamenco masters, Valencia y Rendón de Ávila ("El Estampio") and Regla Ortega, as well as the Pericet Family of <title>la escuela bolera</title> in Madrid.  Since her first show at La Golondrina Café on Olvera Street on October 7th, 1939, Inesita has performed in cabaret, film, television, and musical theater. Since the early 1950s, she has appeared as a soloist in venues throughout Los Angeles, San Francisco, New York City, Mexico City, Madrid, Paris, London, Liverpool, and Valletta.</p><p>Beyond pure flamenco, Inesita's body of work includes <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title>, a lecture-demonstration written by her husband, Bob Dworkin. Inesita lectured while demonstrating discrete parts of flamenco dance to illustrate structure, which she mostly performed in K-12 schools, colleges, and universities in Southern California between 1963 and 1988. Inesita has also presented a program featuring a suite of dances entitled <title>Themes from Goya</title>, which reflected the various stages of the Spanish painter's life. Its premiere at the Wilshire Ebell Theatre in 1955 was followed by performances at the University of California, Los Angeles in 1957 and at the Ivar Theatre in 1958. Another part of her oeuvre includes dances to the harpsichord sonatas of Domenico Scarlatti, which she premiered at the Wilshire Ebell Theater in Los Angeles 1970.</p><p>Since 2012, Inesita has performed with her own company featuring other flamenco artists and expanded her scope to integrate the talents of her colleagues with her own vision of Spanish theater. These programs have been presented by the Alhambra Performing Arts Center.</p><p>Sources:
"About Inesita – Flamenco Inesita." Accessed July 22, 2019. https://flamenco-inesita.com/about/.
Inesita (n.d.) LinkedIn page. Accessed September 16, 2019. https://www.linkedin.com/in/inesita-inesita-5b19a246.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_7c06c2d2de4ea7d9ea91b8aefbe4543f">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection is comprised of materials relating to each episode in Inesita's performing life, which includes correspondence, photographs, contracts, programs, posters, press clippings, scripts, notes, and other printed ephemera spanning eight decades of shows and engagements (1939-2018). Inesita's husband, Bob Dworkin acted as her agent, and, thus, a significant amount of the material is connected to his administration of Inesita's bookings, payment, and publicity as a flamenco dancer. Scripts of <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title>, a lecture demonstration presented by Inesita and written by Bob Dworkin are also included. </p><p>The collection contains audio and audiovisual material, which includes eleven VHSes; two vinyl records of <title>Inesita in Flamenco and Classic Spanish Dances</title>; ten 1/4 inch audiotapes; two 1/2 inch videotapes; and one U-matic. Additionally, there is a small amount of digital material (eight DVDs and five CDs), which include various audio and video recordings of piano and dance performances, or fragments of dance shows; as well as photographs and text from Inesita's book <title>A Dancer's Life</title>.</p><p>A significant amount of Inesita's personal correspondence and memorabilia are also included, such as fan letters, union cards, her Lester Horton Lifetime Achievement Award (2010), and her first dance dress.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_bc6f5fb7c36f6518eb31e6d9e06d62c8">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has been arranged in the following series:
<list type="simple">
<item>Series 1: Materials from California shows and engagements, 1934-2018</item>
<item>Series 2: Materials from shows and engagements in other U.S. states, 1945-2012</item>
<item>Series 3: Materials from shows and engagements abroad, 1940-1962</item>
<item>Series 4: Correspondence, 1913-2012</item>
<item>Series 5: Additional materials, 1923-2018</item>
</list></p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9ef89c624e893dc64e847e90be311c45">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p><extref xlink:href="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf1r29n7jk/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Willy Stahl papers (PASC-M 244).</extref> Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p><p>"Meet the Author" interviews, photographs, and reference materials (LSC 1755). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA. Collection is currently unprocessed. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Flamenco dancers -- California, Southern -- Archives.</geogname>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Women dancers -- California, Southern -- Archives.</occupation>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Inesita</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Dworkin, Bob</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_5009a4c1f434f005e281eec4680184df" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Materials from California shows and engagements</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/2018" type="inclusive">1934-2018</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_64101f64ae9a3ce9163eb99732d789ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is comprised of letters, contracts, programs, flyers, small posters, press clippings, and other ephemera related to Inesita's one-woman shows in California, particularly in her home base of Los Angeles. This includes materials from early piano recitals and flamenco shows; her film work from the 1940s and 1950s; <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title> lecture demonstrations at various venues; <title>Themes from Goya</title> presentations; and dance shows to the harpsichord sonatas of Domenico Scarlatti. This series also contains material from performances presented by the Alhambra Performing Arts Center with Inesita and her ensemble. Additionally, this series contains various audio and video recordings of performances or fragments of dance shows captured in nine VHSes; one U-matic; one 1/2 inch videotape; two 1/4 inch audiotapes; five DVDs; and one CD.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_38bf5dc7cab12177ae8ac6625a5ca83d"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><phystech id="aspace_40819c1299ee83087c8fcf4c862f44f9"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><c02 id="aspace_fa852dfc82169c0355a8a1e0b3e18f0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from early piano recitals at Pacific Institute of Music &amp; Fine Art</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/1941" type="inclusive">1934-1941</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_821fa1c7e4d2192f4e61cc092287b023" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_496a5b78602d036908ec7693b3f6ac87" parent="aspace_821fa1c7e4d2192f4e61cc092287b023" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c5603b70abd0ef78ab39d76c10682774" level="file"><did><unittitle>Early flamenco performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1949" type="inclusive">1939-1949</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_d25915363e8680eb39895e8fedf552b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_56bcd499ae6ec058db9eb44c06d69283" parent="aspace_d25915363e8680eb39895e8fedf552b6" type="folder">2-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0229a9214f563494175a2f354ff13d7f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials (programs, flyers, contracts, press clippings, and letters) related to Inesita's earliest one-woman shows and concerts throughout Southern California, including her first flamenco show at La Golondrina Café on Olvera Street in Los Angeles (1939). Other highlights include materials from Inesita's first major solo concert at the Municipal Concert Hall Long Beach (1943); ten month run as featured Spanish dancer in the musical, <title>The New Meet the People</title> (1944); and solo concert at the Wilshire Ebell Theatre (1949). A sheet entitled "Resumé of Performances" by Inesita is provided for more information about venues, producers, and dates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_61e17e3a7b50483a7ad9fc2ff4abf21f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Film appearances in <title>Skyline Serenade</title>, <title>Here Come the Girls</title>, and <title>Footlight Varieties</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1953" type="inclusive">1941-1953</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_8f816d36e9264ee59dafcc947629e48d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_82b1309c9fc2ba701ad397f4eab56c33" parent="aspace_8f816d36e9264ee59dafcc947629e48d" type="folder">2</container><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_9a9eb476f76643d0941cfb760e109f20" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_61f0eb513e941b26dfb2b57300088102" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b546b5b290df4b1f8157a4cb9bf2e0f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes black-and-white photographs (8 x 10 inches), posters, flyers, contracts, letters, and press releases related to three films in which Inesita was featured as a dancer: <title>Skyline Serenade</title> (1941), <title>Footlight Varieties</title> (1951) and <title>Here Come the Girls</title> (1953). In addition, there is one VHS and one DVD with 2.83 GB (one digital file) of video of Inesita dancing in <title>Here Come the Girls</title>.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_43e74fd3efb58c428b703959f7a96853"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_77a3a888e3f1ca012021449c83de7588"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_0bf08da50562de6076e9dcf8afebc540" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pan American Concerts tours</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1948" type="inclusive">1943-1948</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_2289302e5224920287496cd087335ae7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9c7d81982fd583d7ee0e1e3cf79110ab" parent="aspace_2289302e5224920287496cd087335ae7" type="folder">7-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a83693f80d1b6444e453ab096ddb3082"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily programs from five tours of concert revues with Pan American Concerts at various venues throughout California such as the Wilshire Ebell Theatre; Lobero Theatre; Marines' Memorial Theatre; Long Beach Municipal Auditorium; American Conservatory Theater's Geary Theater; Embassy Auditorium; Pasadena Shakespeare Club; and more.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5840de75d0c270d2102c810210a475c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Performances for various Southern California agencies and organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/2002" type="inclusive">1952-2002</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_89194c396800ac8d0f58e2f1d3ff38fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_36b15c26fd9d9e0365e9c2ec2dc3dc0f" parent="aspace_89194c396800ac8d0f58e2f1d3ff38fc" type="folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21f7060d2edefdc022c8fa0cc27fc101"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes letters, programs, and flyers related to performances for various Southern California agencies and organizations, such as the Council of Mexican American Affairs; Los Angeles Central Library; Beverly Hills Public Library; Biblioteca del Pueblo de Lincoln Heights; California State Federation; and Lincoln Park Recreation Center, among others.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1c5ddc7626751e2c6aa900faaaa48af8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Premiere of <title>Themes from Goya</title> at Wilshire Ebell Theatre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955-10-23/1955-10-23">1955 October 23</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_45841d8c094d52b46d5f56a1d59b2ea8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_34f6af3a8d76ae08a1403c7f8fd4c6c2" parent="aspace_45841d8c094d52b46d5f56a1d59b2ea8" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c4ab2590b47a67685b8213cfc44abc8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes programs, flyers, press clippings, and a script.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_29644576518032481176c82fd79d1bd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Solo dances at Turnabout Theatre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955-11/1955-12" type="inclusive">1955 November-December</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_08af78cd3fc38f4c1265ef7aa82b92a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_79e9d53809cfc16ed9502dd24e491512" parent="aspace_08af78cd3fc38f4c1265ef7aa82b92a2" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_535196d0c0b3dc428451d99c24f12b9a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes flyers, programs and clippings from the <title>Los Angeles Times</title> related to Inesita's performance of three dances, <title>Andaluza Sentimental</title>, <title>Zapateado de Estampio</title>, and <title>Maria Salome</title>.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6834a7a5abac84ee464f203ae77d1d12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1969" type="inclusive">1955-1969</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_e1143aed41ebd5079fec96af347e448e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_2e99c42f9d4b85950f74b609ad0d5ecc" parent="aspace_e1143aed41ebd5079fec96af347e448e" type="folder">5-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc5a78907ca6bc74ab382d067d1b0180"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes mostly clippings from the <title>Los Angeles Times</title> with both reviews and advertisements of Inesita's shows in Southern California. Clippings from student newspapers, such as the University of California, Los Angeles' (UCLA) <title>Daily Bruin</title>, are also included.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3919a0eb700515c3b320f0bf163ee04d" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Themes from Goya</title> performances at UCLA</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_130d73401da1e4b9adf9c2cf216ce603" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_72f54181676541fd931cd14545651312" parent="aspace_130d73401da1e4b9adf9c2cf216ce603" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_76129200fa70a64b1e4c4b4b3433b3f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes programs, postcards, and Inesita's handwritten program notes from two presentations of <title>Themes from Goya</title> at UCLA's Royce Hall on July 19 and November 8, 1957.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_549d3bf04e7e5a14c39556dd63d4fd73" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from <title>Themes from Goya</title> performance at Ivar Theatre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">circa 1958</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_d455e3539075dabc7c0ca9cb98c16ed7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_31114e6cfc8d7007bf71d24f667da044" parent="aspace_d455e3539075dabc7c0ca9cb98c16ed7" type="folder">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ebfb7799b87c4ec5e037f4a5b3b6b4a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Performances at K-12 schools, colleges, and universities</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1988" type="inclusive">1957-1988, bulk 1963-1979</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_d95fa13031e8bbf7811f69af1119e3da" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_34f94e94c46d9388ee88bff3f166c63f" parent="aspace_d95fa13031e8bbf7811f69af1119e3da" type="folder">1-7</container><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_d68c5b5d44523f576811017e1042b121" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_593c73a8b7ed84ffdf31c75c9846c024"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily letters to Inesita or to Bob Dworkin on her behalf regarding both performances and workshops in K-12 schools, colleges, and universities across Southern California. Contracts, flyers, letters, press clippings, and photographs are also included. Some recurrent institutions include UCLA, UC Santa Barbara, UC Riverside, Oral Education Center of Southern California, Inc., Los Angeles Unified School District, Pomona College, Head Start Programs, Claremont Graduate University, Area 7 Alternative School, El Camino College, Office of Los Angeles County Superintendent of Schools, California Institute of Technology, Santa Monica College, and more. This also includes videos of performances at 75th Street School, Head Start Programs, and California State College captured in four VHSes, one 1/2 inch videotape, and one U-matic. Two 1/4 inch audiotapes of Inesita performing in 1965 at Caltech and in 1966 at San Fernando Valley State College are also included.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_e627adcbcc7818982b5e3e9eae251799"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_9cb9256685482b95ff24af67d34fbec3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from solo concert at Contemporary Dance Theatre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958-10-12/1958-10-14" type="inclusive">1958 October 12-14</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_2bb2b3c2697f8d071e4066b8e5752373" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_1fb1eb7385b3dd262400a6150d6b3ae8" parent="aspace_2bb2b3c2697f8d071e4066b8e5752373" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_342c46a55c06cd388c5bd215ab94f982" level="file"><did><unittitle>Performance at Inner City Cultural Center</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968-02-18/1968-02-18">1968 February 18</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_f1fdf56530b7c12f88785c10263b58cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4fc78dcda690a9e2e5ccc9f54e3e6343" parent="aspace_f1fdf56530b7c12f88785c10263b58cc" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b94ba5c3b75165d847b31f22d8a433c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes postcards, programs, flyers, press releases, and clippings.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3f516850d3172eb03977279255206644" level="file"><did><unittitle>Performance at Circle Star Theatre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969-02-17/1969-02-17">1969 February 17</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_474d0b9febe8584498e400c2afd0888b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c0a2be8f87cd91f116dc16c9236d7818" parent="aspace_474d0b9febe8584498e400c2afd0888b" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1fe21eda8f7815a910b56ae1205f704"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes postcards, programs, a contract, clippings, and letters between Bob Dworkin and representatives from the theater.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b9cb90ad240f82494e120843a64a8e32" level="file"><did><unittitle>Premiere of dances to Domenico Scarlatti's sonatas at Wilshire Ebell Theatre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970-05-17/1970-05-17">1970 May 15</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_b159e302f9b1d876c047e306ccb4001c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_32fda63babe1d6ca580df5a4c3be54ca" parent="aspace_b159e302f9b1d876c047e306ccb4001c" type="folder">9-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4905f3a50d6071ed2a12ce56765e4a87"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes programs, flyers, letters of praise to Inesita, handwritten notes, and newspaper clippings.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8f9cecf1c567a0c5d599ef50096211b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Video of performance at La Rosa</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001-11-10/2001-11-10">2001 November 10</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_70683c28a6c1779f01e3a20e604dd151" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_28847d2f47a6d5f7e30d5a7c6c24fbb3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes one VHS with the label "Inesita Performance at La Rosa, Sat 10th Nov 2001, Tape #1."</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_8a0eacc57d284fb467959433e55b1299"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_d476db25c8c2ac2852ec824636347a4e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harpsichord Center Artist Concert Series concerts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001/2008" type="inclusive">2001-2008</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_17a979cdec526cc51ebe046705d22b6c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_9e9b3d6e8f9497df80b64d0213450d8a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_de62240127d47919a029153e9338f502" parent="aspace_9e9b3d6e8f9497df80b64d0213450d8a" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_005574441ad0b9fdc5c948076cc1bb0e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes programs for various concerts from 2001 and 2008; as well as three VHSes from May 2001.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_3ba7bdebc43e13864736f6103fee0d98"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c2ce796c0ec923ec71fa3fc132fa351" level="file"><did><unittitle>Flamenco shows presented by Alhambra Performing Arts Center </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2009/2017" type="inclusive">2009-2017</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_9445e0fbb205200ea55cd562ea1b82bb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_4fff63d29b43a893494382a498509359" parent="aspace_9445e0fbb205200ea55cd562ea1b82bb" type="folder">3</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_deb24049671539f2db198e9548e6f0b3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_11938caed14e49d7763120b402735b04" parent="aspace_deb24049671539f2db198e9548e6f0b3" type="folder">7</container><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_21419a72b0960c0ce689bb8d000632c2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_f34140bc54994c22aff01d53fb47a082" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_78cbd7466812b3142bd793addc5846c1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes photographs, flyers, programs, and press clippings of Inesita's flamenco shows presented by Alhambra Performing Arts Center (APAC). Inesita wrote on the back of each photograph with more details and information about the image. In addition, there are four DVDs with 14.2 GB (4 digital files) of video footage from 2009, 2010, and 2012; as well as one CD with 104 images (.jpg) of a performance in 2013.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_4d4bf57572a2e9892328a1fd1ff8069e"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_31b4747db1b133f630ebd987cf8b5816" level="file"><did><unittitle>Program and flyer from shows presented by Piano Forte Productions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2010/2011" type="inclusive">2010-2011</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_6c5f2fb87b7d62004765316dfe817d02" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_8bbaf1370a6e9245c86fc902bf0221e5" parent="aspace_6c5f2fb87b7d62004765316dfe817d02" type="folder">9</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_25ac14cdc9969b33919354345b13aea2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from shows at Havana Club Restaurant and Bar</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2014/2018" type="inclusive">2014-2018</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_cf2e0ee4e4463d0d367818ca8ff5c8e4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_3d55ddad7352ef62d113a5a7c76b5579" parent="aspace_cf2e0ee4e4463d0d367818ca8ff5c8e4" type="folder">10</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c29ada647227427884e5ff3b71ad6a00" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Materials from shows and engagements in other U.S. states</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/2012" type="inclusive">1945-2012</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ab9de6f26baa98344c1f2cf67a1750a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is comprised of letters, contracts, programs, flyers, small posters, press clippings, photographs, and other ephemera related to Inesita's shows, tours, and <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title> lecture-demonstrations throughout the United States. This includes one 1/4 inch audiotape recording of a lecture-demonstration at Springfield College in Springfield, Massachusetts; one VHS of performances in Las Vegas, Nevada; and one DVD of footage from a film about flamenco by New York University film students.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_ed8ae7f76127988d4b170034e2a6d6a9"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><phystech id="aspace_81380e9bb643b9deb04246eeead06cf7"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><c02 id="aspace_cdb59c14ef954109399d540114d55972" level="file"><did><unittitle>First show in New York City at the Havana-Madrid nightclub</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_55ec475a90cde476996b2699d7434e70" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_418d4070d7f590d97a1b15fbd737cb30" parent="aspace_55ec475a90cde476996b2699d7434e70" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab82cd4910511c8ffe77c035b4437012"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes programs, an autographed photograph and a letter from the comedian, Jerry Lewis (who was also in the production), and a letter from Inesita's friend and dancer, Nitza.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_469a35983f26754071ad2a1d437d0c08" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from shows in Seattle, Washington and Kansas City, Missouri</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1954" type="inclusive">1945, 1954</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_18792b9f8d2e212c6ca0102b07861726" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_065e433db71c786fd5391b09d56d716f" parent="aspace_18792b9f8d2e212c6ca0102b07861726" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f4695c34a854da15c68c0ce598131b2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes programs from Inesita's concert revue at the Metropolitan Theatre in Seattle (circa 1945); and a production of Georges Bizet's opera, <title>Carmen</title>, at the Starlight Theater in Kansas City (1954).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fe5bde94726e28ad065440a946913d14" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1955" type="bulk">1953-1955</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_98d49d71bc51c84f5e5e662e37f1191b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_b4b20a1d5e8d173abc5f2a9de99ed752" parent="aspace_98d49d71bc51c84f5e5e662e37f1191b" type="folder">1-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8a467f2a596e71f4ec6f09a68f6707f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes photographs, schedules, newspaper and magazine clippings, letters, contracts, press releases, programs, and flyers related to Inesita's performances in New York City. She performed at the Kaufmann Concert Hall at the 92nd Street Y, Asia Society and Museum, Isidor Straus Theatre of the Educational Alliance, and Nathaniel Macon Junior High School (J.H.S. 258), Central Needle Trades High School (presently High School of Fashion Industries), and the Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a1ed04746911d2e50c2c6256178027ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Inesita in New York City</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1963" type="inclusive">1954-1962</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_0f6333ab83a7b52758ccb5660e02ab06" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_c059b9cf62e6e183d088c7614e619ac5" parent="aspace_0f6333ab83a7b52758ccb5660e02ab06" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67bc71b9f8b4f076c65072219eda2c18"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes black-and-white photographs (8 x 10 inches) of Inesita either posing in costume or performing.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_09d6d1f5cf94c134d3e759d9433b34fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from performances at Jacob's Pillow Dance Festival </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1962" type="inclusive">1954, 1962</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_35c03952338fcee6d4b40da1d72261d7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_bac65e97d26dc4913b8b3a56da5280fa" parent="aspace_35c03952338fcee6d4b40da1d72261d7" type="folder">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_83469b4fa11fa0f1234a33b282874c05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer tour with Pryor-Menz</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955-02/1955-07" type="inclusive">1955 February-July</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_bd8e2ed69b34dac11428e6a308765361" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_5688eaa39861c75a0ba25da320644d65" parent="aspace_bd8e2ed69b34dac11428e6a308765361" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84ce451bb87aeab6c91833b9bee19542"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains materials from Inesita's five week tour under the auspices of Pryor-Menz Concert Service, which consisted of twenty-three concerts in colleges and universities in Texas, Kansas, Wyoming, Minnesota, and Illinois. Materials include letters to Bob Dworkin from Pryor-Menz about bookings, payment, and publicity. There are also press releases, contracts, letters of praise to Inesita, newspaper clippings, programs, and a detailed itinerary with information about her reservations and performances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_66389f0b8583747418d10d579cc55e87" level="file"><did><unittitle>Virginia Symphony Orchestra performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1963" type="inclusive">1962-1969</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_11549d5a97c70accdafff6c32ce5c7b0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_e877b86f54618c133ac408231f8453e4" parent="aspace_11549d5a97c70accdafff6c32ce5c7b0" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c967854b1797c87bd09a4cb032d3a600"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily correspondence between Bob Dworkin and William Haaker, Musical Director of Virginia Symphony Orchestra, Family Concert Division regarding payment, publicity, and promotion of Inesita's performances in Covington, Virginia; Fairfield, Illinois; Anadarko, Oklahoma; Holdenville, Oklahoma; and Guymon, Oklahoma. Newspaper clippings from these performances, as well as photographs of Inesita and Bob at a social gathering in Covington, are also included.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0db0bc08dd22675395924b5859c610cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York University student film featuring Inesita</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/2012" type="inclusive">1962-1963, 2010-2012</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_8be896470ae748a78932713d4cfc243e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_e7fa261ccf4072e9fc542f3427458604" parent="aspace_8be896470ae748a78932713d4cfc243e" type="folder">5</container><container id="aspace_82af4a998e1a15168f76e1732a242852" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><phystech id="aspace_30b5d813c76dbfdc84988346e3280491"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_448ea2d7717b60d558400b0896ea8ff6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Springfield College performance</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963-01-22/1963-01-22">1963 January 22</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_f0073e839d596d54442a3ae9dce5ac49" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_bd2f7649654177baaf9f222e7edd61b2" parent="aspace_f0073e839d596d54442a3ae9dce5ac49" type="folder">2</container><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_2f4b4bfa1c708d4e1727a42f422aa655" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_59d51d0c9fd8351624d382789ac5c68b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes correspondence, programs, newspaper clippings, and one 1/4 inch audiotape recording from Inesita's lecture-demonstration, <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title>, at Springfield College in Springfield, Massachusetts.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_5d61e8743d239e804feaf1f46c7e36aa"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_441e16ef064be421aef9a86347b0fd76" level="file"><did><unittitle>Video recording of performances and workshops in Las Vegas, Nevada</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2004-01-10/2004-01-10">2004 January 10</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_36c9e99f7c42ee81a7e5e1e7ad177faa" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf6d1c8b19495f80235a42ced9ef7384"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes one VHS with the label "Inesita (6) segments of performances Jan 10, 2004, Community College, Las Vegas, NV, Guest Artist, Fiesta Flamenca Dance Co."</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_210e040e57e9291ae3270afd373ebb0d"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_edf7f7e292afa5be5b1a2fc245456153" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Materials from shows and engagements abroad</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1962" type="inclusive">1940-1962</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_663a4cd9134beb31c74f5b17c041899a">Materials are primarily in English, with some materials in Spanish and French.</langmaterial></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6269858189e753ef3e27873bb74d099"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is comprised of letters, contracts, programs, flyers, broadsides, press clippings, photographs, and other ephemera related to Inesita's performances in Malta, Spain, England, and France.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_df940977570d5d7e8e58316dd6ebc7a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mexico City performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940-06/1956-02-14" type="inclusive">1940 June, 1956 February 14</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_bf985b44f632ca1296e3d2848cd3122c">Materials are primarily in Spanish, some materials in English.</langmaterial><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_68abffbc7e28d830914a5cb00c6100be" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_6b43fc2a56e28dc3da17b7df4de91981" parent="aspace_68abffbc7e28d830914a5cb00c6100be" type="folder">5-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c2c1525f4b9d6cb398877d8647b1fe71"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials related to Inesita's performances in Mexico City at the Rio Rita Sala de Fiesta in June of 1940 and the Instituto Mexicano Norteamericano de Relaciones Culturales in 1956. This consists of contracts, programs, and clippings. There is also one photograph of the 1956 performance included.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_594c6acd19a9ca8d17bc6f3caaca2324" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs from a show in Managua, Nicaragua</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950-05/1950-05">1950 May</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_145371e9e7eb107a7a6a6668d282138a">Materials are in Spanish.</langmaterial><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_96000b67c83c6bdf85426ffdbea417b7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_9cb7abb1aa84ce2e22623b1a9fda2819" parent="aspace_96000b67c83c6bdf85426ffdbea417b7" type="folder">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_12b0f84e795abe3fdc0af2c38cc2b899" level="file"><did><unittitle>Press clippings about Inesita's performances in Spain</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1959" type="inclusive">1953-1959</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_eea8e46c85eeedc6ae40383db1766cb2">Materials are primarily in Spanish, with some materials in English.</langmaterial><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_900fd4307153e07fe81254c8a2727f55" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_c8fff3611071a43f36c41a8fc4a0ffbc" parent="aspace_900fd4307153e07fe81254c8a2727f55" type="folder">4-5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_60ab2d04aa5a2636a794350c80f7ea9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paris, France performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1962" type="inclusive">1959-1962</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_1b1011855845aeba7846ae0cb4733fa0">Materials are primarily in English, with some materials in French.</langmaterial><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_5662decb4321b3c6f8d17b1bebd38640" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_c56f9e121d5e2f863205620a06c423ee" parent="aspace_5662decb4321b3c6f8d17b1bebd38640" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cfcc93ecfd78b0743444a74df3691d74"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains materials from Inesita's performances in Paris, France, such as correspondence between Bob Dworkin and French cultural agencies regarding potential bookings, programs, posters, newspaper magazine clippings, and press releases. Inesita performed at Le Catalan restaurant and the American Center for Students and Artists (presently the Foundation for Arts Initiatives).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_699664c168ae569a9c35bbae8fd89a05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Inesita performing in Paris, France</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_798550733fccfba755002d328e99166a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_b5b3b4877afa530bcb7b9bfbf3950bc6" parent="aspace_798550733fccfba755002d328e99166a" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e1c98c2fa2f9666ae4702a09c7cea3dd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes black and white photographs (8 x 10 inches) by photographer, Roger Denizon, of Inesita dancing flamenco with Pedro de Linares and Eduardo Martinez on guitar at Le Catalan restaurant. Inesita wrote on the back of some photographs with more details and information about the image.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ca9a8707dcc29a908c49e2c3d86b8776" level="file"><did><unittitle>England performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_fc8689006eb9453d1b27805a2c7c01e4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_728b2e11d4874e77ab8389476295e6cf" parent="aspace_fc8689006eb9453d1b27805a2c7c01e4" type="folder">6-7</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_0ebab3c3df75b8692bf4ea24ef23a789" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_2a375e41ee8001b3c1c8add747b88eb2" parent="aspace_0ebab3c3df75b8692bf4ea24ef23a789" type="folder">1-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_20c01c74750c442f395c88cc8fe724a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials related to Inesita's performances throughout England, such as correspondence between Bob Dworkin and venue directors, programs, newspaper and magazine clippings, press releases, photographs, flyers, scripts, handwritten notes, and other ephemera. While in London, Inesita performed at Morley College, London University, London College of Education Dance, St. Pancras Town Hall (presently Camden Town Hall), and at Victoria Halls for the Imperial Society of Teachers of Dancing. She performed at the Crane Theatre (presently Epstein Theatre) in Liverpool and at Birmingham University.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dbcdabdffdde245876bb29baa6aab4f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Inesita in London, England</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_ad0fc41dee8c28a9fcbfac26db0ed60c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_39af6533737fabaf1911849122fcca9c" parent="aspace_ad0fc41dee8c28a9fcbfac26db0ed60c" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2a1958f79aede660b49b04a0bdadd0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes black and white photographs (8 x 10 inches) of Inesita either posing in costume or performing in London. Also includes one photograph of the Maharajah of Mysore being presented to Inesita as patron of her first concert in England. Inesita wrote on the back of each photograph with more details and information about the image.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b6061ed86b610180a5382b19f6d943e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manoel Theatre in Valletta, Malta performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961-10/1961-10">1961 October</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_4d53eaa8aaf133f2b6f984ed406d6d9e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_e70e92298dbcbe4c573f42824ae91e1f" parent="aspace_4d53eaa8aaf133f2b6f984ed406d6d9e" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a98a58504bf7a432f745727445e9a8e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials related to Inesita's performances at the Manoel Theatre in Valletta, Malta, such as correspondence between Bob Dworkin and Captain Paul Bugeja and others from the Malta Government Tourist Board regarding payment, publicity, and promotion of the engagement. This also includes programs, clippings, and a poster.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1f6a0ccf3a9e4929545307e126894d42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Inesita and her ensemble in Valletta, Malta</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_391217aa83ad3de814e94477d1570cfc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_60064dbbb4e91beb5cc88ef381c6d159" parent="aspace_391217aa83ad3de814e94477d1570cfc" type="folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff23233608f2152fd971bca4ee32f57a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes black and white photographs (8 x 10 inches) captured by the Malta Government Tourist Board of Inesita in Valletta, Malta with her ensemble: guitarist, Paco Torres; pianist, John Vernon; and singer, Juan Martin ("Manolette"). Includes mostly photographs of Inesita in Spanish dance poses (bolero, muiñeira, and flamenco) at the Manoel Theatre, the Palace of the Baron of Marquise Luchona, the Ħal Saflieni Hypogeum, and the Tombs of Malta. Inesita wrote on the back of each photograph with more details and information about the image.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_5b5668b79595502e406db1b46aa1f2c4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 4: Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/2012" type="inclusive">1913-2012</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_b2a7ed8ea9e5ba688d0fe104edeeeffa">Materials are primarily in English, with some materials in Spanish.</langmaterial></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9476a2b6b204745e0e6e92aaccfb7d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is primarily comprised of Inesita's personal correspondence with friends and dance partners throughout the years. This includes a small amount of letters written to Inesita's father, Willy Stahl as well as letters to Inesita from her mother, Minnie Stahl. Greeting cards sent to both Inesita and Bob Dworkin are also included.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_48fa1accd32eb8e8f1ab70b1ea4487d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Early letters to Inesita and her family</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1938" type="inclusive">1913-1939</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_0a57e166fa4ded28fe8925857fff2523" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_cb7133b0d72e0328af3b6f22b2f7fd7c" parent="aspace_0a57e166fa4ded28fe8925857fff2523" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cc54b8ac7b9d201a1a87d3d1000a68de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a letter written in German to Inesita's father, Willy Stahl; two letters to Inesita from her mother, Minnie Stahl; a card celebrating Inesita's nineteenth birthday from Helen; and a postcard from Minnie to Willy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b490f1fa43aa4bd7c1ff41e7422a5fde" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to Inesita from Antonio Triana</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1941" type="inclusive">1940-1941</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_e0d1ee9f5cee9aa45428c2d82aec09d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_d735a4ebc70fcbad4b34ed398f25b459" parent="aspace_e0d1ee9f5cee9aa45428c2d82aec09d6" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4521b000f53d3c55e811af0f9cf95fc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters from Olga J. Rosenthal and Lynden Behymer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1945" type="inclusive">1940-1945</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_c03be8d725b24c558aa9557136e81a2a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_1ff0d495eacdbe519b65b6546aa07e98" parent="aspace_c03be8d725b24c558aa9557136e81a2a" type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_134c07fc20154b7a3a215f47912c0b40" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to Inesita from Oscar Tarriba</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_698c6ecac8db4c778500e7e04a973eb8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_805df376f29adb24eb5ebf49b9f3b876" parent="aspace_698c6ecac8db4c778500e7e04a973eb8" type="folder">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_422771d3c4beea91d1654549780ae890" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to Inesita from Carlos Montoya</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_accc564a5491d312df301d8e506271e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_c09c3c6f3518f11ada6c5f67947e401f" parent="aspace_accc564a5491d312df301d8e506271e0" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d1910b428ccdb2ff0a8d172a467dcb3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes some letters that are written by Montoya's wife, Sally Montoya, on his behalf.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_45e72e410a830d511f2d3160192ea411" level="file"><did><unittitle>Greeting cards to Inesita and Bob Dworkin from friends and fans</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/2006" type="inclusive">1949-2006</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_5768471b859b442e200795ac978ca480" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_ce30768fab79134c24b712837a614d66" parent="aspace_5768471b859b442e200795ac978ca480" type="folder">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d901ab9cfab0d6b9777fb2b6931167ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters between Bob Dworkin and various people</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1986" type="inclusive">1951-1986</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_147f4cb43bb60cbd62dd808b9970d5b1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_1a3972684fb342a917e2c6f9dc4be8b9" parent="aspace_147f4cb43bb60cbd62dd808b9970d5b1" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc7f1c990f4340b587b8f92b36894ba7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily letters from Bob Dworkin to performing arts organizations, newspapers, politicians and others regarding Inesita's show bookings and publicity.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3c023ea962cc359d37dd25c3d46a4bb5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to Inesita from Maruja Martín Mayor</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/2009" type="inclusive">1960-2009</unitdate><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1969" type="bulk">1960-1969</unitdate><langmaterial id="aspace_72d0f716a058f983f36b9d133b73402b">Materials are in Spanish.</langmaterial><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_7e29061bea8fe5d2f3b66a2cc53a9152" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_2086bb23d4f7d492840a688446893d3f" parent="aspace_7e29061bea8fe5d2f3b66a2cc53a9152" type="folder">3-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ff3808cd94773f79e77bc03158d7e69"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letters from Inesita's friend from Madrid, Maruja Martín Mayor, describing her day-to-day, as well as information about Inesita's flamenco costume orders. Enclosures include drawings with Inesita's measurements, lists, invoices, business cards, and photographs. Postcards and greeting cards are also included. Some letters are addressed to Bob Dworkin.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f372b97b21976f702f465bbf3e116714" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters between Inesita and various people</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/2012" type="inclusive">1968-2012</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_b4748451fd4a335618a997c727b40519" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_9b87acdb3bfd6c34f2c3c9c09898a2ea" parent="aspace_b4748451fd4a335618a997c727b40519" type="folder">8-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7523fe8bedbb64b10715b72b268ba90d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes letters by Inesita to friends, dance organizations, universities, newspapers, and others about show bookings, past performances, and her day-to-day activities. Also includes letters from people, such as other musicians and artists, praising Inesita for performances and inquiries about dance classes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_53501c18f3d3c5cfe30e69ad166b52af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Printouts of email between Inesita and various people</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2011" type="inclusive">2007-2011</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_ec75bfe51f4080debd2d03d2048d90be" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_25e5f6a2efd2e1bba8105de067dd8855" parent="aspace_ec75bfe51f4080debd2d03d2048d90be" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1dd7ec4fce8dae4863e50adf0e4b0818"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes email covering different topics, such as praises for performances and details about show bookings. Some emails are reactions to specific content and stories found on Inesita's blog or website. Also includes printouts of photograph attachments.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_fd36a65999d6aae4777a8019e3090a99" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 5: Additional materials</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1923/2018" type="inclusive">1923-2018</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_38bd69560a97ba1a0d35b5d0be0f7bad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes various manuscripts of <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title> lecture-demonstrations, as well as notes and research material related to this piece, which was written by Bob Dworkin. This series also includes a significant amount of photographs of Inesita, as well as some of her own personal keepsakes, which include a press book with newspaper clippings of advertisements and reviews of early flamenco shows; passports and union cards; a Lester Horton Lifetime Achievement Award; and Inesita's first dance dress, sewn by her paternal grandmother. A manuscript of Inesita's autobiography, <title>Inesita: A Dancer's Life</title> is also included in both paper and digital (one CD) formats. </p><p>This series contains audiovisual and digital materials, which includes two VHSes, one labeled as "Inesita: 45 min (enhanced) for Donald to make copies," and the other as "Reel 2 1/23/88"; one unlabeled 1/2 inch videotape; seven unlabeled 1/4 inch audiotapes; two vinyls and one CD of <title>Inesita in Flamenco and Classic Spanish Dances</title>; and two CDs: one of Inesita at the piano accompanying her father on the violin and one of her performing his compositions on piano.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_13fe0042db8a5564a1d1e4f67d9ab2f7"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><phystech id="aspace_e72810873cc2fa6046899bdd45692285"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech><c02 id="aspace_47a74da98e4ef7243bffd35960e9ea00" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal materials</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/2005" type="inclusive">1925-2005</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_e04436c0701baa52e6b8299870b51b2c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_adf3cf9995ba0373def7ee86496c3685" parent="aspace_e04436c0701baa52e6b8299870b51b2c" type="folder">3</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_2d577a1b3e0d579521b38a559d23657d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_504ce9ed5c2abfb2826132080fc2dddf" parent="aspace_2d577a1b3e0d579521b38a559d23657d" type="folder">3-4</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_85f070169b454487970f5c9d0da1337f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_556e1d9b31913799a18f5ace0ac17e32" parent="aspace_85f070169b454487970f5c9d0da1337f" type="folder">8</container><container id="aspace_a8d720637ac7ad3cdebd68a6c9bb59ef" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8abf2bf8c70dce3bfef00de480730507"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes various items kept by Inesita over the years, such as her elementary school diploma, business cards, union cards (Actors' Equity Association, Screen Actors Guild‐American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, American Guild of Musical Artists), brochures, receipts, flyers, programs, clippings, and printouts from web searches. Inesita's first dance dress from 1925, sewn by Aurelia, her paternal grandmother is also included (box 16).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e41335daff597711327846f0b5a56b79" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Inesita</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/2016" type="inclusive">1928-2016</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_acae19e6957309242fa77ba632740b25" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_1839816c43d14b7ad89a2d557ba50d38" parent="aspace_acae19e6957309242fa77ba632740b25" type="folder">1-3</container><container altrender="flat box (13.5d 3h 15.5w)" id="aspace_e04f21ecedd0de00c6ea2e5b2f69ca5a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_577161b9056c364017b9276b4b9418a0" parent="aspace_e04f21ecedd0de00c6ea2e5b2f69ca5a" type="folder">2-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2e7e95bf0f9bb49e02849d064f36a68"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes primarily black and white (10 x 12 and 10.5 x 14 inches, and mounted prints of 12 x 16 inches) photographs of Inesita in various costumes typical of Spanish dances, either posing or dancing alone or with others (her husband Bob Dworkin, artists, celebrities, friends). This includes several photographs from the beginning of Inesita's career in the 1940s. There are also color photographs (3.5 x 5 inches) of her playing the harpsichord. Inesita wrote on the back of each photograph with more information about the image.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0c7d8293d1e29dcb6cade9378fd94ba3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Press book with newspaper clippings of reviews and advertising</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1954" type="inclusive">1939-1954</unitdate><container altrender="flat box (13.5d 3h 15.5w)" id="aspace_d6ece5efa38ee44cc05aa7528d9a1395" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_06c877492271622a87afd1e3c39e3109" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Music and Dance in California and the West</title> book</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_0cd26d4025cf5889202eea0db103c9e5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e24d429465263f7c61267c6b232f6ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes an article written by Inesita, "Flamenco and Castanets."</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bd2e921fa53b290e985783f887a50b49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio recording of Inesita playing the piano with Willy Stahl on the violin</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><persname rules="aacr" source="local">Stahl, Willy</persname></origination><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_7ffbfb790e0b1d7524c84719a0b1cc09" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_cbbb9b34a567f76e922c9db38f7836f0" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_897bdc3db78c605c052160b8030c022c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes one CD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of audio.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_b8d1ae967e7512b49ecb8ff766297bd4"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a68061d14ce16563cfea5e73a0abcf9" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ballet Today</title> and <title>Dance Magazine</title> clippings of reviews</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1962" type="inclusive">1954-1962</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_607f91c28f704f9b63864c57178b7035" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_c2879ccd4449d6a38e6c3733d22ded73" parent="aspace_607f91c28f704f9b63864c57178b7035" type="folder">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6eb39025e03dfe1cc98066a1279d336f" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Inesita in Flamenco and Classic Spanish Dances</title> audio recordings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/2014" type="inclusive">1954, 2014</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_33bc5dc26a9de8af3ae429ae04d184ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container altrender="flat box (13.5d 3h 15.5w)" id="aspace_2bd112a98cecf6f6f5b42cd00334f134" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2e5d10111527a4d5514ed423f2a64ae1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes United States and United Kingdom vinyl record releases (1954), as well as the record jacket for the French release. Also includes one U.S. CD release (2014).</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_1c0691b1ac0f374a46024b8bb8496e0b"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_95ef9c9969975470c113dafa02faf9d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Posters advertising performances</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1957" type="inclusive">1955-1957, 2004</unitdate><container altrender="flat box (13.5d 3h 15.5w)" id="aspace_2ee2189436cf50a8a992e3e91196bc84" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_9cc89fef5815e2afa1390e04467c61e6" parent="aspace_2ee2189436cf50a8a992e3e91196bc84" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ff33e903b16f5df4256fd8548d31f71b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Writings by Inesita</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/2012" type="inclusive">circa 1950s, 1988-2012</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_d90b33da28b38f107b244ea6a9de5a31" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_0cdffbce7bc63ccafd55df6db6103198" parent="aspace_d90b33da28b38f107b244ea6a9de5a31" type="folder">4, 7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a8fe3d54141c980f8d4c05e65b7d3a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes various documents written by Inesita, including a eulogy for her husband, costume lists, program notes, remarks, personal statements, a resumé of performances, and a document titled "A Laboratory Workshop for Education in the Arts and Humanities." Also includes printouts of screen captures of Inesita's text documents in process.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_041e197b98f96e89042134f80a73b1fe" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title> scripts and research materials</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><persname rules="rda" source="local">Dworkin, Bob</persname></origination><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/2001" type="inclusive">1961-2001</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_1bac4e5faf8bba4377e917c5bc025ca4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_cc446f1d7caf427a1dcec27e91a60b26" parent="aspace_1bac4e5faf8bba4377e917c5bc025ca4" type="folder">4-6</container><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_70ce0c2653bf6af7f8f4ad515ff07288" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_3d055f58c8c7737fa6a60229b7c5e101" parent="aspace_70ce0c2653bf6af7f8f4ad515ff07288" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50cc8731c9b7c4d159b393c82ecef353"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes several versions of <title>The Mystery of Flamenco</title>, a lecture-demonstration written by Bob Dworkin and presented by Inesita throughout her performing life. This also includes their research notes, articles, and other research material.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_61264b89c1274bf48ff335827364f2ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio recording of Inesita performing Willy Stahl's compositions on piano</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><persname rules="aacr" source="local">Stahl, Willy</persname></origination><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994-12-31/1994-12-31">1994 December 31</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_d1543a3323ed70cbfbfacd6bb3c9e0ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_0aa5f78be07746393ca9b15f0bf1feb3" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2947e0218d84ca144e155a7b0248638b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes one CD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of audio.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_be8edbdbb5978e9f248144399a1311cd"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_e75fa31ad98b3ba768bd913d9a288c5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photograph album of Inesita at her home and studio</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><persname role="pht" rules="rda" source="local">Shapiro, Katie</persname></origination><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2000/2000">2000</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_a3f248bddaeb46388b9445f93436a739" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_242c434838a855b7f12b6d9adf77bb63" parent="aspace_a3f248bddaeb46388b9445f93436a739" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_083a5dc94ac8f305a6a40666190d7901"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes both black and white and color prints of Inesita posing in her flamenco costume.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_96f78fa28f415e26f5d33451354f59d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Video of Inesita in her studio dancing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2003/2003">2003</unitdate><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_817d3eecfcd619277797f113e5d78f12" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_eb3da89c6b1240af9376332fe6c7e038" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_44f1806922a4c1a1f289f21c9225c886"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes one DVD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of video.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_482fc5afb4113198b3f917b970ab0eb0"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_823e9f4c534f9a94d86edbc940309ea3" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Inesita: A Dancer's Life</title> manuscript</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2005/2005">circa 2005</unitdate><container altrender="legal-size document box (15.5d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_1d9ccf229c951458c6b3f62c45e08f89" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_2dc1c19da902a5d4a8d109e6bd33b3c6" parent="aspace_1d9ccf229c951458c6b3f62c45e08f89" type="folder">1-2</container><container id="aspace_23a6037a83d795f3307960020a4c5a49" label="Digital Materials" type="Laptop">Reading Room laptop</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b1a232c6b964048acc9d69d593c171e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes both digital and hard copies of Inesita's autobiography, <title>Inesita: Dancer's Life</title>. The latter contains rough drafts with editors' marks. Chapters of this book are blog posts on Inesita's website, https://flamenco-inesita.com/ (last accessed July 26, 2019). Includes one CD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of text (.pdf).</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_436397e1e869ad02321ea89619b413c3"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS PROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment will be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_0ed501d2326cb9b63888f49ae49281ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lester Horton Lifetime Achievement Award</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2010/2010">2010</unitdate><container altrender="flat box (13d 4h 10.5w)" id="aspace_9b85a328acbab80bbf6c53b532b46660" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_06748039afbe7d4c8f60cc16a16879fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a glass trophy and a program with the names of all honorees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1bcb0e03238a6dcd94641386e18c0e61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unlabeled audio recordings, undated</unittitle><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_90245f6b3f06bbb8ed1563ad765779ab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2733449e60275a14c39dbe66a5ffac0d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes seven unlabeled 1/4 inch audiotapes.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_d3f65a890719a41f461d700c8913ebae"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02><c02 id="aspace_dddbb7fc17a2215bd7322da94ad4c023" level="file"><did><unittitle>Two video recordings, undated</unittitle><container altrender="record carton (16d 10.5h 13w)" id="aspace_6370c9a9c845f92766e6706572d3d686" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9a6b81c04f14c9c280bc8ea54bd26bf8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two VHSes, one labeled as "Inesita: 45 min (enhanced) for Donald to make copies," and the other as "Reel 2 1/23/88." Also includes one unlabeled 1/2 inch videotape.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_e8040f241a3420929ddf9a97df21dba3"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p></phystech></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
