<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC">land2316.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Landes Manufacturing Co. Portfolios</titleproper><titleproper>Finding aid for the Landes Manufacturing Co. Portfolios <num>LSC.2316</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Kelly Besser, 2021.	</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2021 January 11.	</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-01-11 11:34:26 -0800</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.

</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Landes Manufacturing Co. portfolios</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.2316</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(5 flat boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1985" type="inclusive">1953-1985, bulk 1953-1976</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1976" type="bulk">1953-1976</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a12943f998c76de5b4e1162c110815ea">The Landes Manufacturing Co., established in 1953, was known for its for experimental outdoor furniture designs and technical innovations. The collection consists of five portfolios containing black and white and color images documenting furniture designs produced by the Landes Manufacturing Co.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_3a94f9c0290f6eb0effcef52f5471a6a">Stored off-site at SRLF. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance through out electronic paging system using the "Request items" button.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b978ebdec3fcd4e9b01486e63c7726d1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance through our electronic paging system using the "Request items" button.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_6144a053c6e41ea9be1c125714083a59">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UCLA Library Special Collections. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0acac1e42cbf3b851aeeba03a9d7f9d3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Landes Manufacturing Co. portfolios (Collection 2316). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_339cac111fe2cc975fca5ba713f4556b">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Josephine Lauria Fargo, 2016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_62cd4cb9d4d25d624b6f0d05a46d4229">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Siri Luk, under the supervision of Julie Graham, March 15, 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_c9d1b667fe378bc6e3061d31c1af5a3f">
    <head>General</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://catalog.library.ucla.edu/vwebv/holdingsInfo?bibId=8168263">8168263</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8dbcb242f0464d1b4c6eb162904c1af5">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>The Landes Manufacturing Co. was founded in 1953, in Gardena, California by Harvey Leipzig, Fred Sabl, and Martin R. Liebhold. Within a short time, Liebhold became the sole owner of Landes and oversaw the company until it was divided into the textiles department and the metal furniture division. Among the Landes designers were Jerry Johnson, Byron H. Botker, Paul Tuttle, and Heinz Meier. The company aspired to produce well-designed, high-styled, practical, and comfortable furniture at reasonable prices, and was known for its for experimental designs, technical innovations, and use of new materials. Design innovations included the use of canvas slings in seating pieces to replace drawers, springs and strapping; over-stuffed cushions filled with shredded foam; knock-down fabric drawers that could be shipped flat in boxes and assembled by the buyer; and a design line of weatherproof outdoor furniture made from PVC. The company was sold in 1986.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_24c05b97133734409622af9eeb6a07fc">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The collection consists of five portfolios representing furniture manufactured by the Landes Manufacturing Co. Included are 293 black and white and color images of assorted furniture creations. Additionally there are a small number of what appears to be Landes catalog covers and photographs of seven unidentified male individuals. The furniture pieces include tables, chairs, sofas, bedroom furniture, shelving units, and outdoor furniture, among other pieces. Furniture represents designs by Byron Botker, Elsie Crawford, Jerry Johnson, and Heinz Meier, among others.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Furniture designers -- California -- Archives.</subject>
    <corpname source="local">Landes Manufacturing Co.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref5_gja" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landes Designs and Designers (Book 1)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1982" type="inclusive">(1953-1961, 1963-1965, 1982)</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_837b46ca32fa901a4dabfb9a09bece5c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0071af96049b3f867bc1a48ed62237ff"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>66 black and white and color photographs of tables and chairs for both dining and lounging, stools, wire racks and holders, headboards, shelving units, tea carts, port-a-bar, TV trays, and outdoor furnishings. Additionally there is a printed advertisement for the Montecito Unit. Designs represented are for the Balboa group, Delmar group, Memories group, Westwood group, Brentwood set, and Sausalito set. Designers represented include Jerry Johnson and staff designers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref7_za5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landes Designs and Designers (Book 2)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1972" type="inclusive">(1961-1965, 1967-1972)</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_058c2c1c8d2f4a73a8e0c337d6428c34" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c87f3218db0ea456ceefd6065211e957"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>63 black and white and color photographs of tables and chairs for both dining and lounging, sofas, and outdoor furnishing. Additionally there is what appears to be a Landes Manufacturing Co. catalog cover. Designs represented are for the Acapulco group, Carmel group, Coronado group, Encino group, Idyllwild group, La Costa group, Miramar group, Ramona group, Redondo group, Santa Barbara group, and Sonora group among others.  Designers represented include Byron Botker, Jerry Johnson, David Tompkins, and Lewis Van Der Beken.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref9_7ow" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landes Designs and Designers (Book 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1980" type="inclusive">(1972-1976, 1979-1980)</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_6bfc9a278fb2208cdec2a4a1f1fd9763" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4b8abbfb07f5417a3eeded154a74b460"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>62 black and white and color photographs of tables and chairs for both dining and lounging, bedroom sets, a desk, and outdoor furnishings. Additionally there is what appears to be a Landes catalog cover. Designs represented are for the Blocks, the Ascona collection, Malibu collection, Tahoe collection, Belmont group, Bolinas group, Gambria group, L.A. group, Maricopa group, Orinda group, Pacifica group, Tiburon group, Tioga group, Ventura group, and Westlake group. Some pieces appear to utilize steel tubing and ABS plumbing pipe. Designers represente include   Charles Anacker, Byron Botker, Elsie Crawford, Jerry Johnson, Heinz Meier, Paul Tuttle, and Lewis Van Der Beken.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref11_sif" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landes Designs and Designers (Book 4)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1981" type="inclusive">1974-1981</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_a2f7195f092b312c7f71f205a55cb3c0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d615f58871354ffb590fa2264a9f795"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>62 black and white and color photographs of tables and chairs for both dining and lounging, sofas, desks, shelving units, storage cubes and drawers, wardrobes, bedroom sets for mostly children, and outdoor furnishing.  Designs represented are for the Fontana group, Mendocino group, Menlo group, Napa group, Northridge group, Paso Robles group, Sausalito group, Seating group, Toltec group, Verdugo group, Westridge group, Portola collection, and Solana collection. Some pieces appear to utilize steel tubing. Designers represented are Rudolph Bofinger, Byron Botker, David Cornn, Elsie Crawford, Charles Gibilterra, Jerry Johnson, Dan McCue (McFarland Designs), Kimo Martin, Heinz Meier, and staff.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_9sq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landes Designs and Designers (Book 5)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1985" type="inclusive">1981-1985</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_32576e2a537a71a9c124683580c6b852" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5a4b6e8e81e2981b598038ae6555e91a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>40 black and white and color photographs of tables and chairs for dining and lounging, headboards and beds including some designs for children, wardrobes, shelving units, and outdoor furnishings. There are also a catalog cover and photographs of seven unidentified male individuals.  Designs represented are for the  Butterfly chair, Palomar chair, Saratoga circus baby furniture, and an adaptation of the Breuer chair; the Alondra group, Brentwood group, Claremont group, Newport group, Westwood group, Mojave Collection, and San Francisco Collection. Some pieces appear to utilize steel tubing. Designers represented include Charles Anacker, Byron Botker, Chong Chiu, Jerry Johnson, Krister Olmon, and Lewis Van Der Beken.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
