<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c87945w1/">linc9472.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Lincoln (Abraham) photographs from the collection of Frederick H. Meserve, New York</titleproper><titleproper>The photographs of Abraham Lincoln from the collection of Frederick H. Meserve, New York <num>LSC.94/72</num></titleproper><author>Jane Carpenter with assistance from Simon Elliott; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cub&amp;#x00E9;.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>2013</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-07-29 11:17:35 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>The photographs of Abraham Lincoln from the collection of Frederick H. Meserve, New York</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="col" source="ingest">Meserve, Frederick Hill, 1865-1962, collector.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.94/72</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 albums</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(130 photographic prints) : silver gelatin, platinum ; 30 x 25 cm (album)</extent>
<physfacet><lb/>Date from t.p. handwritten in pencil, presentation inscription of June 20, 1942 on t.p. verso, and first letter, dated Jan. 19, 1942, to Ralph A. Gregory in St. Louis from F.H. Meserve in New York City.
<lb/>Added title-page, in typescript, dated 1941: "Photographs of Abraham Lincoln from the Frederick Hill Meserve Collection presented to Ralph Gregory by Frederick Meserve 1941."
<lb/>Photographs are mounted on rectos and versos of 18 double leaves of white paper, with corners of each photograph slipped into slits cut into paper; each photograph numbered in pencil.
<lb/>Bound in looseleaf notebook of faux grain black paper boards with black leather spine.
<lb/>Spec. Coll. copy: in beige cloth clamshell box, with box title "Meserve Abraham Llincoln."</physfacet></physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1942</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_05f6f12a2e57a1c5f27ad4c44c71fc7a" label="Abstract">Looseleaf notebook from 1941-1942 containing a set of 18 double leaves of 129 small photographs of Abraham Lincoln, collected by Frederick Meserve, and presented to his friend, Ralph A. Gregory, who was also a collector of Lincolniana.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_035512028e4f05579d5d84e53de6ded9">Stored off-site at SRLF. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_75b8eb60884412372f8dcf6d516588aa">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_80399043543512b9309d784f36e2ae52">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ed2ab0b8a9bcddc3b5c4a043ce71881e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UCLA Library Special Collections. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cefc863d2c81cd6cd45b6359d83876f4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], The photographs of Abraham Lincoln from the collection of Frederick H. Meserve, New York  prepared for Ralph A. Gregory, a student of American history of Saint Louis, Missouri (Collection 94/72). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_57390eafbc2999e2212798bd63cc6042">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Albert Boni.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_9996f130a17e1d62c44ee83f8864cea9">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9966842243606533">9966842243606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2db51aececbda8072032b96c308956f8">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>New York City businessman, and one of America's premier Lincoln collectors. Frederick Hill Meserve began collecting in 1880, when he set out to find photographs to illustrate the Civil War diary his father was writing. When he bought a packet of photographs at auction for $1.10 that included 100 Mathew Brady salted paper prints, he was hooked. By 1911, he had tracked down and catalogued 100 Lincoln photographs. The photographs document the changes in Lincoln's face over the years, as he struggled with the tragedy of the Civil War and the death of his son. Meserve's Lincolniana is now part of the Meserve-Kunhardt Foundation at SUNY Purchase, directed by Peter W. Kunhardt, Jr., Meserve's great-great grandson.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bc2eca443631bd587ccd07ed2efddd98">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>According to Meserve's letter of Jan. 19, 1942 to Gregory, these photographs of Lincoln originally appeared in Meserve's book, The photographs of Abraham Lincoln (New York: Privately printed, 1911), and represent photographic prints of all known photographs of Lincoln, printed from the original negatives, and from copies of daguerreotypes and photographs. The single 8x10 platinum print of Meserve is by Lawrence B. Lockwood of Cleveland, Ohio. Also included in the notebook are 11 letters written by Meserve to Gregory, documenting the course of their friendship from July 24, 1940 to March 14, 1959; 5 p. of notes on photographs #117-130, and A-B; and 1 printed "contact sheet" of 108 small photographs, with title "Meserve's enumeration of Abraham Lincoln's original photographs," and notes below of name of photographer and place of sitting of each photo.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b8afdaa1ecff7fffb27de721c86c8c5e">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Part of the 
<extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6489s0cc/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Photograph Album Collection (Collection 94)
</extref> in UCLA Library Special Collections.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <processinfo id="aspace_27daea9a9c547a81818ec51269a4d7ba">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="lcnaf">Photographs of Abraham Lincoln from the Frederick Hill Meserve Collection presented to Ralph Gregory by Frederick Meserve 1941</function>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photograph albums</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photographic prints.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Platinum prints.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Silver gelatin prints.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Portrait photographs.</genreform>
    <persname source="ingest">Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 --Photographs.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Lockwood, Lawrence B., photographer.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Meserve, Frederick Hill, 1865-1962 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Meserve, Frederick Hill, 1865-1962 --Photographs.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Boni, Albert, 1892-1981, former owner.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Gregory, Ralph A., former owner.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Gregory, Ralph A.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
