<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt229032h5/">mo170198.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Morgan (Sydney) commonplace Books</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Sydney Morgan Commonplace Books <num>LSC.170/198</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Manushag Powell, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, July 2004; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2009</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address><p>Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2q81b7n">LSC's Metadata Rights Statement</extref> for more information.</p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-07 14:14:07 -0800</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Sydney Morgan Commonplace Books</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Morgan, Lady (Sydney)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.170/198</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 items</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1800/1810" type="inclusive">1800-1810</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_708e664fc3253f0d733c1f549fbec77e" label="Abstract">Three volumes of commonplace books by Sidney Owenson (aka Sydney Owenson, later known as Lady Morgan). The volumes were filled during the prolific first decade of her writing career.</abstract>
    <physdesc id="aspace_0112ddd8d62cd8136a446682eb5596b4" label="Physical Description">3 v. (132, 73 with 5 loose papers enclosed, 50 leaves) : paper ; 195 x 170 mm. Binding: Marbled paper-covered boards, red tape reinforcement on spines.</physdesc>
    <physloc id="aspace_e7be38800def44f856c22b7d38ed75cc" label="Physical location">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_856bac98337814d6c6eca45e83cc2f0a">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4792acfa3c7eb9597da27f4da9bfa67e">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_18d84e7dbc1f6ff1ee018572795fe188">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <odd id="aspace_857f96cb13b455bc17aa57da1a18695d">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942304033606533">9942304033606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9b7b2d3bdd3efa94abf7d5663cd6b3bb">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Sydney Morgan Commonplace Books (Collection 170/198). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2b4ba07a23531de7ecdd24e2dcbff65d">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Manushag Powell, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee in the Center For Primary Research and Training (CFPRT), July 2004.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's library collections and archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_80313f1a1255a122c88314ab61923d06">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Lady Morgan, born Sydney Owenson (ca. December 25, 1776-April 16, 1859) was a highly successful though somewhat controversial Anglo-Irish Romantic writer, whose works include historical romances, drama, poetry, travel narrative, history, biography and critical essays. Owenson was distinguished by her ability to use historical romances to critique Anglo-Irish relations and the perils of careless and avaricious imperialism while reviving ethnic pride in Irish culture. The daughter of celebrated Irish actor and nationalist, Robert Owenson, and a Shropshire woman named Jane Hill, Owenson was raised in Dublin. She received a gentlewoman's education and was an avid autodidact as well. After her mother died and her father suffered a series of financial difficulties, Owenson went to work as a governess, and later as a writer, to help support herself and her family.</p><p>These volumes of extracts span roughly the first decade of her writing career. Her first work, <title>Poems</title>, Dedicated by Permission to the Countess of Moira, was published in 1801 and her first novel, <title>St. Clair</title>, or, the <title>Heiress of Desmond</title> (ca. 1803) came shortly thereafter; from then on she ceased governessing altogether in favor of writing. Owenson became one of the early creators of the carefully-researched historical fiction / historical romance genre which made Walter Scott famous. Her work, however, is more nationalistic than Scott's. Although some of her novels, such as <title>The Novice of Saint Dominick</title> (1807) and <title>The Missionary</title> (1811) do not address Ireland directly, she worked throughout her career to correct English prejudices about the history, behavior, and character of the Irish. She accomplished this most successfully in her third novel, <title>The Wild Irish Girl</title> (1806). The heroine, Glorvina, was so wildly popular as to make Celtic accessories fashionable in women's dress. In addition to nine novels, Owenson published essays, drama, a collection of Irish songs, a biography of the painter Salvatore Rosa, historical works (most notably <title>Woman and Her Master</title> [1840], a feminist approach to history), and the well-received travel narratives <title>France</title> (1817) and <title>Italy</title> (1821).</p><p>Owenson became Lady Morgan in 1812 when she married Sir Thomas Charles Morgan, who had been knighted in 1811. Though the match seems to have been successful, a condition of their marriage, an unusual one for the time, was the keeping of separate finances. This measure was due in part to Owenson's life-long preference for independence, and her continued success as a professional writer.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d30a68cee4ab53e4083c596377ae79a1">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>This set of commonplace books consists of three independent volumes given separate titles by the author. Each volume contains an index or table of contents. Based on the dates found in the text, they would have been compiled largely while the author was living in Ireland, though Volume II seems to have accompanied the author to London. Collectively, the volumes include quotations, biographical notes, literary extracts, letters, and original commentary and narrative works.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_05051238df7d72815b23245a27679ded">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>The volumes are as follows: <list type="simple"><item>Volume I: Extracts from Various Works (circa 1800-1801?)</item><item>Volume II: Extracts and Reflections from 1800 (1800-?)</item><item>Volume III: Extraits Francoises Compilês par Sidney Owenson (circa 1800?).</item></list></p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_37ba1881e5bbea5266d8490737007d64">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt538nb916">Bound Manuscripts Collection (Collection 170) </extref>. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref13_s9l" level="item"><did><unittitle>Volume I: Extracts from various works</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa 1800-1801?</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0afc19f73924aa95c41aa3698b410bd" label="Mixed Materials" type="volume">I</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6af577728d9c60f0fb2c164d51d9291"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Volume I is dated 1810, but it contains manuscript versions of works published in 1801 and earlier material. Volume I begins with an index of sixty-four authors, in no obvious order, whose works are represented in the volume. They range from classical to contemporary writers. Owenson includes several quotations from Confucius (credited as such in the copy), although she does not list him in her table of authors.</p><p>The volume is divided by four subheadings: Poetic Extracts, Prosaic Extracts, Miscelanies [sic], and Original Poetry by Sidney Owenson, although it is important to note that these categories do not accurately describe all of the content within the sections (i.e., prose appears in the poetic extracts and vice-versa).</p><p>Of particular interest are two elements found near the end of the volume. The first is the section titled "Original Poetry by Sidney Owenson" (though it contains misc. matter besides her poetry), which includes manuscript versions of poems such as "Will 'o the Wisp," "Sonnet to Hope," "To Myself," "To My Muse," "Chloe and Cupid" (in pencil, and barely legible), "Stanzas" ("When shall I be at rest"), and "The Post Boy (waiting for a letter from my father)," which were published in her first work, the 1801 Poems. The manuscript versions differ substantially from their finished incarnations, and many show evidence of composition: strike-throughs, words replaced, etc. The poems are preceded by a list of 42 "Poems by Sydney Owenson," somewhat re-ordered and with many strike-throughs. Many of the titles here are recognizable as versions of the poems included in her 1801 volume.</p><p>The other matter of interest is her self-explanatory "List of books I'm anxious to procure," which includes, among others, Johnson's Lives of the Poets, "Petrarch - Tasso - Metastasio," Lorenzo de Medici, Burke's Sublime and Beautiful, "Lives of Peter the Great, Frederic the Great," and James Harris's Hermes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_ty2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Extracts and reflections</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1800, 1800-?</unitdate><container id="aspace_b38b2dc35901b7d71f20fdb7a03fdc85" label="Mixed Materials" type="volume">II</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2f4ea5aa16024f663fd63822cd4da98"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Volume II is dated 1805 in two places, but the dates seem to have been partially erased. This imprecision as to dates may be related to Owenson's well-known efforts to obscure her real age. If Owenson was in London when she commenced filling this volume, which the contents support, that would confirm a real date of 1805 (when she traveled to England to publish her second novel, The Novice of Saint Dominick).</p><p>Volume II begins with a short list of authors that seems to be a continuation of the list in Volume I. Volume II contains occasional comments from the author on her reading, initialed S:O. It also holds copies of a few letters, such as one sent to London on the twelth of September documenting her sister Olivia's health. There is also a rough pencil sketch of an angelic nun menaced by some sort of devil, with the note, "the Castle Spectre humbly dedicated to wise Olivia who sat for the picture of that and the witch of Endor," and the postscript, "I am a spectre."</p><p>There is a second "List of books I'm anxious to procure," this one including, among others, Smith's Theory of Moral Sentiments, William Smellie's Philosophy of Natural History, Thomas Leland's History of Ireland, and Petrarch's Life. There is also a manuscript version of Owenson's poem, "To Fancy," which was published in her Lay of an Irish Harp (1807). As with the manuscript versions of her 1801 poems, there are substantial differences between this and its final version. There are five loose pages of notes and partial correspondence tucked into the volume.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_mk5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Extraits Francoises compilês par Sidney Owenson</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa 1800?</unitdate><container id="aspace_17b490d0ded71edcd9266609baa4b63a" label="Mixed Materials" type="volume">III</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0848d50dec401e07b053339d0b67a263"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Volume III is dated 1800, although the dates 1829-30 can be read on the following page. The text is in French. Volume II has a table of contents in Owenson's hand listing authors' names (2r), beginning with Mademoiselle de Scuderie [sic], and including Scudery, Racine, Boileau-Despréaux, Phillipe Quinault, La Fontaine, Molière, and Voltaire. The entries themselves are generally short biographies for each author, although there are occasional literary extracts as well.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
