<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf638nb37c/">monro777.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Monroe (Agib S.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Agib Stewart Monroe Papers <num>LSC.0777</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Manuscripts Division staff; machine-readable finding aid created by Alight Tsai and Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2002.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-07 15:17:56 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Agib Stewart Monroe papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.0777</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.0 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(4 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1959" type="inclusive">circa 1913-1959</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7bb927b97e0a3b9e833622a866a971a7" label="Abstract">Agib Stewart Monroe (1886-1959) was a surveyor with the California State Highway Commission (1913), an assistant city engineer in San Diego after World War I, a consulting engineer in the office of attorney Arthur M. Ellis (1922-32), and from 1932-55, had his own office in Los Angeles. The collection consists of correspondence, court transcripts, legal notes, notebooks, stock certificates, maps, blueprints, books, and ephemera.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_da171c07c85bb9cd32ee187826501852">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f6951ab234a5f040847fa253db52f39a">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_45a038919a0245efea0f307c08b9b035">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d6dc1e185346754ff929150bfc9bf5de">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5c879043d4c1dd8f9bf38f229db6b40b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Agib Stewart Monroe Papers (Collection 777). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_198f3f06abac9afde16b4a612bc2029d">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Mrs. A. Stewart Monroe, 1961.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_77ebf630b25df0798d8a9306f4df798e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Manuscripts Division staff.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_7df089590e60008e8a8f2a0118ec6e28">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9942334473606533">9942334473606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8dc39d97284bd55a317427908a276e03">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Monroe was born on January 16, 1886 in Pennsylvania; with no formal training except by correspondence school courses, he became a civil engineer; came to California in 1907; became a surveyor with the State Highway Commission in 1913; served as assistant city engineer in San Diego after World War I; consulting engineer in the office of attorney Arthur M. Ellis (1922-32), and from 1932-55, had his own office in Los Angeles; he died September 22, 1959 in San Marino, California.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0dc96e2dbec0bd52428f68c7fc86f429">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection consists of correspondence, court transcripts, legal notes, notebooks, stock certificates, maps, blueprints, books, and ephemera. Includes papers relating to the Investigation Act of 1931.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Consulting engineers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.</occupation>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Civil engineers -- California, Southern -- Archives.</occupation>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Monroe, Agib Stewart -- Archives</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_1a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence, Sanitation District's Forms, Standard Plans Book of the California Highway Commission, Book of uses and definitions of legal terms, copy of the application of the City of Monterey Park (California) to the State Advisory Board for Federal Emergency Funds for a sewer, and notebook.</unittitle><container id="aspace_a9f5853e98a590ca149c9f1ca71a2f4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref12_ziu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Books relating to charters of various cities, amendments, ordinances, specifications of road construction, and other important statutes.</unittitle><container id="aspace_6a6a80ee5dde58d67d5d06960b02d565" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_q29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stock certificates, maps, blueprints, papers relating to the Investigation Act of 1931, and pictures, ephemera.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1931 and v.d.</unitdate><container id="aspace_944179cdf8600821573a2ea8d60c7f8c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref14_d5o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal notes, court transcripts, and paper bound books.</unittitle><container id="aspace_b5c18da3abd330361793986b0d80d320" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
