<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8g44r19/">nati1944.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">National Lesbian Feminist Organization Records</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the National Lesbian Feminist Organization Records <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1978/1979" era="ce">1978-1979</date> <num>LSC.1944</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Molly S. Jacobs, 2011; Jessica Tai, 2016.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 19 September 2017.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-16 13:30:11 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>National Lesbian Feminist Organization Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">National Lesbian Feminist Organization (U.S.) </corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.1944</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 document box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4771564c4545462455118c9b56aea1d8" label="Abstract">The National Lesbian Feminist Organization (NLFO) was founded in 1978 as a grassroots organization in order to "act on a feminist platform which deals with the oppression of lesbians in all its manifestations,including but not limited to discrimination based on sexual preference, sex, race, age, class, and physical disability". As a grassroots organization concerned with accountability, the NLFO committed itself to fighting racism and classism both inside and outside the organization. Membership was open to all lesbians and women identified women whose beliefs aligned with the organization's mission. This collection contains an organizational history, founding convention notes, correspondence, ad hoc and steering committee memos, financial statements, and newsletters. The papers also contain information on local and state chapters, resources, and lesbian rights marches. Highlighted are behind the scenes efforts to organize local chapters, the formation of the Lesbians of Color Caucus and statements, and disagreements over the credibility of "representative organizations."</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_9b6c6568f56346db7004e9f8e3b1d15e">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f3c8c55209b7f8cfd21f0accc2cd7392">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_37dbb6aa019b06e147a8e163573e614f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_36db902cd6c7d569091560c829c63465">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c6ef82bc3612a6157ef58bc0ef9aeff6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], National Lesbian Feminist Organization Records (Collection 1944). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1b08a432feb0cf66c28b78afcee99e44">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition </head>
<p>Provenance unknown. This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_24ea4b821f53a92a0676a6ea0f17b960">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Molly S. Jacobs, 2011.
Description enhanced and further physical processing completed by Jessica Tai in 2016.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_e6380797584c996237a5b2218ead2149">
    <head>General Note</head>
<p>The <extref xlink:href="http://digital2.library.ucla.edu/mazer/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive</extref> at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the <extref xlink:href="http://digital2.library.ucla.edu/mazer/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives</extref>, the <extref xlink:href="http://www.csw.ucla.edu/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW)</extref> and the <extref xlink:href="http://www.library.ucla.edu/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">UCLA Library</extref>. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_2c0cddda3adb3cdda3206f03fa62bf9f">
    <head>General</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9969540863606533">9969540863606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_19aec15874ca3de8209a0db9c50e7ab1">
    <head>History</head>
<p>According to their literature, the National Lesbian Feminist Organization (NLFO) was founded in 1978 as a grassroots organization in order to "act on a feminist platform which deals with the oppression of lesbians in all its manifestations,including but not limited to discrimination based on sexual preference, sex, race, age, class, and physical disability. There is a need to achieve equal rights and legal protections for all lesbians...a need for developing lesbian culture." An Ad Hoc Committee formed in Los Angeles and took on the responsibility for the planning of the national convention to be held in July of 1978. A nationally based steering committee was selected at the convention, whose responsibility was to guide the organization through the first crucial months.</p><p>As a grassroots organization concerned with accountability, the NLFO committed itself to fighting racism and classism both inside and outside the organization. The group called for a "minimum of 50% of all the women involved in the level of planning and decision making to be women of color of various backgrounds and 50% of all white women of various class backgrounds." Membership was open to all lesbians and women identified women whose beliefs aligned with the organization's mission. The structure of the NLFO consisted of local memberships known as the "locals," whose representatives were sent to state and national conventions. The Los Angeles chapter was named the Alice Paul Chapter.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_71fe59936f560be13e0558a5c4cb8365">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The National Lesbian Feminist Organization Records contains organizational documents, including meeting minutes, financial statements, and documents relating to the founding convention, and information on the Women of Color Caucus. It also contains correspondence and newsletters.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_da23b6da69c00712a5b04bb8ae4645f5">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>Materials in this collection are arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">National human rights institutions -- Archives.</subject>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">National Lesbian Feminist Organization (U.S.)  -- Archives</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_uhc" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO History</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_40cfa184bd2fc534735dc19358f7cd93" label="General Physical Description note">press release (no date); newspaper article (1978 April-May); organizational documents</physdesc><container id="aspace_102cf978a3b8f70c4182ccdde7e041c5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7516b688bac633658178fd80809d5936" parent="aspace_102cf978a3b8f70c4182ccdde7e041c5" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_252d6a3d3b1dd09f068b1dbe7fdb9e47"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains background and scope of collection from Mazer Archives (undated); press release reporting on founding convention written by Mary Spottswood Pou (1978); three page article from an unknown source reporting on founding convention; information sheet on NLFO; and resolutions from the founding convention.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref14_blp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ad Hoc Committee Meeting Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ca498d7312c3bd2ffb56c7e23fc07ec9" label="General Physical Description note">meeting minutes; organization structure outline</physdesc><container id="aspace_07735e08a66d6715b1ad73cd70935d80" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c8c622a937706e1d8c3dd062c5f7379c" parent="aspace_07735e08a66d6715b1ad73cd70935d80" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3bbcae4fe5c9b9de8b6d7aff25c8f69e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains minutes from four meetings of the Ad Hoc Committee totaling 38 pages; notes from "Workshop 3"; mandate from the Southern region delegate, Linda J Lorell; count of number of women of color in the delegation; motions and agenda items with vote tallies by region; proposal for a national steering committee; list of topics to be considered at the state conference.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_6yk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Written Record of Founding Convention</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e737199d70f6a2a7640be0d3871922b5" label="General Physical Description note">organizational documents; member lists</physdesc><container id="aspace_411f5bc6438842764b7ae9edc4b0b046" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3fb4b1bf17f2ffad8b495bb4d7401cfb" parent="aspace_411f5bc6438842764b7ae9edc4b0b046" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6dfc39d1dda91cb5007552e560384fce"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Written record of the proceedings from the founding convention, including: rules of the convention; agenda; accountability; dues; founding; local exemption; membership; name; purpose; steering committee; structure; transexuals; wimin of color. Also contains delegate list (7 pages); mailing list (6 pages); registered observers; list of press, staff, and miscelaneous observers; national delegates; and an unofficial written record of motions and resolutions (20 pages).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref20_mnh" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO Founding Convention Packet</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978 March 17-20</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6a37224494e8768536a2f852d9bf35e1" label="General Physical Description note">information packet; convention pass</physdesc><container id="aspace_aa57b8d112de045dd41674fbb2c33f24" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5fef3560567e28be6b19a16db2f3e2ab" parent="aspace_aa57b8d112de045dd41674fbb2c33f24" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11303c723c9c1febb1e58a9de54d0768"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains local information, including maps and guide to local businesses and emergency contacts; agenda; convention rules; and a convention pass for Kerry Lobel.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref23_zma" level="file"><did><unittitle>Founding Convention Responses</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_43a7d131bb1869ae6c575e43c07168cf" label="General Physical Description note">letters; attendee list; convention report</physdesc><container id="aspace_ceb0bb5e77b6ac4267e6519857564a37" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d2dd495c38994f6b306bedb72ca65095" parent="aspace_ceb0bb5e77b6ac4267e6519857564a37" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb6aac24384a7c1e41302170fae50834"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains letters to the Ad Hoc Committee in response to the founding convention; "incomplete list" of Jewish lesbians at the convention; report from the convention with handwritten notes updating progress on proposed actions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref26_zcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lesbians of Color Caucus</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c29b8e287ab4778ed08c7f2dbee56ca5" label="General Physical Description note">press releases; letters; caucus report</physdesc><container id="aspace_868fd6a110a09b586b8daee52022bf39" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7c830e8c1646787f868a06153e9d6905" parent="aspace_868fd6a110a09b586b8daee52022bf39" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fdf0e1b3339c076925a4cd760aef98f4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains Lesbians of Color Caucus Statement; Lesbian Latina Alliance Statement; Affirmative Action Committee Report from Houston (1978 July); Affirmative Action Committee correspondence; mini biographies of Yolanda Retter and Carmen Vazquez.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref29_bld" level="file"><did><unittitle>Feedback on Organization Restructuring</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_d9c93cafc7911a444dce88af354fdb69" label="General Physical Description note">letters</physdesc><container id="aspace_301dbb275b17241ec1b780dd2f0a3658" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_b6984205dc562a98f315b2c950755bbf" parent="aspace_301dbb275b17241ec1b780dd2f0a3658" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35e86f7c41dc8e7d728b86a6ae995dbc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>In the NLFO Newsletter, number 2, a restructuring of the NLFO was proposed and members were asked to provide feedback through a survey included in the publication. This folder contains three responses (no date).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref32_tov" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_eeda3d014dc618c921d4d5c9435ae4e0" label="General Physical Description note">letters</physdesc><container id="aspace_af68593510ce67c04018f972a3c6e4dc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_117010a78c23aff4e87801c22db3e8f6" parent="aspace_af68593510ce67c04018f972a3c6e4dc" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fba2b37ddd836a5b94c087c1ce88864f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains letters written to the NLFO, primarily requesting information about the organization, and letters from NLFO to members. Also contains one article from an unaffiliated publication, The Wishing Well, requesting information on placing an advertisement in the NLFO News.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref35_ci6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence with Rosalie Nichols</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e7c21d0b15cb55bdebfc28f26d8e8b50" label="General Physical Description note">letters; news editorials</physdesc><container id="aspace_f2ed44dc6f5c1bf4bc7dc99ab51d7cf1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f3c9b71d1b9482188e3dc316e51179cf" parent="aspace_f2ed44dc6f5c1bf4bc7dc99ab51d7cf1" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e4ddcc4717013b27210f2fa5f75f97f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains a letter submitted to the NLFO News (1979 April) and Off Our Backs (1979 May) by Rosalie Nichols (aka "Teleli") disputing the openness and acceptance of the NLFO and a response by Jeanne Cordova, NLFO News co-editor, directly to Nichols (no date) and to the NLFO Steering Committee (1979 May 11). Also contains several letters written to "Off Our Backs" and Nichols following the letter's publication.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref38_fdu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Steering Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_1878ea9de05dc30ba3c4d665af406878" label="General Physical Description note">meeting minutes; memoranda; committee reports</physdesc><container id="aspace_0d530ce388b490f66396afabfce40f60" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_8083a05f8b735ddc90477da9bcf29003" parent="aspace_0d530ce388b490f66396afabfce40f60" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9b145d9db41f5363c8b49e259ba04cc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains minutes and memos from March 1978 convention; minutes from Denver meeting (1978 May 27-29), Washington D.C. meeting (1978 July 9), and Knoxville meeting (1978 July 15); list of steering committee members (1978 June); affirmative action committee report (1978 July 19); and Minnesota Convention planning documents (1978 July 1978)</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref41_341" level="file"><did><unittitle>Steering Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4d4d0fafbfa745c02fec299e1cdf1bf9" label="General Physical Description note">memoranda; letters; letterhead</physdesc><container id="aspace_a60b884f204d83f4c449c8d67cbe5039" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e2311ef6f09739824842114a3c27b40c" parent="aspace_a60b884f204d83f4c449c8d67cbe5039" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7047a52312ac1e40307aac1588b230cb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains memo regarding grievance hearing procedures; letters requesting more wimmin of color for the Steering Committee from the Affirmative Action Committee; memos pertaining to the newsletter and appointment of a scribe; and memos regarding fundraising and working with other organizations. Also contains press release letterhead.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref44_jmc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fundraising Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9ab068fa9d6dcab64ccf55968d0f1567" label="General Physical Description note">reports; flyer</physdesc><container id="aspace_51dc7ea8451e4c43b78ab22cbd5d8bcb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_fcf01e8efd5285e98c24f7067824b271" parent="aspace_51dc7ea8451e4c43b78ab22cbd5d8bcb" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b942c7cec56986b106a527e27eb90f63"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains fundraising reports (1978 March - May) and an expense report (1978 May 10), a request for donations (no date), and a flyer for a fundraiser titled the "1st Annual Anita Bryant Barbeque" held in Los Angeles (1978 April 30).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref47_6fs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Statements</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_1c9d6dd339482224e16f97e80a874102" label="General Physical Description note">financial reports; checks; accounting book</physdesc><container id="aspace_88614f18b5d4803bed1a38b9931681fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_27c7269253f719b242d7b4e3026c03e5" parent="aspace_88614f18b5d4803bed1a38b9931681fd" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a2f79fd75ae0f2d7e557c4eb08328dc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains four financial reports (1978 May 30; 1978 July 1978; 1979 May 6; 1979 July 15); an accounting book (partially filled); two blank checks for the NLFO News; one NLFO expenditure report (1978 July 18); and one revenue report (1978 July 18).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref50_2i9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mailing Lists</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">circa 1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_746dbb0b9012086fbae0d939c8a89217" label="General Physical Description note">mailing labels; member and delegate lists</physdesc><container id="aspace_6078eab2efc3658d62cf8b259ff15e33" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_b15cf6572210b74500eb73eb312d0c0d" parent="aspace_6078eab2efc3658d62cf8b259ff15e33" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d598e020d854de8e88557ec7d0db2ef3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains mailing labels (11 pages); new member mailing list; list of southern regional delegates (with names, addresses, age, and race/ethnicity); and Great Lakes Region addresses and telephone numbers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref53_auq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chapters and Affiliated Organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1977-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_42c49d3b89fcdd8452b7a3dd8245becd" label="General Physical Description note">memoranda; press releases; reports; correspondence; flyers</physdesc><container id="aspace_91c3dd4dd4669d3d5fde1166d620c2dc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f462d891cabf5426b363795c9d569098" parent="aspace_91c3dd4dd4669d3d5fde1166d620c2dc" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9842599cd181d152a1df8fc5eca70876"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains guidelines for state conferences; press release on the formation of a Southeastern Regional Conference; reports and letters from local chapters, including Iowa City (1978 June 16), Madison (1978 July 6), Milwaukee (1979 January 8), and Baton Rouge (1979 February 20); a Milwaukee member mailing list; a Madison member mailing list; a Colorado Springs mailing list; a report from the Wisconsin NLFO statewide conference (held 1978 Novement 10-12); and several letters from individuals interested in forming local chapters. Also contains correspondence from other organizations, including Women's Community Center in Eau Claire, WI and the Lesbian Resource Center in Elmira, NY; responses from NLFO representatives to organizations and individuals; a proposed structure for a planning meeting in San Jose for a proposed California Lesbian Feminist Federation (1978 February 18-20); information about the Lesberadas, a lesbian-feminist organization, and the Lesbian-Feminist Organizing Committe (LFOC). Includes minutes of a general membership meeting of LFOC (1977 August 14) and a flyer for an LFOC event, as well as correspondence between NLFO and SLPAC, a Michigan-based organization (1979).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref56_hwz" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO Newsletter Drafts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a3fde3b8a7ab252d5cbd8140ff654714" label="General Physical Description note">newsletter drafts</physdesc><container id="aspace_29dcf71e1201913cc14c4daaf38d8f0c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_bfa082a00d35ef59e14a94894e106910" parent="aspace_29dcf71e1201913cc14c4daaf38d8f0c" type="folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_673bc0f880735c6ee9ea0f9d2cacd2db"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The first publication of the National Lesbian Feminist Organization, originally titled "NLFO." This folder contains original drafts of NLFO articles and letters. The content includes a report on the founding convention, steering committee updates, letters to the editor, updates from lesbians of color, a report from the Eastern Regional Lesbian Conference (held 1978 April 1-2), request for assistance from the Tri-City National Defense Fund, updates from local chapters, and an issues forum.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref59_825" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO News Original Drafts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_76567b038694d1a44df66f22a2b6f51f" label="General Physical Description note">newsletter drafts; letters</physdesc><container id="aspace_6fb3e4067ccb6ec7e0656685a20c4fc5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0ea781bab803e9f4de9058f375220849" parent="aspace_6fb3e4067ccb6ec7e0656685a20c4fc5" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ec6af7eeadd05e1689e83393edf9b5e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The NFLO News was the official publication of NFLO and was published in Los Angeles. This folder contains original drafts of articles and letters to be published in the newsletter, including a letter from the NLFO News staff; updates from local chapters, including Milwaukee, Madison, Stevens Point, Green Bay, Tucson, Baton Rouge, Alice Paul (the chapter in Los Angeles), Denver, and Colorado Springs; letters to NFLO News; Lesbians of Color outreach; information on the National Gay Rights March in Washington, D.C. (to be held 1979 October 14); information from the Steering Committee; letters regarding Rosalie Nichols's editorial printed in "Off Our Backs." Also includes letter and member roster from Baton Rouge, a letter requesting information from Wisconsin-based NFLO chapters, and an editorial coordinating sheet for the first issue (1979 April-May).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref62_wtl" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO Newsletter Subscriptions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_22db151641aec3101ff316505bd03f9f" label="General Physical Description note">letters; newspaper clippings</physdesc><container id="aspace_3043c09de64cdc8cd576c012ca8941c4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5cca2f6bfa1ca9429b050aa254d2a6c5" parent="aspace_3043c09de64cdc8cd576c012ca8941c4" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_243cc8b6fa0c16fea73aa964b22f3e40"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains letters from individuals and organizations requesting subscriptions to the NLFO's newsletter, "It's About Time." The folder also contains requests for newsletter exchanges from other organizations and a list of newsletters NLFO exchanged with and a list of newsletter distributors. Also contains a pamphlet from the Naiad Press, Inc. listing their publications.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref65_s0h" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO News Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_5912a56aa61e1fcba6a66dc08af6a353" label="General Physical Description note">letters</physdesc><container id="aspace_91bf9b095132222d1b8f24ab85bfbe4b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7e0d5a017e66a3168ab37f22ab0196d4" parent="aspace_91bf9b095132222d1b8f24ab85bfbe4b" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f9eff2ff97c7fa98d7bdcd3934c3f87c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains correspondence to and from the NLFO News, the NLFO's second publication. Letters include requests for subscriptions, contributions, change of address requests, and letters between members of NFLO News staff.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref68_c7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>NFLO News Memos</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4f55bac60f5589a56a01685d8ff7b5da" label="General Physical Description note">memoranda; meeting minutes</physdesc><container id="aspace_f3ff4d254631f216e316c3c7ede0f817" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c68bf788ac2a9a74d0ce1e0b02f768d4" parent="aspace_f3ff4d254631f216e316c3c7ede0f817" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f33a6ccdedbb41a282b7035c0ac256a4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains memos to NFLO News Staff; NFLO News Staff Minutes; and memos from NFLO News Staff to other committees, including the finance committee.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref71_0w6" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO News Budgets</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_77a74e9b11a50fcbd21a8ea26c5e21ee" label="General Physical Description note">memoranda; financial reports</physdesc><container id="aspace_382a0d641700774d8db69fea23932968" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5e8848858ce0829d6913604762178fd1" parent="aspace_382a0d641700774d8db69fea23932968" type="folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3f375a128e307b720f6bd0a5c66e7794"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains a memoranda outlining expenses (1979 May 17), a financial report from the NLFO News to the NLFO Treasurer (1979 June/July), and expenditures from the first issue of NLFO News (1979 April 21).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref74_xrn" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLFO Publications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1979</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_633f2ed81d9dd61ee10eb42663c3590f" label="General Physical Description note">organization publications</physdesc><container id="aspace_2781f21192f2c51759d224dc70ca70cd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6ed40980e1ec5c47cff09a760985eca2" parent="aspace_2781f21192f2c51759d224dc70ca70cd" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_36bc2e9893de76d21a05e51386dcab8e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains original issue of NLFO no. 2, D.C. March (undated); NLFO News no. 3 (1979 April/May), no. 4 (1979 June/July), no. 5 (1979 September/October), no. 6 (1979 October/November); and the Wisconsin NLFO Networker volume 1, no. 1 (1979 February).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref77_w1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal for Gay Rights March on Washington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2c047ab9152d61c31c18605584214139" label="General Physical Description note">committee letters; questionaire</physdesc><container id="aspace_c4d49f052b747158ca687949630a2106" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_09079be969ad8bb621fc251730bfc0ec" parent="aspace_c4d49f052b747158ca687949630a2106" type="folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a60a3dade6efff37ef71cdf64451f016"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains a letter from the Committee for the March on Washington presenting the idea for the march with a proposed date of May 6, 1979, which includes a completed questionaire suggesting ideas (1978).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref80_ev8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ephemera, Press releases, and flyers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1979" type="inclusive">circa 1970's</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ac5a3b1a2e9a52e6506a6f20a8e8f207" label="General Physical Description note">photos, comics, letterhead, stickers, directory, newsletters</physdesc><container id="aspace_7ed9f47e49a1c91b9875859f35385b9b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1755941f83729f9ce5ac57c881b7f396" parent="aspace_7ed9f47e49a1c91b9875859f35385b9b" type="folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cb5975c181c201e052940f1d3d9c1986"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains bumper stickers; several comics, some hand drawn, others from newspapers (most have Anita Bryant as the subject); request form to join NLFO; NLFO letterhead; directory of women's periodicals, labeled 'presslist'; newsletters and flyers from other organizations, including National Organization for Women, Tribe, Tri-City National Defense Fund, Seabrook Safe Energy Walk, and Mobilizer; and two photos.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
