<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8cc12s7/">nati2202.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">National Lesbian Conference records</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the National Lesbian Conference records, <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1989/1991" era="ce">1989-1991</date> <num>LSC.2202</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Stacy Wood, 2013; Sabrina Ponce, 2017; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 4 December 2017.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-16 12:29:07 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>National Lesbian Conference records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">National Lesbian Conference (1991 : Atlanta, Ga.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.2202</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1991" type="inclusive">1989-1991</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b17ad4e530618e962661b17964c7b72d" label="Abstract">The National Lesbian Conference was the first and only of its kind, attempting to set a national lesbian activist agenda. The event took place in Atlanta, Georgia in 1991 and drew over 2,500 registered attendees. The gathering was comprised of one full day of caucuses, five plenaries, four mornings of anti-oppression training and slightly fewer than three hundred workshops. This collection contains pre-planning materials as well as a conference program and news coverage of the conference.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_4431f974b27e9d38bd64f39bb6dcc5c1">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8aa015fd4667f8b12c9d58ca41b8e88e">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_80221521a811f76ca44992ef42e1caa9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_312ab21587cabeae69f7f7e8f25c32d0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_573b5cc25bcae8aa392cf14f92344075">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], National Lesbian Conference Records (Collection 2202). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8ef8ca9c66e1aee45a66c396b3b6f3ac">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Provenance unknown. </p><p>This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the 
<extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://mazerlesbianarchives.org/">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives</extref>, the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.csw.ucla.edu/">UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW)</extref> and the  <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.library.ucla.edu/">UCLA Library</extref>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a720e3268d65b9fd5039a476845e3a83">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Stacy Wood, 2013. Description enhanced and further physical processing completed by Sabrina Ponce in 2017.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_bff7717ce9f3771cc68a1fef78542dfc">
    <head>Sponsor</head>
<p>The <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://digital2.library.ucla.edu/mazer/">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive</extref> at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://mazerlesbianarchives.org/">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives</extref>, the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.csw.ucla.edu/">UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW)</extref> and the  <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.library.ucla.edu/">UCLA Library</extref>. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_501620eb6b0cc50de9fa4efcc108dd05">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9973847773606533">9973847773606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_868a59e9718d1c23057720c5990d0076">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>The National Lesbian Conference was the first and only of its kind, attempting to set a national lesbian activist agenda. The event took place in Atlanta, Georgia in 1991 and drew over 2,500 registered attendees. The gathering was comprised of one full day of caucuses, five plenaries, four mornings of anti-oppression training and slightly fewer than three hundred workshops. </p><p>The Conference became a concept after the American attendees at an international lesbian conference in 1986 felt that they had no unified voice due to a lack of national lesbian agenda. In 1988, a few American lesbians met in Washington D.C. to plan a national lesbian conference. Subsequently, planning meetings were held in North Carolina, Oregon, and Missouri. Meetings operated by modified consensus. Consensus and parity (defined as 50% lesbians of color, 20% disabled lesbians and 5% old lesbians) were of prime importance. The full steering committee, with over 100 seats to represent many different interest groups, was never fully seated. Although the ostensible goal of the conference was to decide collectively on a national lesbian agenda, the goal remained elusive. The conference became fertile ground for intra-organizational conversations about representation and the political process, but a fair amount of strife and dissent plagued much of the conversation. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0d6fbaf898b12c90c5c8c8edce18b315">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>This collection contains pre-planning materials as well as a conference program and news coverage of The National Lesbian Conference, held at the civic center in Atlanta, Georgia in 1991.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_47d8dc75859998ada715b24d3f616616">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement </head>
<p>Materials arranged by type.</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_a98739990cfe176f9b5ce31c277ecaea">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p><extref xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8z89fjx/" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Old Lesbians Organizing for Change records</extref>. Available at Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States -- Congresses.</subject>
    <corpname source="local">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">National Lesbian Conference (1991 : Atlanta, Ga.) -- Archives</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_25m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pre-planning</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_efc0187e4f58f4adabc6aa922068f616" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0a1489bb482742da8cf859a39f58366b" parent="aspace_efc0187e4f58f4adabc6aa922068f616" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a141847c16d44a334c2743ce3940e6a2"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Documents relating to the preparation for The National Lesbian Conference. This includes flyers for fundraising events, registration documents, volunteer information, press releases, proposed program schedules and drafts of conference materials.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref14_nrt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Old Lesbian Organizing Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1991" type="inclusive">1989-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_0083ad7ae4da90b0a17f318ebb734a8f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d060752b245d630cc91227aef816cfbc" parent="aspace_0083ad7ae4da90b0a17f318ebb734a8f" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0ca84a63b367db2bf44458223cb3dd5"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Documents relating to events and programming concerned with ageism and aging lesbian organizations. This includes newsletters for organizations, correspondence, speech drafts, meeting agendas, flyers, and workshop materials for an anti-ageism workshop.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_e8y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991" type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_67277002d30e3609e75b50a7bc837b58" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d7e7848e444b13f073e262de0d2c5b11" parent="aspace_67277002d30e3609e75b50a7bc837b58" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b8414100b1f44e1cced11e720882160"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Newspaper articles and clippings covering The National Lesbian Conference. Primarily, the articles are from lesbian, feminist, and progressive periodicals like <title render="italic">off our backs</title> and <title render="italic">Frontiers</title> as well as local Atlanta news outlets. The articles discuss the events of the conference, the divisiveness it exposed and the broader lesbian movement.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref20_vjx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference materials</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991" type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_02de15d236430fa5ddeb7a21cad7b79f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ad9cc6695385970e7ba4f935585c4102" parent="aspace_02de15d236430fa5ddeb7a21cad7b79f" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a25e4f6c64415566650c6e2a9e8e341"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Information and materials from participating organizations and groups within The National Lesbian Conference. This includes flyers, brochures and pamphlets, essays, membership information and calendars.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref23_fvn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991" type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_17b3ba4f7a6b93bc4fdadacc2702681c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_40ffbdb47b0da685e176b1d00047874b" parent="aspace_17b3ba4f7a6b93bc4fdadacc2702681c" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9014dd538d2f738a869ad6d32f60e511"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Full program for The National Lesbian Conference.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
