<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8z039bj/">pacif946.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Pacific Electric Railway Company motor coaches and railroad cars photographs</titleproper><titleproper>Photographs of Pacific Electric Railway Company motor coaches and railroad cars, 1927-1950 <num>LSC.94/6</num></titleproper><author>Jane Carpenter with assistance from Simon Elliott; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-16 15:26:54 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English.</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Photographs of Pacific Electric Railway Company motor coaches and railroad cars</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Pacific Electric Railway Company</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.94/6</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 boxes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(875 photographic prints) : b&amp;#x0026;w, 27 x 33 cm or smaller in boxes 29 x 40 cm or smaller.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1950" type="inclusive">1927-1950. Range of dates from dates on photographs and manufacturing specifications.</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8db7fb427e18fbf8546812b8d0a9de4a" label="Abstract">Collection of 875 unmounted photographs (including duplicates) of motor coaches and railroad passenger cars in operation between 1927 and 1950 on routes of the Pacific Electric Railway Company and related bus and train systems of Los Angeles, California, and environs.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_8e4706a50be1bed759a48734b78984bf">Stored off-site at SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_23745c01bcc33323aca1d08058954ba4">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_7a4f3a6b8a7211402ba3a8d60cd8b3ff">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UC Regents. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_41fe620f6c32449976893004932d38a9">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Photographs of Pacific Electric Railway Company motor coaches and railroad cars (Collection 94/6). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4d5657d9ca7ab327f7da8c95aba44156">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_ebd0c06ee79b545a70a940cd0e9d90b4">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9967126583606533">9967126583606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d5d5919fcb49c92ae6b44a5f011eebb6">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The photographs, probably assembled by the Pacific Electric Railway Company public relations department, for use in a pictorial history book of early Southern California transportation, include detailed interior and exterior views of the different models of vehicles in use by the Company, close-up views of some of the bus engines, and shots of the buses and trains carrying passengers on routes throughout the Los Angeles area, in towns such as Glendale, Pasadena, Santa Monica, Torrance, San Pedro, and Riverside. In several of the photographs, a Pacific Electric bus winds its way up Sunset Boulevard past the UCLA campus in its early years--with Royce Hall, Powell Library, and Stone Canyon Reservoir visible in the distance--all the way to the end of the Castellamare line in Pacific Palisades. In other street views, a bus passes Los Angeles High School; Otis Art Institute, at that time housed in the Spanish-Moorish mansion donated in 1918 by Gen. Harrison Gray Otis, founder and publisher of the LA Times; and the lotus-filled lake of Echo Park. Another early photo shows a 1911 coach surrounded by oil wells. Three photos document the Pacific Electric Camp in Agua Fria, east of Highway 89, a vacation camp built in 1917 by the Company for its employees in which they lived in tent houses, and enjoyed the dining room, social hall, swimming pool and other amenities. Close-up views of the display window of a local travel agency reveal brochures and posters for Pacific Electric Company vacation tours. There are also shots of railroad sidings, terminals, machine shops, track maintenance workers, railway personnel, drivers, conductors, porters, and freight checkers, including one photo of a stylishly-dressed woman freight checker. Several photos document hundreds of shipbuilding workers entering and leaving the shipyards in Long Beach. The United States Maritime Commission, which oversaw ship construction had its own private railroad car, the subject of one of the photos. Buses, trains, and trucks of other lines, including the Santa Monica Municipal Bus Line, Pacific Electric Motor Transport Company, the Los Angeles Motor Coach Company, People's Motor Bus Company--known for double-decker buses, Southern Pacific Company, and Los Angeles Railway are also documented. Included with the photographs are typed leaves of specifications of the vehicles, providing model series numbers, body dimensions, paint details, upholstery, engine size, date of manufacture, manufacturer, and many other details. Manufacturers included White Motor Coach Co., Mack Trucks, Inc., GMC, and Yellow Coach Manufacturing Company. Most of the photographs bear the stamp of Arrow Studios of 1053 S. Hill St. in Los Angeles, although other studios, such as Isham-Robinson (1722 Los Angeles St.), Keystone Photo Service, Arts Engraving Co., Inman Company, and Stagg are also represented.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_165eef1327c5d56eb7582adbeef5b0a4">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Part of the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6489s0cc/">Photograph Album Collection (Collection 94) </extref> in UCLA Library Special Collections.</p><p>Additional information available at the website of the Pacific Electric Railway Historical Society at <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.pacificelectric.org/">peryhs.org.</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photographic prints.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Pacific Palisades (Los Angeles, Calif.) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Transportation -- California, Southern -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Transportation -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mechanics (Persons) -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Machine shops -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Oil wells -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Travel agents -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad passenger cars -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Electric railroads -- Cars -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Buses -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Buses -- Design and construction -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bus travel -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bus terminals -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad terminals -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad accidents -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad sidings -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Road rollers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bus drivers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Shipbuilding industry -- Employees -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Shipbuilding industry -- California -- Long Beach -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Trucks -- California -- Los Angeles -- Photographs.</subject>
    <corpname source="ingest">Yellow Coach Manufacturing Company.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">University of California, Los Angeles -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Otis Art Institute.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Pacific Electric Railway Company -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Arrow Studios.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Arts Engraving Co.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">General Motors Corporation.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Inman Company.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Isham-Robinson Photography.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Keystone Photo Service.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Los Angeles High School (Los Angeles, Calif.) --Photographs.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Los Angeles Motor Coach Company --Photographs.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Los Angeles Railway --Photographs.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Mack Trucks, inc.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Pacific Electric Camp -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Pacific Electric Motor Transport Company -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Pacific Electric Railway Company --Employees --Photographs.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">People's Motor Bus Company -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Santa Monica Municipal Bus Lines -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Southern Pacific Company --Photographs.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Stagg Photographer.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">White Motor Coach Co.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
