<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c80v8m12/">phil2386.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Philippine comics collection</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Philippine Comics Collection <num>LSC.2386</num></titleproper><author>Processed by Valerie Vargas; edited and encoded by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2024 October 1.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address><p>Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2q81b7n">LSC's Metadata Rights Statement</extref> for more information. </p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-10-02 16:23:28 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Philippine comics collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.2386</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.0 linear feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="2007/2018" type="inclusive">2007-2018</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_61882c457943e83131b2c445a1c1025a">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f035a3907b710723ff556354eea8d8b2">The comics are predominantly in Tagalog and English. Oftentimes, Taglish, a code-switch between Tagalog and English, is used. Some comics use or incorporate Baybayin, an ancient script used by Tagalog people in the Philippines, in the dialogue or as sound effects.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6d38e3f8443d31e8047aa196e4dd4db7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2e851a92acd961e7e9ae644206e6eed7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1ecba720840a7a071597ee0e703c2bd9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Purchased from a seller based in the Philippines, date of receipt unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_545063f21535ca794dfba84d08a9dfda">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9997031821906533">9997031821906533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f9a8628886b588d4dfd423056cd32121">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Philippine Comics collection (Collection 2386). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_44fef9434475a5b59152c2602d8f6329">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Valerie Vargas under the supervision of Jade Alburo and Jasmine Jones, 2018.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's Library Collections and Archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6abce5a353bccd1c2dbe0d2339208127">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The comics format has been been a popular medium in the Philippines for decades. 
However, Ferdinand Marcos (1917-1989), nationalist president and corrupt dictator, heavily censored all publications. After Marcos was deposed by nonviolent revolution in 1986, independently published comics began to flourish. Like zines, the culture of independently published <emph render="italic">komiks</emph> was reborn in the 2000s due to advances in technology, when creating and sharing them became more widespread.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2294ce0b395d54740a287d8c63e9d248">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Philippine Comics Collection contains comics that showcase the creative minds of Filipino artists in the Philippines. It spans the years of 2001-2018, with the bulk of the materials dating 2011-2017 or are undated. They were created by various artists and are mostly collaborations. Many of the comics are self-published or published by small publishers like Pelikomiks Studio and Azhdarchid Komiks.</p><p>The <emph render="italic">komiks</emph> feature creatures of lore and incorporate Filipino culture into the storytelling. Content often mirrors the daily lives of the artists. Original Filipino superheroes -- often teenagers who find themselves being granted a superpower to save the people of the Philippines from attacks -- are also included. </p><p>
The <emph render="italic">komiks</emph> are printed on glossy-paper, in color, or are scanned and printed in black and white. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_691fda7873058339430d90504584e128">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection has been arranged chronologically by publication date.</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3422c0089d76b8662eedab3fe0c15072">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8zs33rc/">Philippine Zine Collection (Collection 2281).</extref> Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_6a3c529c9166a84bfbc4342f2f5a60f6" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>PINOY TOTOY PI-TOTOY</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012-2013</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee5f783952513ec850914f7e0988320d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Pinoy Totoy is the Captain America of the Philippines, and while he's much smaller and younger, he's doing the best he can at 12 years old. As a fan of superheroes himself, Totoy was not able to hold back the urge to step up to the call of justice when he saw other children in danger! The first issue of this Filipino comic book series was published by Bakal Komiks in 2012.</p><p>Creators: Carlo Valenzuela; Patrick Enrique; Mel Casipit; Amos Villar</p><p>Publisher: Bakal Komiks</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_3be864ef6f1c8aeda5614259f068799c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 1</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_65db3a370dbaee76fb275b55f898b44a">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_07492d76a7d1de058bfa24a46d54186b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 2</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_15286b51bf7be31f6ebe7876e1a44569">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d667d29e12a01dbb36d2285bb732445f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 3</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0839c664cb03e67b62c80f3341c5d86e">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_e41e0d764258c102c2026bf75252ebbb" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Alamat Ni Manila Man</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014 April</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a2ffeee17c96b696fb042ed01561eae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Alamat ni Manila Man</title> (The Legend of Manila Man) is a Taglish comic book series published in Manila, Philippines. The self-styled vigilante, Manila Man, is a mysterious urban superhero and defender. The story begins when Kendi, a recently promoted investigative journalist, connects her predecessor's recent murder to this vigilante.</p><p>Creators: Mike Ignacio; RH Quilantang</p><p>Publisher: Frances Luna III</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ade3186feb9934d2b83427fbf428717a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Chapter 1: <title>Bahagharing Itim</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014 April 03</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a070bc604ac5e918fe97f8c83bb2045d">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_46bfbb180dc320bf0f6d742bedcb94e3" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Bokunawa</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f56e64c59da300a5f04baf09d17b6b22"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Bokunawa</title> is a Philippine manga written in Tagalog that references Bakunawa, a sea serpent from Philippine mythology that swallowed the moon, to show a fictional fate of the Philippines under global warming, extreme drought, and extremely long days due to the sun not setting. People depend on scavengers, or pilots, who operate giant walking robots, to find water—a scarce resource because the land is drying up and the temperature is relentlessly rising.</p><p>Creators: Raphael Cezar Casanova;  Ruth Hanzessa F. Rodriguez; Freya Dy</p><p>Publisher: Dr. RaCe's Publishing House</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c998850f3051be74b6823bf69929742" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Bruho Barbero The Barbarian</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011-2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_36428308851535e1c53df045d10f6509">3 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_210702fcc4ceb62a2b874b7aada2f58d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Bruho Barbero</title> is a Tagalog comic series that follows Bruno Barbaro, the strongest undefeated barbarian on the planet, as he transitions into living his life as Bruho Barbero, a mild-mannered barber, tired of fighting and violence. In each chapter, Bruho's attempt at a peaceful life is disturbed by warriors who want to be the first to defeat him. The first three issues of this series was published in 2011-2013 by Mengo Jam Cartoons in the Philippines.</p><p>Creator: Rommel J. Estanislao</p><p>Publisher: Mengo Jam Cartoons</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_86adf2a803c7e410eb509efc73be77a8" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Bruho Barbero The Barberian</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011 November 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c02c1a3c3bd90b508a4aee2f78728383" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Bruho Barbero The Barberian: Bururus</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012 October 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2cb847ea123993ffd3818571a55a3aaf" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Bruho Barbero The Barberian: Man's Tender Trap</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013 November 16</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_6113dd08122dd552429e2f9bc1aaa7f5" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>CAUTION: DRUGS/SEX/ROCKn'ROLL</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013 February</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3fb8561f405f5881443e3afd78a9940b">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd6ade3d04929e7ec2fa8cd5925a5cfa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>CAUTION: DRUGS/SEX/ROCKn'ROLL</title> is a Tagalog comic book by Patrick "Rawwrr" Enrique that was published by Chain Mason in Manila, Philippines. In this comic book, an <emph render="italic">aswang</emph> (shape-shifting demon) made a binding life/death contract that gave a man who almost committed suicide a more lavish life. Enrique incorporated supernatural elements and used it as a creative and engaging way to shine a light on heavier topics such as suicide and drug addiction.</p><p>Creator: Patrick  Enrique</p><p>Publisher: Chain Mason</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9fddc9ee4e28f7af3223a4ce07fd5b77" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Si Heronimo alyas… HERO, Ang Bagong Bayani ng Marikina</title> </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2010-2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_da1d9cea223261cbea8af2150fa1cc6a">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d40b3dc1196e82ec51eef73557329170"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Si Heronimo alyas… HERO, Ang Bagong Bayani ng Marikina</title> is a comic series created by Rommel "Omeng" Estanislao. It is about Heronimo, a vigilante hero who can't wait for the government to act on the crimes in Marikina, a city in the middle of Quezon, Pasig, and Rizal, and took up the alias HERO to save the community from crimes. HERO dons a lucha mask and uses unconventional weapons like yoyos, slingshots, and bottle caps as <emph render="italic">shuriken</emph> as he faces criminals like the Janitor Fish-Man and Chinese hit men.</p><p>Creator: Rommel J. Estanislao</p><p>Publisher: Pocket-Size Indie Comics</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_133d091685a5c082f165be3b05e4ee49" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Si Heronimo Alyas... HERO, Ang Bagong Bayani ng Marikina 3: Attack of The Janitor Fish- Man</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013 April 12</unitdate></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4d61a3343566443388ecfe0d67865a2f" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Si Heronimo Alyas… HERO, Ang Bagong Bayani ng Marikina: Bugbugan Na!</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2010</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c93ee6a59c17e6b8e2b4e5830810f63a" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Labandero X</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013 December</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0852de8565230558e8c8ed145e69f2f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Labandero X</title> is a Tagalog comic created by Luigi Jocson or "Lui421," and published by Circle 421 in 2013. In this silly comic, our superhero Labandero X, uses cleaning products when attacking villains who aim to pollute the world.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e3d35471aee429d0f4f6be4e1981cba2" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Liga ni Likeman</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66bfe58dd786e854e9609baa1e817661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Likeman Komiks</title>, also known as <title>Liga ni Likeman</title> is a semi-autobiographical webcomic by Rasel Reyes that has been featured on the Philippine Daily Inquirer's entertainment section. <title>Liga ni Likeman </title>stars a social network addict cum super hero, Likeman. Likeman's companions are fellow netizens (internet citizens), including his mother, Lady Geegee, a YouTube sensation; Gamer Girl, his love interest; Ogie, his best friend who is as smart as a search engine; and Boy Inlab and Perly, a love duo who constantly fight on the internet.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_85e8749700ad9835c0b1a8d2f5efd245" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Liga ni Likeman: Meet the Netizens</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_c4f1b1460d3d59be829d17044ecc7e5d">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_32ac62bfbc69728b146a0eeb061b6320" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Liga ni Likeman: Issue 1.1</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_293de5585c6ec507cebada0d8baf3bda">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_6cfce5f7e8647ca19e5924581bfbc18f" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Love Riot</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011 November</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d578ba3385adc88cc72bd0c9fa52179f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a comic book about Joey, a young boy who transferred to a new high school to curb his tendency to get into fights. However, he can't seem to escape violence as he runs into more trouble by fighting with a girl in his class. Eventually, he finds himself fighting alongside her as she battles her enemies.</p><p>Creators: Cyrus Romanes; Frances John Haro; Edgar Torres Jr.</p><p>Publisher: FHATE Comics</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_94be872555d68469456df8848365d11a" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Love Riot: Chapter 1</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_d2289bd9d0d7285acccac63bd9ac9fc2">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ae33453b0ae43a36573409adbb291e4b" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Love Riot: Chapter 2</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_aa3326377996fa6794385725a74332b0">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0b515b804ffdf5c332e9a887641648df" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Love Riot: Chapter 3</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_9af5e37be8ae968e1157809e66b66143">3 items</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_00ae05d57c61ce57c4a511030f7b913a" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Oh the Irony!</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_0f7fe08fc11600225eb15e217484c78a">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d8e2a4a20317adfbf55c5c22e416160"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains comic books by Luigi Jocson, also known as "Lui421," and was published by Circle 421 in 2014. Every book contains a collection of not-so-usual stories of your not-so-usual everyday individuals living their not-so-usual everyday lives.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_44826cb0e9790e12e4061fcd2a4c5e02" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Recreate</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_30516ed3d5f7e0e548c691fa5ff9449f">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95a6418d1e3f6e7fb159bb1daeb410d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a comic created by artists under the aliases Yolak and Rawwrr. The story is fueled by power hungry, violent Lord Bel-shok who was captured by a powerful witch-queen of the Ishen forest. She is able to persuade Lord Bel-shok to comply with her demands to go to the Balete tree to see "him" by supplying Lord Bel-shok with the ancestral key to his land.</p><p>Creators: Carlo Enaje; Patrick Enrique</p><p>Publisher: Chain Mason</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d37b93c3c35a1f528683cd8121c137b5" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Tayuman: At Ang Mga Nagaalsang Tinapay</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d28412cf7085d5a95289b933ed625f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This comic is about Tayuman, sentient pastries, a famous actress, and corrupt landowners. This playful comic exposes serious themes of exploitation and corruption, all while working with the theme of sentient bread.</p><p>Creator: D. Jose</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_68ec4ad21b9ba1e8ac913b55c8f10745" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>The Hunting</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d7f9a619e7b17c852916b3bfaa61136d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This comic follows the story of Zyo, a dark elf who found himself in Manila while on the run from white elves trying to hunting him down. In Manila, a place believed to be full of good food, people, and hiding places, Zyo is forced to use the sword that his late brother left him in order to fight against the white elves. Zyo unleashes its powers against the white elves. Can he be the true wielder of Naga, the sword of freedom?</p><p>Creators: Daniel Collado; Miko Migriño; Laraine Gazmen; Mikhail Plata</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_767a893f926f5aee04ca383bd8634ef5" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>The Hunting</title> Chapter 1</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_32c61241ec9f85bd8761759e86b18085">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd148938f10cd1ec86453ecfb1a628a5" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>The Hunting</title> Chapter 2</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_981f497f86d5bd306889bad8ed4899a0">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8c7df241b312bbeaf7fdb4a2db5031d9" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Windmills</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011-2017</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8df0961c1dc06d1af283e33dd23bf54d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Windmills</title> is a semi-autobiographical comic with anamorphic characters that depict Josel Nicolas, the author, as a son, a friend, sometimes a lover, and a comic book artist. This semi-autobiographical comic shows the author's adventures in life and love through the lens of wisdom balanced with the ability to laugh at oneself.</p><p>Publisher: Flipside</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_3aacaef88c7c0a34a77061d8da45128b" level="item"><did><unittitle>No. 4: <title>I'm Gonna Be-ear</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011 November 10</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_aa62154a2c473a5a9223256c195567f2">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bd7b180af4ef95e982a9107830f66cfa" level="item"><did><unittitle>No. 5: <title>It's About Time</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_463246e61efb946e9a414d7487ffa139">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d3f055232fa24157affafef641085c1c" level="item"><did><unittitle>No. 6: <title>Stop Talking To Yourself</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_601438e92216582ca482e922c6ea8b7a">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_31133089361b226b0a09ba21c14f7f22" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Darwin's Association of Delicious Evilness</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_895cf823333592d1b88975c530d0a1fb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Darwin is a little, evil mastermind in the making. He has big plans of being a tyrannical dictator who will plant a giant bomb in the core of the earth. But Darwin is still an elementary school student, focusing on recruiting classmates who would be fit to be members of his evil association. This dark but mostly humorous comic brings bits nostalgia through its young characters, their street games, and the elementary school setting of the comic.</p><p>Creator: John Carlo Clemente</p><p>Publisher: Alamat</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_b464e0333c9baef9297787439a6141d8" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Darwin's Association of Delicious Evilness 1</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_f0b088fcd84e85b0b30d2eb9cea01e68">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f73546f12fe592e8f43d51416625f23f" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Darwin's Association of Delicious Evilness 2</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_454daf8695701599b888f91908fe01e1">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e16c4af6d3e4938fc79cfa19c3eaa101" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Darwin's Association of Delicious Evilness 3</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_31bb15c9129a0e6b684ed4fd63445b43">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0e54643a31c81110530a7e197300e8ae" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Darwin's Association of Delicious Reflection #4</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_7a7cd8b65da09596a93d23dee5ed62b6">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a020f8b5d121d080c052ff108f27651c" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>???</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15e428ce43d9622fc0b0c09c522a7d82"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The first comic, <title>???#1</title>, is a compilation of mostly autobiographical strips about DJ Legaspi, except for a few, including one about Yeti Crab. <title>???#2</title> is a compilation of different comic strips that are purely autobiographical, providing a variety of stories about DJ's life, including stories about his dog, his childhood, his beard, and his wedding.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7d3908285bd67b0475c48c694fe8ea0d" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Candido's Apocalypse</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4da9ebbac7ee773b05e38113554227bf">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89286296bf4aa0820d6c6609ad2f15fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this comic-book adaptation of Nick Joaquin's classic novel, teenager Bobby gets the power to see through people, literally. First, Bobby begins to see through people's clothes, until he begins to see through their skin and gaze upon their flesh and bones.</p><p>Creators: Cyrene Ela; Natasha Ringor</p><p>Publisher: 502 Komiks</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9164afeadcb58e395d829088d5f5dd91" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Maso</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2010</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_b55d85ab9f0ce20393055442ba4d5e78">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2c38ae8ba60094a926e74dcf3bc7deb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a superhero comic book, Filipino-style. Maso, a well known superhero works with BANGIS, a league of villains, to save his girlfriend. Burdened by shame, he takes out his frustration on other heroes and starts to smear his image in the eyes of the Filipino people. Maharlika, a former American superhero literally knocks some sense into Maso, but trouble is around the corner. A special operations squad of heroes attack the two of them because Maharlika turned his back on the United States.</p><p>Creator: Ramil A. Ibay</p><p>Publisher: dGREAT</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_04c0a4bdeca0f7372454c60072392422" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Manosaur</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3d8264bd07cd5b6304af0be4b9a0d203">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_59507385fbd1cb351e92940049562b77"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Manasaur is the lone survivor of the meteor shower that wiped out the dinosaurs on Earth, and now, he tries his best to fit in with the modern human world.</p><p>Creator: Elbert Or</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_dfa7e8d21ccf1959eb3236725237aa4d" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Goons</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_90a13b661d3a1bd4333cba83572e2f2e">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2dd3f2b794d087c71fc54e5b56b05eda"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Goon</title> is a comic about Zeus, a man hired to be a henchman for a league of villains. All proceeds from the sale of comic were donated to the victims of Typhoon Yolanda.</p><p>Creator: Mary Or; Hinchel Or; Joey Pastrana</p><p>Publisher: 502 Komiks</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a8984614bd5bc9097eaceca526fe30d6" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>PAD KOMIKS</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2cf713f1b7055810e4bef7977c61368"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>PAD is an abbreviation for Pagibig, Aksyon, Dilim-a three part comic series about Boy, who falls in love with a girl who later disappears. Despite the journey Boy takes to save her, they still end up breaking up, teaching Boy the lesson that sometimes, the things that make us happy have always been right besides us.</p><p>Publisher: Ardie Aquino</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_9b7c7e2644d1c33649b1e0713917b749" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Unang Yugto Pagibig</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_2eeecb8fca2fb00006c2b0613cd0da61">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f5139531e25b65a1b2a6513b60237194" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Ikalawang Yugto Aksyon</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_ee56c2de948fa0cbc25071fdbceb63c8">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c473b3cde8984f9e9ca12caa07485fec" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Ikatlong Yugto Dilim</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_957fa1078cd359aad2332672708d4223">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8b355eb406fdfb906a476785e458540e" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Sanduguan</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2007-2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3b4d29e6981656b0072e9918ded77845">4 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f849ddcf9808c49c722e5939862a6688"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Sanduguan</title> is a fictional comic book universe of Filipino superheroes based on native Filipino myths and stories. The universe is split into three factions: Sandugo, Katipunan, Inc. and the Zodiac Force. The concept of the Filipino hero team, Sandugo, was loosely based on sanduguan (blood ritual) done by Katipuneros who vowed to fight against the Spanish occupation in the Philippines. In these <title>Sanduguan</title> issues, Sandugo battles against the villain Vital and his Acolytes for the Eye of Bathala, or the eye of the Creator.</p><p>Creator: Gener A. Pedriña</p><p>Publisher: Kathang Indio Studios</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_1872867283db23d0cb55681ed6529148" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Sanduguan #12</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013 March</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_02c5760c69134100e3cf51dc6f721e92" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Para Fierra</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b681f55eb8c0b41da596700ab6064661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This comic centers around Donny, a young man who boards a jeepney driven by Mang Aldo, who agrees to drop him off after making his usual late night rounds. Little to Donny's knowledge, the jeepney shuttles passengers made up of demons, angels, incarnations, and anthropomorphisms to places beyond the human world. What Donny doesn't consider is the price for a ride to heaven, hell, and back.</p><p>Creators: Fidelis Tan; Kiko Dans</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_657d8f73383619f623c775211860f0f3" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Route 1: Night Riders</title></unittitle></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_57090ac0891deb13714c4f5f88e31531" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Route 2: Impyerno</title></unittitle></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8974dba3d36cc0b18a4de0f352eb8337" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Superhero Na Stainless: Boy Bakal</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2010-2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_aab45524f56b2305059d3ca4d6374741">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b04e085e5ae7ea0e341a47b4ee1ea51e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Boy Bakal</title> follows the story of 10-year-old Rayan Keen, a child prodigy and owner of a successful chain of junk stores scattered across the Philippines. His superhero costume is made of strong, sturdy stainless steel that helps him fight against crimes and villains. This volume includes 10 chapters of the superhero comic book.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ed99d8e857fe61f935f0a1873fbcc557" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>I Hate Mornings</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_bf8237e1ee8a0f9ac72ddabfcc70de79">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c20e87a362e59c735c7b8420a44634b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a comic book about an author of comic books and his struggle to write about crime fighting heroes that are also realistic. The author thinks it is absurd to both be a superhero and be real. However, the reason he hates mornings so much is that he unknowingly turns into a crime fighting hero at night after falling asleep and wakes up not remembering anything. It is ironic because the realistic superhero he struggles to write about is actually himself.</p><p>Creator: Kenneth  Yu</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7f63bdb403a5dfa269ac2538f2a19464" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Shatter Space - Space Mando</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_5bee3b18406a8d41cadc0ed98da3791c">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a32ef1a16ee312c647ae2e003936454"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Shatterspace</title> is about a space-faring nomad who believes he is the last of his kind. Not having seen a sign of life for a while, he checks a planet out in search of intelligence but discovers more than he bargains for.</p><p>Creator: Nelz Yumul</p><p>Publisher: Dark Bulb Comics</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_12fa5d4a3b1a2cc32c574fd0af15049b" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Hari ng Komyut</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6d3b995423020c55a5df9080d95b2366">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e3e29f46da420c347567c717af7131f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The King of Commute rises above the long lines, the hassle, the rudeness, and the traffic during his endeavors on public transportation. This compilation of single-page comics shows the everyday journeys of the King of Commute as he travels through the city by taking jeepneys, buses, trains, and van services with kindness and grace.</p><p>Creator: Lizette Daluz</p><p>Publisher: Anino Comics</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_dce4bdcbe3d9dd54dcea27c605ce6fe8" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Opismeyts</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_72ff14887753de19f353252c84a3a326">4 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63f909a1b2e64ed473949ac23259ee50"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Opismeyts</title> was originally a webcomic that started out with the title <title>Model Employee</title>. After being rebooted a few years later, <title>Opismeyts</title> became successful, and started getting printed in <title>The Daily Inquirer</title> and made into compilation comic books. The comics revolve around the daily lives of so-called "model" employees and their boss.</p><p>Creator: Ramark Masangcay</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_41843f4a0a1b6a19a9a011f6088cd4ff" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Lindol #1</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c67c240529cd3aca3d1381d53fe73b1e">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d490174856d8699d11b50c9d289fb41"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the New World, ravaged by earthquakes and tsunamis, people have to adapt to the aftermath that wiped out society's structure. We follow the story of a former marine and an art conservator, who go out of their way to find bare necessities as they navigate through the rubble of the Philippines. The purpose of this comic, aside from entertaining its readers, is to raise awareness about earthquake preparedness for this overlooked threat to society.</p><p>Creators: Tedi Gustilo Villasor; Randy Valiente</p><p>Publisher: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://www.tedi31.com/">Tedi31.com</extref></p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_21557755e0bbce340d873520422dc86b" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Bravos: Cebu</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_452731cded909166d199ef9766930fd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In a world where only the Philippines has superheroes, those with powers serve their country as Bravos. <title>Bravos: Cebu City</title> features the story of Lea, who gets recruited to attend Maharlika High, a government-accredited educational facility for the exceptionally gifted. Leah has no interest in becoming a Bravo, but accepts the scholarship because of the financial support. This chapter falls under the same universe as <title>Bravos: Manila,</title> despite having different writers, artists, and art styles.</p><p>Creators: Elbert Or; Cy Vendivil; Jem Bernaldez</p><p>Publisher: Studio Salimbal</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_076e5c17ba6c70280195ceed05ec3f5a" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Cebu</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_4d3b79bb3ece1957c210deb750b50545">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f9e011179c0d0e88f4c9172d951affcd" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Manila</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_10c5fb8238b2af9fb52505299268c297">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26ab612bd13a1dfb75ff82a8a36e89fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: Paolo Chikiamco; Butch Mapa; Wilson Dela Fuente</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_2fed1421272475b56976aebf2307658b" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Butiki At Ang Pagong</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_421d846c3019c4c2570e5e3d8d1e9c3f">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_315c6eac1c83ae92030ce01a446fc245"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A comic written in Baybayin, the ancient script used by Tagalogs in the Philippines. The comic is a modern rendition of a Tinguian folklore about a turtle and a big lizard who went to the field of Gotgotapa to steal ginger. The responsible and slow turtle warns his friend to be careful, but the reckless lizard does not listen. Despite getting the ginger, the lizard gets caught by a human, and the turtle gets away.</p><p>Creators: Cy Vendivil; Koi Carreon</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aedb34256b4b6678e579c0cdfe3cb33f" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Badass Na Buhay Ni Lam-Ang</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014-2015</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eb56992db5f793f450085ad5acd90e5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a modern rendition of an Ilokano epic poem about Lam-ang, an extraordinarily strong warrior. Like any epic journey, the story starts with the birth of Lam-ang, in which he names himself using  his extraordinary ability to talk as a newborn. Shortly after, he begins searching for his father, which ends up in disappointment and anger because the Igorots have beheaded him. Lam-ang erases the Igorot tribe from existence, settles on a mountain top, and then ventures out to find his purpose. Eventually, Lam- ang chooses a wife, but cannot marry her until he defeats all of her suitors. The original version of this epic has been passed down orally, evolving over the course of Philippine history. This version's bold style does not shy away from showing Lam-ang's extremely strong powers and how he uses them.</p><p>Creator: John Carlo Clemente</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_6f3f40a1ea6acfc165d749873fab97af" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Paglapag Ng Epikong May Laman At Buto Sa Mundong Ibabaw</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_33e15e617f0b320c68ba3957bcb873ee">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c62e98b38807f68d5106946ca17ce471" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Sayaw Sa Kamay Ni Kamatayan</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_63c85e026a54857424c91273892f4a42">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e74fdfbec2a1b1ab87dee68a62c25a0" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Mga Gutom Na Buwitre</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4cb086ba9630cb46817fd86db0635f4d">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d44af1e32a58cb91bc49a2f6db4d7a4d" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Libog Ng Digmaan</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9e4605c5c7556e18edefcf77cd9c232a">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_fc27803ab09c4ee4feb8d341fa31cf53" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ligaya</title> #1 and #2</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_11dabcc53bca4120b653d6a719c57b82">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e7ea04649e28bf599b3ffb4092d6b21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A comic about two sad kids and the ghost of a national hero that tackles the problems that slip into people's everyday lives.</p><p>Creators: Addie Onday; Faye Bergonia</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_eabd00ccdfb7b81e6e57c16e011f80b2" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>The Lolita Chronicles</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f72571f0879176646e769c09538e81f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These comics follow Lolita's life in the office as a financial analyst as she faces strict bosses, haughty co-workers, and a messy love life. Maria Criselda Santos sprinkles in Filipino gay lingo in the comic as a way to create humor in the dialogue.</p><p>Creators: Maria Criselda Santos; Stacee J</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_d15c4e4b96a0073836fa94db394eefec" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>First Love Never Deadmas</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_837f5d229adfe7104a3b9d8a40a8eb7d">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c04116bd377fb82a506f70738854d9df" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Beauty And The Beastmode</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_e79320e60708d8dca4641e6537985dd6">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_00e581eeb10c202adae3e55d06b58acd" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>AWOL To Remember</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c83c65b7c9ffad874a2f25d62934e22b">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3259052aad22a9894f491dc5808634c0" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>All The Love In The Fort</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_08491e5b608d28421dc6fe8957810424">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_9c58eaf26469b2e2ffcf0dd01ca52c37" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Espiritista</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73ecac2688b766d795f0d3a9a79c5650"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Espiritista</title> is a comic about a school that teaches students how to defend and fight against malevolent <emph render="italic">Engkantos</emph>, or ancient spirits. In these chapters of <title>Espiritista</title>, Samuel is facing off with his old mentor, who has betrayed him and the school, and has sided with the <emph render="italic">Engkanto</emph>.</p><p>Creator: Niño Balita</p><p>Publisher: Pagsapuge Comics</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_a60d190589b98712344d525818539af0" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>4: Tears and Cobwebs of the Past</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_58794ce94894ce55a376622110707e6c">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d81f7323b366d6b525d561ab8f8772fc" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>5: Forbidden and Unforgiven</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_ace04ecbe6f862db1a0431b9bf388886">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c2cb38df83818c413fecaeb436e6c2fa" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>6: Motives and Tactics</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_37d3d08edb1e0e96aa31c4a5bbbed8c4">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_73ad33080eb1aa15b40be31178127b2a" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Native</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c775788257c0b242d866440a5de34631"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Native</title> is a comic book series by Julius Villanueva that is about how the human race is resisting violent alien colonies that have invaded the Earth. It shows how humans have either sided with, or have taken up arms against the violent bug-like creatures despite being outnumbered and overpowered.</p><p>Publisher: Azhdarchid Komix</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_e1c14914aaa96744e937bec36d643ba6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 1</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_db37e628ff81a1587c86a644567acd76">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c3f207418fbdb47ae552bbb1e7f7fcd1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 2</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_05fed3072878b0f450a2b33b989a2094">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_506678f9b3354e135cb7f1830207a807" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 3</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_77a5a779a6f41fe36a0ab90bf3c7c753">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e86fa4c95e75fa51dd916c9fc6d3e16e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 4</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_1b6ec964234233b32ad6683b024e85a4">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5ad35603c476cf64dd5673d040326588" level="item"><did><unittitle>Issue 5</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ccf448bbfdb10608c62b1635ed9f8fcb">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d2b77c5edbd32ea6cf0342d5d7c5b9bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Epilogue</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c451478f94824ee32645b79e12dc7030">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c782b2b86ea96055019b4b11113e1fbf" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Antingeros</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4538c259cb64a736fb612529a66f5a78">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b7997e53131ad748c6d99e9f5c9e58b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In these comics, four childhood friends each obtain an <emph render="italic">anting-anting</emph>, a magical charm that gives power and protection, by remembering and following a neighborhood grandpa's stories about them. These friends walk a careful line between power, ambition, violence, and treachery with their borrowed powers from their <emph render="italic">anting-anting</emph>.</p><p>Creators: James Bernardo; Geonard Yleana; Carlo Cruz</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_687c0c44997ead72514daa4e11c08069" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Higante</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f4fb529e94b70de9162a6f69f215052d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This comic book series is about two homeless brothers, Obet and Toti, who scour garbage heaps for food. While hiding in a drainage pipe, Obet finds a mysterious liquid that turns him into a giant when he drinks it. Not free from the binds of poverty, Obet uses his new powers to get him and his brother food, as well as to protect other people in poverty.</p><p>Creator: Geonard Yleana</p><p>Publisher: Pelikomiks Studios</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_802f195bea81bc27c71c9049ce609c1c" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>A Monster Grows From the Wasteland</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_fffbfb51e9615b1cfbbcc063ec40f693">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cb992ca00c612d263c5927a331ab438c" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>A Mountain of Appetite, A Big Fistful of Hate</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_89eb62126c31db8a01a034109bae0b03">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_41354b82197190c0166715ba105b7ada" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Of Mice, Monsters &amp; Men</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_7d54a24d90065a230d900786a6c15e3d">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e463a2d56892bcdf8cbd5cd4ea4b2025" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>The Drink of the Gods</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_50eeff8d58e80146b3dcbaa5af3cc1e8">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b54bc17ef553606600df06e35daaee82" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Into the Hole</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_199690e77b8c931c44b74d5097653580">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8639b48494eefa3060e95ce353b8acc7" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Aswang de Manila</title> 1 and 2</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_b06e5fea973df2c2aef006091fe0a249">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ac3793f84eb25923b81d137975a3bf0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These comic books are about Maria and Jose, classmates whose paths cross when they acknowledge that they both sense and see <emph render="italic">aswangs</emph>. Throughout this story, the different types of <emph render="italic">aswangs</emph> are introduced, and their purpose and relationship to humans are revealed.</p><p>Creators: Kevin Samala; Nadine Narag; Ianthe Pimentel</p><p>Publisher: Blue Indie Komiks</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ab30b3612d60691babaaf5f958b3702d" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Agila</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015-2016</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f73320b4fdb16043e66b2e499aff2ed2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Agila</title> is a comic series about Juan José, a college professor of Philippine history, who was chosen by the spirit of a mysterious wooden mask that provides him with superhuman abilities.</p><p>Creators: José Victor Fuentecilla; Arjohn Perdon; JC Panililio</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_488ecef5476fbee876665112535b6f8c" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Agila 001</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015 August</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_92b6c23ecb0315bc90ec378cab86e6b4">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_95a8e126f95d789b1ee061875e1bc8d8" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Agila 002</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015 November</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_ddcde91b2ae8017f257f438af166525f">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b4d0e23116042e959944dc950093dfc" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Agila 003</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016 March</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4a1b9a8e93ed2a641c2e9ffe380774c7">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_6bc197ed34eafe0f355569447d9ada43" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila Metronom</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_765ae33b82ab35e305b87fb90676e486"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Brandon is a geek who has loved comic books, RPGs, and cosplay his whole life. At 17 years old, he becomes the world's first superhero, complete with the cape, mask, skintight outfit, and amazing superpowers. Metronome shows the emergence of Dakila as a superhero, but also as a young boy who is trying to fill the shoes of a savior.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_00e1153856497c44e92566513feec8b1" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Buwan</title> Part 1 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_0dd7d6381ea869d735691beb6c351c67">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0ae6fd58bc19c1f596f75271a1d74116"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Jason Confesor</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2fa85d7ba0023e6fe5563ea28e3b4f82" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Buwan</title> Part 2 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_60bccad0bc6e714fbe6a0bd3ccd04a8f">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a4e5074137a452eebfd338deacc1d14d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Jason Confesor</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a5b33270315bf419ded2252d6bc24ff2" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Metronom</title> Part 1 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_2e459780ccf20ad45a52b536d98989cb">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_76b3be36f0943da276d8a885e7d5384a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Nonie Cruzado</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_92dc863dff8fef248d119753654eec86" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Metronom</title> Part 2 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_9ab66823bbd514c6b47b893e473cb82a">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_342a21d58d6857f4e3e84e5598af6c80"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Romnick Magbanua</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c17ec8a055d3d4bebf6b0345638a3ec6" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Metronom</title> Part 3 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_4ecabacb9865386f9e2f732dda060c6b">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1dfe3f1d7d73c6107ef61b48f39204c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Romnick Magbanua</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9d1b985e3957f56f0a3e88f736f0f666" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Siyudad</title> Part 1 of 4</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_534be75b25f117ef96b9d3fa6fb2acbe">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_40da32d4bd9fa203c66281f29b891cde"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Pyotr Mutuc</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4e9f337044e34f65bfeb3d599d619016" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Kadena</title> Part 1 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_3e80634b4a396d2f02fe8dfb61d1f392">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bfacd4f34768405eb92fbdc1d316a5d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Patrick Flores</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0c1fede2eca7a61502f56f5e7d3b9b16" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Kapalaran</title> Part 1 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_ca57f31f0082ed1a3dbdcfd8f31a0e0b">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f618265ebb7556e36ae32d351a81874"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Bibo Reyes</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b27e10277aa465627320fd283b23c8a2" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Lumilim</title> Part 1 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_8a4c18d475ba7f02d73a7f67ce817e9b">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a553228211ad79ec8180242ddf721c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Elmer Cantada</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_78769e6c98996d9fc998f4c2c5de398c" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Makadaot</title> Part 1 of 3</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_660e2e6654f5d03e7af6bc19b6f9aa48">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba49e992ffb4aafe294a36ecf624af5f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Carl Corilla</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7816736d63ed1bd3e52f984a6504f77b" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Dakila: Dahas</title> Part 1 of 4</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_eb9a49f0b34daee15d28dfeb952c3ce9">1 item</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f06c1cf797d604877998ca6928a467f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creators: David Hontiveros; Gaston Garcia</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_377b1440a3a4a67e726573b7c4a882fa" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Incognito</title></unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_5729010a021e1d62775ecc96202d6d11">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3254e5a881a643d2ba846903166111b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Intramuros is the strongest country in the world due to its advanced technology and because of a wall that keeps its people safe. When a mysterious killer and thief dubbed Anino infiltrates Intramuros, the safety and economy of the country becomes compromised. These comics are the 3rd and 5th installations of the Filipino comic series.</p><p>Creator: Faye Villanueva</p><p>Publisher: Kawangis Komiks</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_68ff06f8aa91f063df1d95d3e3b19259" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ella Arcangel</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016-2017</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0451be647f7ae6dc92ac24eb2f902253"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Ella Arcangel is a <emph render="italic">mananambal</emph>, a person that can treat both natural and supernatural maladies. She lives in Barangay Masikap, an area ridden with poverty, crime, and hardships. In addition to watching out for supernatural occurrences, she is concerned about the well-being and future of her <emph render="italic">barangay</emph> and its residents who are living in poverty.</p><p>Creator: Julius Villanueva</p><p>Publisher: Azhdarchid Komiks</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_9281276a6ecaefd3d97c16bb9c4da800" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Oyari sa Dilim</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_6a5810ef9bfe25f9b95959275f0753df">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_703ad12c85319fd26330ce09cab64c2c" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Lupang mga Naglaho</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_c8822241c141a5e1ed03a575ba586f9a">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ae0143a742f31e90779748424e244496" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Morion</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015-2017</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84be0496f6e27f312db6b9e64361e61e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a comic book series inspired by a local festival in the town of Marinduque called <emph render="italic">Moriones</emph>, celebrated every Holy Week. It is based on the premise that God made three creatures at the beginning of time: angels, humans, and djinn.</p><p>Creator: Wan Malinao Mañanita</p><p>Publisher: Frances Luna III</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_2ae7e94b1bc9ee2039b79106e0038ee0" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Morion</title> vol.2 issue 1</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9f1729a31576a7baa90680bee07a5179">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d6456b1074af51a0d0636f5163657b98" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Ang Morion</title> vol.2 issue 2</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_977de5140fa8ea7e555cc9d1e18d89bc">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_5dd6fc21df33d63090685ab0810e87e1" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Anarchy Inc.</title> #1 and #2</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_819fc0b012beef4ee2d674b22da4b834">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85ad95deda94bd71290ffd1c0d42fb2f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a comic series about anarchists who use their superpowers to protect the streets from syndicate families fighting for territorial control. Although the anarchists work individually and fight each other over territories they patrol, a mysterious anarchist comes onto the scene and proposes that they all work together.</p><p>Creator: Chuck Llanto</p><p>Publisher: Eventual Empire</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_966ba6cdc0a7d9f7b2c34449c066754c" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Muros: The Cemetery Girl</title>, Parts 1, 2, and 3</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2015-2017</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_bd9475f0a373142573d7f078782c40b9">3 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4aba65642a74e8d2ba87bde8f67afa35"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A three-part comic book series about a dystopian Manila, a place that has turned into one of sin and danger.</p><p>Creators: Paolo Chikiamco; Borg Sinaban</p><p>Publisher: Studio Salimbal</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e839798ad849db5ebd71c5c98f238466" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Crime-fighting Call Center Agents</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011-2013</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad78440c4d2493d8cf34cafbd4b8bbc9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is a comic book series about a group of call center agents who frequently run into supernatural beings and situations that call for them to fight.</p><p>Creators: Noel Pascual; AJ Bernardo</p><p>Publisher: Kowtow Komiks</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_5a6ce656f99e50e4ea78321abb2aac00" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Crime-fighting Call Center Agents #1: Psycho Killer On A Bike</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_3bbe0f6d257a6c6759ee25fa2f132dcd">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9887e8e5de7242090ddbda02ecf96c15" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Crime-fighting Call Center Agents #2: Pag-uulayaw Sa Barrio Namayapa</title> part 1 of 2</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_7404f3178fefa3183f8cf95eeed15b5a">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_92431b914b2c7fb16cf3c7dfb1e6b0cc" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Crime-fighting Call Center Agents #3: Pag-uulayaw Sa Barrio Namayapa</title> part 2 of 2</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2012</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_549654f162f2c3540977e479a52d567d">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ad6891eba73e311333d82960c49780d9" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Crime-fighting Call Center Agents #4</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2013</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_25c03da78bc738cc2f78649d0a49aec1">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_5921229e0b370e10e6bcc86581e55b43" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Kayaw</title></unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04516927369041d98557f7b9b01755d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Kayaw</title> is a three-part comic series that follows the story of a female Japanese intelligence officer named Kamiko as she embarks on her mission to conquer the Kalinga mountains in the Philippines. Despite the sheer force and advanced war technology of the Imperial Japanese Army, they are no match for the indigenous headhunters who know the terrain of Kalinga like no other. The comics advertise Katribu Tatu, a subgroup of the Katribu Art Movement, who specialize in giving customized indigenous tattoos that are similar to the ones seen on the Kalinga warriors in the comics.</p><p>Creators: Steve Magay; Dax</p><p>Publisher: Hollowpoint Studios</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_0af9538dceb228ee9af6ddc0f7a1e5ba" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Kayaw</title> (part 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2014 April</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a8ed02a7d4845c203b043b8cf652a0bd">1 item</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b4d2a3935409fd64f487f2b671c1bd8f" level="item"><did><unittitle><title>Kayaw</title> (part 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2016 April</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_1ca838ac01515d455df3fb21ba220cf8">1 item</physdesc></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_59799c3d3cf477bec81757a269adc10b" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>Ignition Comix</title> Issues 1 and 2</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_820cd73b8b86895a78d3b524e99d55a8">2 items</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a36320c51360a6b5f7bfa02852cb3ff7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><title>Ignition Comix</title> is a compilation of four different stories published by Atomic Monkey Production in Makati City, Philippines.</p><p>Creators: Michael Del Mundo; Michael Seludo</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
