<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8gq6zzh/">puce9462.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Puce photographic album</titleproper><titleproper>La puce, 1880? <num>LSC.94/62</num></titleproper><author>Jane Carpenter with assistance from Simon Elliott; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-27 12:07:49 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English.</language></langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>La puce</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.94/62</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 albums</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(20 photographic prints) : albumen, 15 x 21 cm (album)<lb/>Photographs (12 x 17 cm) are affixed to rectos and versos of leaves of heavy beige stock, bordered in red.
<lb/>Bound in red cloth covers, with title "La puce" stamped in gold on upper cover; gold moir&amp;#x00E9; silk endpapers; all edges gilt. Gift of Frederic Thomas Blanchard.
<lb/>Spec. Coll. copy: in modern beige cloth-covered clamshell box, with spine title "La puce."</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1880/1880" type="inclusive">1880? Date from ms. note on verso of rear endpaper.</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2df6da02388f76ed68c17e5c4363b88d" label="Abstract">Album, probably created in France in 1880, of twenty erotic photographs of a young woman inspecting herself for fleas, whose actions are intended primarily to titillate.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_5095017f3e18874b0e1cfe8b02d247fe">Stored off-site at SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1f8487fce1df5e5bea3e06b270e0a1a8">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ed91dbbb1d57b847fcd3a6bdc9c716cb">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical object belong to the UC Regents. Literary rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d2847359bac8741e26d527ba25b95402">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], La puce (Collection 94/62). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e147cf3a562f5dd74a9fd764d7903e7a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_e74c189aac1a8cb1b2db0b0acfc36c71">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9965138203606533">9965138203606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_95bedb706ebb9ebde8ae0876f052c356">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The first six photographs show the young woman, dressed in long-sleeved Victorian blouse and skirt, seated on a lavisly draped couch beneath a large mirror, in which the viewer can see her reflection. She reads, then falls asleep. The remaining fourteen photos reveal the young woman gradually undressing, presumably to locate the flea ("la puce") that is biting her. First she removes her blouse, then her stockings, finally her skirt. She holds aloft the offending insect in the final photo. See the chapter "Sexual connotations of the flea in word and image" in Georges de la Tour's "Flea-Catcher" and the iconography of the flea-hunt in seventeenth-century baroque art / Crissy Bergeron, available online.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_4b1120ed1451b250b0259ba8f8f21bbd">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Part of the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6489s0cc/">Photograph Album Collection (Collection 94) </extref> in UCLA Library Special Collections.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Albumen prints.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photograph albums.</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Photographic prints.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fleas -- Symbolic aspects -- Photographs.</subject>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Erotica.</genreform>
    <persname source="ingest">Blanchard, Frederic T. (Frederic Thomas), b. 1878, former owner.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
