<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8kh0qpm/">sanj2187.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Sanjian (Avedis K.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>Finding aid for the Avedis K. Sanjian papers <num>LSC.2187</num></titleproper><author>Machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Finding aid last updated 2024 February 21.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-18 12:04:48 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Avedis K. Sanjian papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.2187</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">25.8 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(24 record cartons, 4 document boxes, and 1 shoebox.)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1945/1995" type="inclusive">ca. 1945-1995</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5a91e0bc462fd5dc2228a701e54c7dd6" label="Abstract">Avedis Krikor Sanjian, Professor emeritus of UCLA's Department of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures, was a world-renowned scholar of Armenian studies who wrote ten books and authored more than 40 articles in English and Armenian. The collection consists of personal and professional correspondence, Armenian studies lectures and notes, Department of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures faculty meeting minutes, UCLA Armenian studies minutes, brochures and student publications, his research files, publications, slides, microfilm, photos, audio and video tapes, curriculum vitae and biographies.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_6a6a8ec66e8899ce5f59c7fef59b26f9">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_37dcf9276d42827b28531351d5995e6d">Materials are in English and Armenian.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_743849ea8e39af529ff4ebc107561f2a">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d5c8c04053d4bd72c0fcedd7e2ab2098">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e8e6127125c95b6b2b76dde9179e8b12">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Greg Sanjian, 1997.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_c0415c628f3debdad88acba3da3ba38b">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9973225023606533">9973225023606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_408c705e1f30b64d2a19d7f9b5854e07">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Avedis K. Sanjian papers (Collection 2187). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b264aa011816eaf3974936546e5ef3fe">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Kelly Besser with assistance from Rebecca Bucher, 2013.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's Library Collections and Archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_cc2e6e63ed7d854a061a05daeae0a89d">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>Avedis K. Sanjian was born on February 24, 1921 in Marash, Turkey. After spending years in Armenian refugee camps in Syria and Lebanon, the Sanjians moved to Palestine in 1926, and three years later settled in the Armenian Quarter of Jerusalem, where he grew up. Sanjian earned two degrees in English: a bachelor's degree from the American University of Beirut in 1949 and a master's degree from the University of Michigan in 1950. He married Helen Karaghuzian in 1950 and they had their son Gregory in 1952. Four years later he became the first graduate student at Michigan to receive a doctorate in Near Eastern Studies. </p><p>Sanjian's academic career began in 1957 with an appointment at Harvard University's Center for Middle Eastern Studies as a postdoctoral research fellow in Armenian studies. He was appointed assistant professor of Armenian studies at Harvard University in 1961, the first time full-time Armenian studies appointment in the United States. At Harvard, Sanjian developed the first curriculum of Armenological courses in the U.S. and compiled <title render="italic">A Grammar of Classical Armenian</title> to enable others to learn this language. </p><p>Sanjian left Harvard when the Department of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) invited him to join its faculty in 1965 as associate professor of Armenian studies. Three years later he was promoted to the rank of full professor, and in 1969 he was appointed to the first ever endowed chair at UCLA, the Chair for Armenian Studies. At his suggestion in 1979, the Chair was named after medieval Armenian mystic poet Grigor Narekatsi. Also in 1969, he inaugurated UCLA's graduate program in Armenian studies.</p><p>From 1970 to 1974, Sanjian served as Chairman of the Department of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures, which had four undergraduate and seven graduate degree programs. During this time he was also working on his opus, <title render="italic">A Catalogue of Medieval Armenian Manuscripts in the United States</title>, a descriptive and analytical study of all Armenian manuscripts housed in the United States with the exception of the UCLA collection for which he prepared a separate catalogue, <title render="italic">Medieval Armenian Manuscripts at the University of California, Los Angeles</title> (Z6621.U65963 A76 1999). Sanjian finalized negotiations for UCLA's acquisition of this collection with Dr. Caro Minasian and hand-delivered its most valuable item, the manuscript of the Four Gospels executed at the Armenian monastery of Glajor.</p><p>Sanjian wrote ten books and authored more than 40 articles in English and Armenian. He is a founding member of the Society for Armenian Studies (SAS), served as its chairman on three occasions and as editor-in-chief of its publication, the <title render="italic">Journal of the Society for Armenian Studies</title> (JSAS). He also served as a board member for the National Association for Armenian Studies and Research (NAASR) and provided testimony on the Armenian genocide before the United States Congress Subcommittee on Future Foreign Policy Research and Development on May 11, 1976.</p><p>Sanjian, UCLA Professor of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures, Emeritus, died at the age of 74 on July 22, 1995.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_26a1ea05f88ded45b0e76293710d652f">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection consists of personal and professional correspondence, Armenian studies lectures and notes, Department of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures faculty meeting minutes, UCLA Armenian studies minutes, brochures and student publications, his research files, publications, slides, microfilm, photos, audio and video tapes, curriculum vitae and biographies.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6aaa457da7ac2888bac9dc6852de5de5">
    <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection has been arranged into the following series:</p><p>1. Correspondence.
2. UCLA files.
3. Research files.
4. Publications.
5. Audiovisual materials.
6. Curriculum vitae and biographies.</p>  </arrangement>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref1_h36" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle><container id="aspace_6baefe6b1287627fc9dc7d3ae126d737" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_52b35fb8a0fc97ab19e2771d9498de62" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_461086d256784be92776973ab5cac232" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_f23e86bb876b731577f441c60df027db" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_dcc787b37cb12f603dbc08eeeb0784b4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_f659a1b15a0f861ea3038cecf17012e1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_2fd24b09ce5b439747d1cee7ea4ddcce" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_80e6bbce2e3a4610baede498edaa1e5f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_c35b122a6b2c467197011a330afdbea4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_322e5a6d9fe5a6e3775bbaae2a22c5b2" parent="aspace_c35b122a6b2c467197011a330afdbea4" type="folder">1-36</container><container id="aspace_2149dd81fa909f00184870521b8e7e6f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8bdc5393ee4fa048df9c375c3b43af7a"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 1-4: Personal correspondence files are organized alphabetically by correspondent's last name. Materials include letters from UCLA Librarian for Armenian and Greek, Gia Aivazian, Parisian literary critic and poet, Krikor Beledian, Director of Harvard's Center for Middle Eastern Studies, Sir Hamilton A. R. Gibb, Director of the Armenian Film Foundation, Dr. Michael Hagopian, and Austrian Turcologist of the University of Vienna, Andreas Tietze.</p><p>Box 4-9: Scholarly and professional correspondence files are organized alphabetically by organization, project, publication, event or subject. Materials include letters from Sanjian during his service as Editor of the Journal of the Society for Armenian Studies (JSAS), as a founding member and chairman of the Society for Armenian Studies (SAS) and as a board member for the National Association for Armenian Studies and Research (NAASR). </p><p>Box 8-9:The NAASR files include letters from Chairman Manoog S. Young and Helen Sanjian as well as minutes, rules, by-laws, mailing lists, reports and constitution.</p><p>Box 10: Armenian Assembly correspondence from Sanjian's service on its Board of Directors. Materials also include its newsletters, conference reports, congressional statements commemorating April 24 as Armenian Martyrs Day and Sanjian's paper, "The Armenian Genocide: It's Causes and Effects."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref3_kfe" level="series"><did><unittitle>UCLA files.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5f20986c98a0e93808ed2d18ce4710fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_5732fac2c3c8097f0da9b88c6dedfc44" parent="aspace_5f20986c98a0e93808ed2d18ce4710fc" type="folder">1-26</container><container id="aspace_09245eeb57c86946d7d4d937017c64d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_0ae4312dddb023fce9fc5b44ab15c2d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_9df15d40deb6cfb40125d49857063d0c" parent="aspace_0ae4312dddb023fce9fc5b44ab15c2d6" type="folder">37-51</container><container id="aspace_8dbad8f35905f2870d2f650a569eba68" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_aba654af6a3cf99dbfe29363e39f8ea1" parent="aspace_8dbad8f35905f2870d2f650a569eba68" type="folder">1-26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5a4275b3e647726e429e622b00bc20ea"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 9: Research grant applications, Department of Near Eastern Languages and Cultures faculty meeting minutes, annotated typescript of Sanjian's "Armenian Genocide's Seventieth Anniversary Address," UCLA Armenian Studies press releases and informational brochure.</p><p>Box 11: Faculty Advisory Committee for the Gustave E. Von Grunebaum Center for Near Eastern Studies and Faculty Advisory Committee for the Center for Medieval and Renaissance Studies Annual Reports, minutes and correspondence, copies of the Armenian Students Association publication <title render="italic">Roots</title>, correspondence concerning the inception of the UCLA Narekatsi Chair of Armenian Studies, typescript of interview with Sanjian concerning UCLA's Armenian Studies program, press releases, photos and programs regarding the exhibition, "A Millennium of Armenian Culture," and Sanjian's lecture notes, outlines and reading lists for Armenian history courses.</p><p>Box 12: Handwritten and typed Armenian studies lectures and notes on topics such as language, alphabet, historians and historiography, medieval tales, poetry and folk songs, the cultural renaissance, Shakespeare's sonnets, the millets, the Armenian Question and monk and poet, Krikor Naregatzi.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref5_abq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Research files.</unittitle><container id="aspace_bc61444b815e3e873d620910d7e3ace7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_1720971993497fdb1ccc1a8e33b90e36" parent="aspace_bc61444b815e3e873d620910d7e3ace7" type="folder">1-25</container><container id="aspace_7893200430de62b7871f560a2e1719b5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_42974e3f6e3b46e051bbbb86642893df" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_80cf499996ff1de17f738233d12df686" parent="aspace_42974e3f6e3b46e051bbbb86642893df" type="folder">1, 10</container><container id="aspace_1cc389b11568e1f7d8267fac4aa98623" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_3042105067cefb047bafe1f56a729e6d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_1e58ab4671e97656a45fa01f6fb51f05" parent="aspace_3042105067cefb047bafe1f56a729e6d" type="folder">1</container><container id="aspace_2a0348dea5339cb9bc5723a793e7b7b2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">29</container><container id="aspace_1097821d8e3efbd64a200adf972b4524" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_0f27265ec5c2c556d0caa599717b3407" parent="aspace_1097821d8e3efbd64a200adf972b4524" type="folder">27-45</container><container id="aspace_cd7ce0e8019edd417a06d64a267beefd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_1fe5dadb2ed005a2a8aa22c1514cb91f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_e56387a67c0fa7392d01bb98a33fcf5f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_a053bd449209e34b9e607e417f4327d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_fb5a2eafaf31728aba313017c92af909" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_ac87cba591bdbf8b19b1ce7caf79165c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_b06ad7a3ac72957bdea34a3acf22dad7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8a58249ad14202418fb17a4d03ac331"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 12: Files include material on the following topics concerning Armenian history: Medieval manuscripts in the United States, education and pedagogy, translation of literature, the alphabet, gospel iconography, Glajor's curriculum and scholastic pursuits, Magistros' Epic and Christianity.</p><p>Box 13: Files on the following topics concerning Armenian history: Grammar, poetry and literature, Gregory Magistros and the Tondrakians, Plato, Michael Psellos, medicine, architecture, painting, sculpture and the Four Gospels at the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</p><p>Box 14-15: Sanjian's notes on Medieval Armenian manuscripts organized by country, state and institution. Materials also include photocopies of specific manuscripts such as The Jewish Bride from the Spencer Collection of the New York Public Library and a box of photos of manuscripts from various institutions.</p><p>Box 16: Sanjian's notes on each manuscript in the UCLA Collection of Armenian Manuscripts (Collection 2089). Manuscript files are organized numerically by manuscript number and name. Materials also include detailed summary description and correspondence concerning the Glajor Gospel and binding descriptions by Sylvie L. Merian of Columbia University for each manuscript in the collection.</p><p>Box 17: Materials concerning the history of the Glajor Gospel including files on the History of the UCLA Gospel, Esayi's literary works, the school of Glajor, the manuscripts executed at Glajor, the iconography of the Glajor Gospel and a box of slides and photos.</p><p>Box 18-19, 23: Notes, papers, correspondence, articles, clippings and publications concerning Western-Armenian classical poet Vahan Tekeyan.</p><p>Box 20-21, 23: University of Michigan research materials for Ph.D. dissertation, <title render="italic">The Sanjak of Alexandretta (Hatay): A Study in Franco-Turco-Syrian Relations</title>. Materials also include Sanjian's seminar papers, his correspondence with the Armenian Democratic Liberal Party, bibliographies: Armenia and Armenians in Academic Dissertations, the Armenian Assembly's Directory of Armenian Scholars and the Armenian Press Directory. </p><p>Box 22: Sanjian's notes on Medieval Armenian manuscripts handwritten in Armenian with photocopies of manuscripts.</p><p>Box 29: Sanjian's handwritten notes in Armenian on index cards.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref7_dva" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications.</unittitle><container id="aspace_13d6248563a7f9074a905f37707ba54b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container><container id="aspace_479bd12cc80856492f3a162d1e8c1936" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_6ee5008f80c1cea60ce8b7a7dd7e5c34" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6449ba7495e187c60a9647d31f37bc7c"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Sanjian's publications are organized according to his bibliography as follows: Books, articles in English, articles in Armenian and book reviews.</p><p>Box 24:  Bibliography, typescript copies of dissertations, books, offprints, and photocopied articles in English and Armenian.</p><p>Box 25: Articles in Armenian, book reviews, UCLA Armenian Manuscript Collection 2089 Catalogue, Sanjian's congressional testimony concerning the Armenian genocide, unpublished work and typescript of <title render="italic">Armenian Gospel Iconography: The Tradition of the UCLA Gospel</title> by Sanjian and Thomas F. Mathews.</p><p>Box 26: Typescripts of <title render="italic">The Armenian Communities in Syria Under Ottoman Dominion</title>.</p><p>Books in this collection have been individually cataloged. They are discoverable in the Library catalog with a keyword search for: "Ex libris Avedis K. Sanjian".</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref8_atd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Audiovisual materials.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f84b0745441c0c71c6ae787b3891059f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_6a9c60036ea079e9dd16c4cfc52bc5c3" parent="aspace_f84b0745441c0c71c6ae787b3891059f" type="folder">26-33</container><container id="aspace_04c24b81d0064df5a69af93a41d86a2d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_01e24694f14eadec135eede2ff24e7e7" parent="aspace_04c24b81d0064df5a69af93a41d86a2d" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_d9bffdc5697c214b3bc21cc07eb75630" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_6ac553e50bb7cabfbe009915b169d03d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f739fd7635e26609b2ef61f764bf4f9d"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Box 19: 2x2 Anscochrome slides of Armenia. Folder 26 contains an outline with description of the slides. Slides include images of archaeological excavations, ruins, cathedrals, churches, shrines, educational institutions, museums, public buildings and scenes.</p><p>Box 21: Black and white photos and postcards of buildings in Armenia. Captions cite names of structures and architects.</p><p>Box 27: Thirteen audiocassettes and sixteen VHS videotapes. Videotapes include the following titles: Cilicia...Rebirth, The Armenian Woman in Literature and History, The Armenian Genocide and Mandate for Armenia: American Military Mission to Turkey and Armenia, 1919. Eight audiocassettes are Modern Western Armenian language lessons produced by the Harvard University Modern Language Center. Five audiocassettes are contained within a small box entitled, <title render="italic">Self Teaching Armenian Language Method Practical Textbook of Western Armenian</title> by Haroutiun Kurkjian.</p><p>Box 28: Slides, microfilm, negatives and photos. Images include UCLA Glajor Gospel, Armenia, St. Mark's Gospel, Oregon Gospel and Jerusalem holy sites.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref9_2nf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Curriculum vitae and biographies.</unittitle><container id="aspace_ea579259a66dd68be4e9e7ce7e71ab4f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_4ca4387df87e0fdfee5c5deb1ef018ec" parent="aspace_ea579259a66dd68be4e9e7ce7e71ab4f" type="folder">2-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1ad675cde56b7efc081839381550182a"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Materials include multiple versions of Sanjian's curriculum vitae, a tribute booklet published on the occasion of his 30th anniversary in Armenian Studies, a memorial resolution by Willie L. Brown Jr., Speaker Emeritus of the California Assembly and a memorial program from Forest Lawn Mortuary.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
