<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1j49r2s5/">wo170119.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Worrell (Edward) journal of campaign through the south western and western prairies in the months of May and June, 1833</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for Edward Worrell : A journal of a campaign through the south western and western prairies in the months of May and June 1833 <num>LSC.170/119</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>May and June 1833</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address><p>Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2q81b7n">LSC's Metadata Rights Statement</extref> for more information.</p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-09-29 16:08:37 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Materials are in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Edward Worrell : A journal of a campaign through the south western and western prairies in the months of May and June 1833</unittitle>
    <unitid>LSC.170/119</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 volume</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">68 leaves : paper ; 250 x 205 mm.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1833-05-01/1833-06-30" type="inclusive">May and June 1833</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d4f94e6450f0047201ffdcae37b36974" label="Abstract">Two copies (one full, one partial) of a daily journal kept by U.S. Army surgeon Edward Worrell. The journal is noteworthy for its insights into the day-to-day life of a solider in the American West, as well as the attitudes of such soldiers on Native American culture.</abstract>
    <physdesc id="aspace_15beede3656ba9ad8e3de916ad051bfd">68 leaves : paper ; 250 x 205 mm.  Layout: Average of 25 lines of writing per page. Script: Cursive. Binding: Paper boards.</physdesc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3bbb94cbb96c9fc9cbd8099db6394057">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ef6cc493cb3a813b76b962c7b76a92b5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED ON-SITE: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ec3b6c19e8bb7239e890a780a9960784">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_349cbf27688a00a8375866303d3c298b">
    <head>Provenance/Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Purchase, Zeitlin Books, ca. 1930s.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_afe2e907d6620e7aba29d6615b6d1ff3">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9942304033606533">9942304033606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <processinfo id="aspace_226761143d8c7aec990dddbf4256bc62">
    <head>Processing Note</head>
<p>Processed by Jonathan Naito with assistance from Jain Fletcher; finding aid created with assistance from Laurel McPhee, September 2004, in the Center For Primary Research and Training (CFPRT).</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Problematic Content and Description in UCLA's library collections and archives.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_15ae373806660bd457d0420683b67626">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>Edward Worrell was born in Delaware; he left civilian life to serve as an assistant surgeon at Fort Gibson, a post he held from 1832-1833. He was honorably discharged in 1842 and died in 1877.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_736f31bbb3773757bf5f17d26df5b303">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>This bound manuscript includes the full text of a daily journal kept by Edward Worrell, an assistant surgeon who was part of an 1833 U.S. Army expedition to confront and contain the Pawnees in present day Oklahoma, and what appears to be a partial second draft of the same journal. Located in the Three Forks Region of present day Oklahoma (then Arkansas), Fort Gibson was actively engaged in attempts to diplomatically and forcibly convince local tribes and those relocated from the East to recognize the sovereignty of the United States government. The 1833 expedition led by Lieutenant Colonel James Many was the second such expedition to originate from Fort Gibson, and like the 1832 campaign, ended in failure. The detachment consisting of two select companies of the Seventh Infantry and three companies of Rangers traveled 513 miles in 55 days, however, the soldiers were slowed by their heavy equipment, lack of sufficient provisions, disease, and extreme weather conditions. On June 30, 1833 they returned to Fort Gibson having had only indirect interactions with members of the Pawnee tribe. Throughout his journal, Worrell comments on the day-to-day life of a member of the U.S. Army and the beauty of the prairie, while also recording events of potential military importance. It seems as if he later attempted to produce a version of his journal for public or private circulation; the partial second draft is divided into chapters with brief summaries at the head of each chapter.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_69edbbbad5e9846ff5a3285ebb88a604">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>A copy of this manuscript is in the Negative Microfilm Collection, no. 02493.</p><p><extref xlink:href="https://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt538nb916" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new">Bound Manuscripts Collection (Collection 170)
</extref>. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref8_vt1" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 1r-1v: introduction</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref9_bk9" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 1v: list of officers associated with the campaign</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref10_1or" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 2r-52r: journal of the campaign arranged in daily entries</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">May 6-June 30, 1833</unitdate></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref11_s4k" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 53r: blank</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref12_svo" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 54r-68r: partial draft of the journal; divided into chapters with summary descriptions at the head of each chapter</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">May 6-May 15, 1833</unitdate></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
