<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt158023r5/">wr170296.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Wright (M.) diary of a Surveyor </titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the M. Wright Diary of A Surveyor in East New South Wales, Australia, 1847 <num>LSC.170/296</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Jonathan Naito, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, July 2004; machine-readable finding aid created by Caroline Cubé.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2008</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-09-27 13:11:31 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>M. Wright Diary of A Surveyor in East New South Wales, Australia</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Wright, M.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.170/296</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Volumes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">148 leaves : paper ; 280 x 210 mm. bound to 350 x 230 mm.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847/1847" type="inclusive">1847</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_98918b73275d1719b6c628bb60b637cd" label="Abstract">The typed transcript of a diary by an Irish surveyor working in East New South Wales, Australia from July 1, 1847 to November 17, 1847. During this time Wright surveyed areas in the vicinity of Dungog, Newcastle, and Singleton. Wright discusses surveying and life in New South Wales, and also includes an unfinished tale about an evil parson.</abstract>
    <physdesc id="aspace_0fbb81db9ce2547cab0751e5f388517e" label="General Physical Description note">148 leaves : paper ; 280 x 210 mm. bound to 350 x 230 mm. Binding: Purple Riven spring-back binder.</physdesc>
    <physloc id="aspace_37999dcb6fbece004e4cd1acf9111fe9">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b1623c8b859fdf9159ade9c7f8323de4">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8c3f470bf3184e3393e438559e367d01">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_530b4138f4f2496cc4d56034320095a9">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6f75f5196f9ea6c21ea6e53e51dc38c2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], M. Wright Diary of A Surveyor in East New South Wales, Australia (Collection 170/296). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_696e7e0cdf131cc8d3e3517b58c456ef">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Jonathan Naito, with assistance from Jain Fletcher and Laurel McPhee, July 2004,in the Center For Primary Research and Training (CFPRT).</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_617ce587ebfbc786ef3cc6576b93544e">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/trta7g/alma9953571053606533">9953571053606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_50f1af651b78b3f0d42a51b53f5e00d9">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>The manuscript suggests that M. Wright was Irish by birth. He was irregularly employed as a surveyor in New South Wales, Australia, and during 1847 surveyed portions of Dungog, Newcastle, and Singleton.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8904039afdb0497ca0ea7fb9fa7395eb">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>This volume is a typed transcript of a diary covering the period from July 1, 1847 to November 17, 1847. During this time Wright surveyed areas in the vicinity of Dungog, Newcastle, and Singleton. He discusses personal, professional, and public matters, including the change in governors in New South Wales from Sir George Gipps to Sir Charles FitzRoy, Mr. Edmund Besley Court Kennedy's Cape York expedition, and the Commercial Bank scandal. Much attention is given to the Presbyterianism and Scottish population in Australia. It also includes an unfinished tale about an evil parson that stops and starts at irregular intervals throughout the manuscript.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f245b9a67bd721d01b175bd7d1eb288f">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt538nb916">Bound Manuscripts Collection (Collection 170) </extref>. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Surveyors -- Australia -- New South Wales -- Diaries.</occupation>
    <persname source="ingest">Wright, M. --Diaries.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref12_74n" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 1r-3r: the demise of Sir George Gipps</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_632" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 12r-16r, 33r-34r, 38r-40r, 56r-58r: M. Wright, "The Devil's Own Parson."</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref14_u2u" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 13r: Harbor survey of Newcastle</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_9o2" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 15r, 20r-21r: Mr. Kennedy and the exploring party; complaints about Sir T. S. Mitchell</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref16_0iz" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 26r-33r: Newcastle and the arrival of Sir Charles Augustus Fitz Roy</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_4pe" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 63r: drop in price of land from 1837-1847</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref18_ryv" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 74r-80r: Dungog and Singleton</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_aav" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 81r-90r: New Forest in Hampshire and Clarence Town</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref20_13s" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 99r-100r: land regulation</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_o6o" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 101r-116r: Commercial Bank scandal</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref22_hd5" level="item"><did><unittitle>ff. 123r-25r: squatting regulation.</unittitle></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
