<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8cf9qvq/">yell9411.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Yellowstone Park : color photogravures by F. Jay Haynes</titleproper><titleproper>Yellowstone Park : color photogravures by F. Jay Haynes, [between 1890-1910] <num>LSC.94/11</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Caroline Cubé, 2013.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-23 13:43:27 -0700</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Yellowstone Park : color photogravures by F. Jay Haynes</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Haynes, F. Jay (Frank Jay), 1853-1921, photographer.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LSC.94/11</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 albums</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(20 photogravures) : color ; 28 x 38 cm (album)
<lb/>Photogravures are signed "Haynes-Photo."
<lb/>Color photogravures are numbered 1-20, and mounted, one to a page, on leaves of heavy textured cream paper; printed captions below image.
<lb/>Bound in heavy textured tan wrappers, secured with three tan ties in three holes along left margin; title and author printed in dark brown on upper cover.
<lb/>Spec. Coll. copy: in modern beige cloth clamshell box, with box title: "Yellowstone Park."</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1890/1910" type="inclusive">[between 1890-1910]</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_44a289276c31e8b34042292a67f57eef" label="Abstract">An album of twenty color photogravures, printed in Germany, possibly between 1890 and 1910, of views of Yellowstone National Park taken by F. Jay Haynes, who started photographing the park beginning in 1881.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_87ae6d514afbc373bcc1211e3798a977">Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_349624ab0630730091ddccc2229896d1">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9cd37cb795e7aba42f511cc030ccfe20">
    <head>Restrictions on Use and Reproduction</head>
<p>Property rights to the objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d5f69f246c4327505fdfd8529fb587df">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Yellowstone Park : color photogravures by F. Jay Haynes (Collection 94/11).  UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_29783d1adb20b6b98786e622a00ce99d">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language
that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form
located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special
Collections.</extref></p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_73221ffaabc51a5cab91247e11506a81">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9971285093606533">
9971285093606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_fb196e13bfd4e370367aae1903465c84">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>Professional photographer, publisher, and photographic historian of the Northwest and Yellowstone National Park. F. Jay Haynes was born in Saline, Michigan in 1853, and learned the photography business in Ripon, Wisconsin, where he found himself after working as a traveling salesman. In 1876, he and his young wife established a studio in Moorhead, Minnesota, and Haynes began working for the Northern Pacific Railroad as the company expanded west, providing them with marketing and publicity photographs of their trains, depots, and sites along their routes. Riding the rails on a free pass from the Northern Pacific, Haynes was able to travel all over the great Northwest, and photograph whatever he wanted. He later bought his own railroad car from the company, and had it outfitted as a photographic studio. As the Palace Studio Car traveled from town to town, Haynes took photographs for local customers, and sold them prints on return visits. In 1881, Haynes began photographing Yellowstone Park, and over the following years, set up several photo studios within the Park. Haynes served as official photographer for the visit of President Chester A. Arthur to Yellowstone in 1883, and for the winter expedition through the Park led by Arctic explorer, Frederick Schwatka, in 1887. Haynes was the first to photograph Yellowstone at that time of year. Haynes' son, Jack Ellis Haynes, took over the business in 1916, and continued as official photographer of Yellowstone until his death in 1962.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_57fd3ca6db9c15c50afac8b1923668d0">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>No. 1. Gardiner Canyon -- No. 2. Liberty Cap and Hotel -- No. 3. Mammoth Hot Springs -- No. 4. Golden Gate -- No. 5. Obsidian Cliff -- No. 6. Norris Geyser Basin -- No. 7. Paint Pots Fountain -- No. 8. Morning Glory Spring -- No. 9. Grotto Geyser Formation -- No. 10. Punch Bowl Spring -- No. 11. Emerald Pool -- No. 12. Old Faithful Inn -- No. 13. Old Faithful Geyser -- No. 14. Keppler Cascades -- No. 15. Hot Spring Cone -- No. 16. Lake Hotel -- No. 17. Rapids Above Upper Falls -- No. 18. Canyon from Artist's Point -- No. 19. Canyon from Inspiration Point -- No. 20. Great Falls, 360 Ft.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f8164ff1fd78885245476ae75027c5b1">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Part of the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6489s0cc/">Photograph Album Collection (Collection 94) </extref> in UCLA Library Special Collections.</p><p>For additional information on F. Jay Haynes, see <title>F. Jay Haynes, photographer,</title> published by the Montana Historical Society, 1981; and Edward W. Nolan, <title>Northern Pacific views: the railroad photography of F. Jay Haynes, 1876-1905</title> (Helena, MT: Montana Historical Society Press, 1983).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rapids -- Yellowstone National Park -- Pictorial works.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Old Faithful Geyser (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Liberty Cap (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Obsidian Cliff (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Mammoth Hot Springs (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Norris Geyser Basin (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Morning Glory Pool Spring (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Grotto Geyser (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcnaf">Lower Falls of the Yellowstone River (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <genreform source="rbgenr">Photogravures.</genreform>
    <genreform source="rbgenr">Photograph albums</genreform>
    <genreform source="rbgenr">Photographic prints</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Geysers -- Yellowstone National Park -- Pictorial works.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hot springs -- Yellowstone National Park -- Pictorial works.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Waterfalls -- Yellowstone National Park -- Pictorial works.</subject>
    <corpname source="ingest">Lake Hotel (Yellowstone National Park) --Pictorial works.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Old Faithful Inn (Wyo.) -- Photographs</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Yellowstone National Park --Pictorial works.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
