<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC" url="https://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8891d1w/">squi0064.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Squire (Jason E.) collection</titleproper><titleproper>Finding Aid for the Jason E. Squire collection <num>PASC.0064</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Jasmine Larkin, 2020.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher><p><date>Online finding aid last updated 2026 January 15.</date></p><address><addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline><addressline>Box 951575</addressline><addressline>Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 310-825-4988</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 310-206-1864</addressline><addressline>AskLSC@library.ucla.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.library.ucla.edu/visit/locations/library-special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address><p>This record is made available under an Universal 1.0 Public Domain Dedication Creative Commons license.</p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-01-15 14:19:13 -0800</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jason E. Squire collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82117621" source="naf">Squire, Jason E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82117621" role="dnr" source="naf">Squire, Jason E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PASC.0064</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/3614</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.4 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(20 boxes and 2 half document boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">32 audiovisual carriers</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(30 unprocessed audiocassettes, 2 unprocessed open reel audiotapes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 born-digital carriers</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(2 optical discs, 1 hard drive)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">33.6 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(61 files, 0 folders)</extent>
      <physfacet>Transferred from 1 hard drive.</physfacet>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/2020" type="inclusive">1967-2020</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_2d1faee9e16550470c6ff9f5acc0d883">Stored off-site. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_5e7642b2c8974341e2c5ecbcb6cdcab1">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b8a1f805d1120c61ef306d1a83a16347">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_f2ced620576f712b712a8f3f654174c2">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO, AUDIOVISUAL and DIGITAL MATERIALS: Audio, audiovisual and digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0c5b96cea8a6e449696a266ae48515c2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Reproduction and Use</head>
<p>Property rights to the physical objects belong to UCLA Library Special Collections. All other rights, including copyright, are retained by the creators and their heirs. It is the responsibility of the researcher to determine who holds the copyright and pursue the copyright owner or his or her heir for permission to publish where The UC Regents do not hold the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_62722ebc5d1f0d51d1a5e4ef3a2f9ff1">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Jason E. Squire collection (PASC 64). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_024e3f176bf7df95f4f8216848a89d61">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Jason E. Squire, 1983, 2017, 2024.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9a9797f03a8fde0bb29ef4bb14e5cb2b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Digital materials were received on 1 hard drive. All digital file naming, organization, and arrangement created by Jason E. Squire was retained. Inventory available at Library Special Collections.</p><p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived user interest and research value, availability of staff and resources, and competing priorities. Library Special Collections provides a standard level of preservation and access for all collections and, when time and resources permit, conducts more intensive processing. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards and best practices.</p><p>We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/21198/r2zs2tnj">Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.</extref></p><p>Final processing by Kelly Besser in consultation with Miki Bulos, 2025.</p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_893108845540b41ad2132b1b2cc43d15">
    <head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="https://search.library.ucla.edu/permalink/01UCS_LAL/17p22dp/alma9932222403606533">9932222403606533</extref></p>  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8e97dfb30af3d17a1cfeeb9e0bd55c6c">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Jason E. Squire was born in Brooklyn, New York; Professor Emeritus at USC School of Cinematic Arts; BS, Syracuse University (1969); MA, University of California, Los Angeles (1972); WAER Syracuse radio program director (1968-69); assistant to vice president of production, Avco Embassy Pictures (1970-71); assistant to senior production vice-president, United Artists Corp. (1971-73); executive in charge of development P.E.A. Films, Inc. and Alberto Grimaldi (1974-78); production executive, Burnt Offerings (1976); associate director of television movies, 20th Century-Fox (1978-81); executive producer, soundtrack albums Conan The Barbarian (1982) and Conan The Destroyer (1984); faculty member, USC School of Cinematic Arts (1988- 2020); Visiting Professor, Beijing Film Academy (2011-13); Master of Entertainment Studies, DeTao Masters Academy, Shanghai (2014); Official Scholar/Participant, Mallen Screen Entertainment Conference (2006 - ); writings include The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice (co-editor, 1972), The Movie Business Book (editor, 1983, 1992, 2004 from Simon &amp; Schuster, 2017 from Routledge), with Chinese, Japanese, Korean, Spanish and German translations; and Red Harvest (screenplay); host of The Movie Business Podcast (2022 - ).</p><p>Source: Biography written by donor, Jason E. Squire, 2025.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8acb348ab49521b71d4848dbf7916ff5">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Collection consists of transcripts and digital audio files of interviews conducted by Jason E. Squire with motion picture industry executives and creatives. Includes 27 interviews for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice (© 1972) including with Stanley Kramer, Sydney Pollack, Norman Lear, Bud Yorkin, David V. Picker, William Goldman, Russ Meyer, A.H. Howe, Richard Lederer, Gordon Stulberg, Nat D. Fellman, Stanley H. Durwood, Stirling Silliphant, Walter Reade; 33 interviews for The Movie Business Book (© 1983) including with Mel Brooks, Robert Evans, James Bridges, Sydney Pollack, William Goldman, Joan Micklin Silver, Raphael Silver, Paul Maslansky, Robert Laemmle; 19 interviews for The Movie Business Book Second Edition (© 1992) including with David Puttnam, Henry Jaglom, Norman H. Garey, Mike Medavoy, Robert G. Friedman, Sydney Pollack, D. Barry Reardon, Ira Deutchman, Robert Laemmle; 18 interviews for The Movie Business Book Third Edition (© 2004) including Bob Berney, Benjamin S. Feingold, Michael Grillo, Christina Fong, Louis A. Feola, Kevin Yoder, Sydney Pollack, Mel Brooks. Also 30 audio cassettes of interviews with William Goldman, Sydney Pollack, Mel Brooks, Robert Evans, James Bridges, David Puttnam, Barbara Boyle, Shari E. Redstone, Robert G. Friedman, D. Barry Reardon, Mike Medavoy, Rob Aft, Michael Grillo, Louis Feola, Joel Gotler, Robert Laemmle, Dan Fellman, Christina Fong, Al Ovadia, Jessica Tuchinsky, Bob Berney, Lindy DeKoven, Frank Biondi, Jr. Also digitized interviews that predate The Movie Business Book with Henry Fonda, Rod Steiger, Otto Preminger, Joseph E. Levine, Gov. George Wallace; digitized kinescope interviews with Henry Fonda, Rod Steiger &amp; Claire Bloom; also digitized lectures at Beijing Film Academy, Shanghai International Film Festival, Beijing International Film Festival; Tokyo Institute of Technology; also digitized Movie Business Book Third Edition launch at Barnes &amp; Noble at The Grove with Henry Jaglom, Dan Fellman, Barbara Boyle, Stephen M. Kravit, Michael Grillo, Rob Aft, Dan Ochiva; also digitized Movie Business Book Fourth Edition launch at Barnes &amp; Noble at The Grove with Blair Rich, Kevin Goetz, Eric B. Fleischman, Ilan Haimoff, Linda Benjamin, Stephen M. Kravit, Steve Montal, Barbara Boyle (with remarks by Alan Horn); also Movie Business Book Fourth Edition Tribute and Panel at Museum of the Moving Image (New York) with Shari E. Redstone, Harold L. Vogel, Michael Barker, Warrington Hudlin, Dan Ochiva, Jamie Wilkinson; also Movie Business Book Fourth Edition panel at William Morris Endeavor (Beverly Hills) with Michael London, Jewerl Ross, Eric B. Fleischman, Ilan Haimoff, Barbara Boyle, Peter Dekom, Rob Aft.</p><p>Source: Scope and Contents written by donor, Jason E. Squire, 2025.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9c5f40a3e79ffc80924948e5100c2934">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection was arranged according to its existing order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Motion picture industry -- United States.</subject>
    <genreform source="rbgenr">Interviews.</genreform>
    <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82117621" role="dnr" source="naf">Squire, Jason E.</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82117621" source="naf">Squire, Jason E. -- Archives</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_2e6037a4bc27e6b304ff717a87920e89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview transcripts</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192375</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_108abba86ceb240156de3d55f680d1dd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a3f694e99f7b50e8674640364f0e1ad4" parent="aspace_108abba86ceb240156de3d55f680d1dd" type="Folders">1-24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af1e18d3be593681f901640febdf7668"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Robert Evans, Sydney Pollack, Mel Brooks, Joan Micklin Silver, Russ Myer, William Goldman, Lee Rosenberg, Lew Weitzman, Eleanor Breese, Roberta Kent, Norman Garey, Peter Geiger, Gary Concoff, Tristine Rainer &amp; Sylvia Schneble, Richard Lederer, Gordon Stulberg, David Picker, Roger L. Mayer, Richard Zimbert, Norman Rudman, Barry Weitz, Paul Maslansky, James Bridges, and A.D. Murphy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a57ebbb2a2e1b5675a7601db9e95c18b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview transcripts</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192376</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d34fed43d6acc845f74f87234817e85" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_10de73c862e12c68672eacb76cb17292" parent="aspace_0d34fed43d6acc845f74f87234817e85" type="Folders">1-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a27fc8cc7852ec9c2a54be81108810b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Peter Myers, Barbara Boyle, Raphael Silver, Nat Fellman, Robert Laemmle, Philip M. Lowe, Jack Valenti, Stan Blum, and Martin Polon.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c7c9dcbe9ad59c55e1471c82a6d748bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview transcripts</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192377</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_e799135f146c779a721615d1119f1e06" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_fcaaa05e79ff064565efbd0dceffb910" parent="aspace_e799135f146c779a721615d1119f1e06" type="Folders">1-27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c13daffd4e088b9fab7143e20f8cca5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Stirling Silliphant, Kenneth J. Rotcop, Lew Weitzman, Lee Rosenberg, Marshall Green, Tim Donahue, Barry J. Weitz, Don Kopaloff, Art Levinson, Stanley Kramer, Sydney Pollack, Bud Yorkin &amp; Norman Lear, Russ Meyer, Fred H. Detmers &amp; Frank P. Brackett, Fouad Said, David A. Lipton, Roger L. Mayer, Gordon B. Forbes, Richard Lederer, Gordon Stulberg, Saul Rittenberg, M.J.E. McCarthy, Nat D. Fellman, Stanley H. Durwood, Dennis Friedland, Walter Reade, and David V. Picker.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e06e21fa1bb7b37204a9b19912ace59a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192378</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970-1991</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_bd5fe96dccf14f68df6bb452a0030534" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_dbbb643b7edbeffe587bb9b8c2257429" parent="aspace_bd5fe96dccf14f68df6bb452a0030534" type="Folders">1-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e655d5ac7427f890023a51f0652c9164"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the 1972 and 1983 books. Participant files include the following: Gary O'Concuff, Robert Evans, Nat D. Fellman, and Peter Geiger.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_28eabd3f3f7255406e09065f3b05f62b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192382</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970-1991</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_12cd5a4fd50a4c29a33df1969b91253e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_d1338e16e9c9442661da0b64ababda82" parent="aspace_12cd5a4fd50a4c29a33df1969b91253e" type="Folders">1-17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f453b9d1c1f0ff0b6625cc3eca4b733b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Marshall Green &amp; Tim Donahue, A.H. Howe, IATSE, Richard Kahn, Stanley Kramer, Paul Lazarus, Philip Lowe, Dick May, Michael F. Mayer, Roger Mayer, Russ Meyer, Martin Michel, Peter S. Myers, Raphael Silver, Gordon Stulberg, Lew Weitzman, and Richard Zimbert.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6ba7e1b8cd6e3298de9d80a428f0283b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192393</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1979-2001</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_8b10bed0519fa792799ca00b4f7cfffe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_4d00b7417082b9bd5ae9192fbcd621f7" parent="aspace_8b10bed0519fa792799ca00b4f7cfffe" type="Folders">1-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_39905f4192368db0c0d8834babb2106c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Stanford Blum, Eleanor Breese, James Bridges, Reg Childs, Peter Dekom, Ira Deutchman, Stanley Durwood, and A. Alan Friedberg,</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7de6eb4102ba264ca3bf740824738ca7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192396</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978-1993</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_b8fe920d10baef7dd10581949363446e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_ad5835e25f988fb74b0e7f60c741617a" parent="aspace_b8fe920d10baef7dd10581949363446e" type="Folders">1-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de610944c3a85d0fb06fa3ad073ceed5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Paul Maslansky, Mike Medavoy, Motion Picture Association of America, Arthur D. Murphy, and Martin Polon.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2d890ded68001d2e44a1a7087a69e158" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192401</unitid><unitdate datechar="copyright" type="inclusive">circa 1978-2013</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_94da23a3fd68cac28708ef7f9f518181" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_33a8b4bd59189136b6ba97b2d8dc1387" parent="aspace_94da23a3fd68cac28708ef7f9f518181" type="Folders">1-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73bf6214545154391b902643e32207eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: D. Barry Reardon, Joan Micklin Silver, Jack Valenti, Van Wallach, Barry Weitz, Bob Berney, Steve Blume, and Mel Brooks.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_06832f77a2ad8f75bb586cd283e3e8c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192403</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978-2004</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_0cf2d75b8e2fc77814cf9143c89c03f8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_db7c696d5af10b99453a26bf61553ba0" parent="aspace_0cf2d75b8e2fc77814cf9143c89c03f8" type="Folders">1-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f428bdf282a012d0055443097c482ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Lindy DeKoven, Ben Feingold, Louis Feola, Christina Fong, Charlie's Angels Originals, Rob Friedman, and Norman Garey.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5a1766cdba75f7a397a9133b181539d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192405</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978-2015</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_ab8c280c1511da9ceb69416bcd175314" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_8267b8df6f09d36f616a04d17b101947" parent="aspace_ab8c280c1511da9ceb69416bcd175314" type="Folders">1-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_92d06e8cd367bc9da378ec62c258ee02" level="file"><did><unittitle>Participants' files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192406</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1979-2005</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_6e911edf8b669a93b699b9a7892632ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_d42588ac030d4e14494fa0b388ae98d3" parent="aspace_6e911edf8b669a93b699b9a7892632ee" type="Folders">1-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c0461dc04253bb0bb13927cb25ed1a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains files for the following: Lee Rosenberg, Norman Rudman, Tom Rothman, Nigel Sinclair &amp; Steven Gerse, Paul Sweeting, and Kevin Yoder - NRG.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a10db765856d5e0e7079158499bc0bbd" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business - original manuscript</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192407</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1972</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_8e1004faa309ad13b0d98f1ecd900383" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_fc7df121dfdc39f3aac65c9bc8d0d71d" parent="aspace_8e1004faa309ad13b0d98f1ecd900383" type="folder">7</container><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_aa534921a4e371cbbfaeb34082b5f4bb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_f5758737f5846e8a2f74d8ecf011f621" parent="aspace_aa534921a4e371cbbfaeb34082b5f4bb" type="Folders">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bf9eedf6cf3deeae97e7076b988b4e72" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - manuscript</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192408</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1981</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_d5001965e82c8675f971f19730f0fb4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_6f13e12453ecd07fcba9ff24b9274914" parent="aspace_d5001965e82c8675f971f19730f0fb4e" type="Folders">3-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_285d82ee48af30ba7bef4ead8f575a5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - second edition - production manuscript</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192409</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1992</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_cd006a8da73d799dbbe0877c45ff02ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_241cefad730728484c15d215bb40650b" parent="aspace_cd006a8da73d799dbbe0877c45ff02ae" type="Folders">1-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_782ca49ff98e75cab356c78ce0aecdc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - third edition - production manuscript</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192410</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">2004</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_b6c95b91a2a4619e4275b6e5ec61aa72" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_ac624bf43e1fb24a9eb4846d3684f308" parent="aspace_b6c95b91a2a4619e4275b6e5ec61aa72" type="folder">5</container><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_612b6a32e69dba9942f40c1977b5b3a5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_97c9df27867396c3bbbf1cea4e846e55" parent="aspace_612b6a32e69dba9942f40c1977b5b3a5" type="Folders">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e075eb4902c6490f8213f71ce14a6c5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - third edition - production manuscript</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192411</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1981</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_f12442b2a288c3414d1a25eef3580c9d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_5c0135bd23f71656473a5420b03d7d91" parent="aspace_f12442b2a288c3414d1a25eef3580c9d" type="Folders">3-4</container><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_72074e0a4ece54b668c78775ec75a356" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_c1bf64f8fd708bf8c9632bb7a9c1a6ff" parent="aspace_72074e0a4ece54b668c78775ec75a356" type="Folders">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9c907e1acf8f37e373ef7625fa2e11a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - second edition</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192412</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1992</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_4221672881f85b51d0f79284541464f5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_db3a38ef1ebe24a3472d14071ba7b10b" parent="aspace_4221672881f85b51d0f79284541464f5" type="Folders">3-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4591d8162613fc240a179c07a2713180" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - third edition - manuscript copy</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192413</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">2004</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_2b07f4ad993339d6cb3513114dea3744" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_8d608b95a95f6c83c0b38027feb21c2f" parent="aspace_2b07f4ad993339d6cb3513114dea3744" type="Folders">1-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2d421c3cb27c8f2e2531c035d54d5cd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - fourth edition - manuscript</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192414</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">2016</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_6626a10c6f020d315e86174e13b13de6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_67c3ac4473480cb35c839a4b703ae16b" parent="aspace_6626a10c6f020d315e86174e13b13de6" type="Folders">4-5</container><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_0192c51d2ba239ccacc54ed691fd37c0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_af83cd8dd9b95249fd4a3b074f24808a" parent="aspace_0192c51d2ba239ccacc54ed691fd37c0" type="Folders">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_194400d496585646fe26fb0772578ebc" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - camera-ready pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192415</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">1983</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_adc8bf550854ad09feaf64804c8a0fe5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_500be11db0b0a2fb6851a7086c5af229" parent="aspace_adc8bf550854ad09feaf64804c8a0fe5" type="Folders">3-5</container><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_ff435b0f4240d9b89226f9c028320afe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_2517eea22389bd42fe39ee8efb5d2e80" parent="aspace_ff435b0f4240d9b89226f9c028320afe" type="Folders">1-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a2776c7a3b87b2cb2750aae52a5624e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - third edition - first pass pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192416</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">2003</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_e83794dd1718123fa4f69e49e6b1f960" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_4842df8b7b1f57b7dd84188f5444a958" parent="aspace_e83794dd1718123fa4f69e49e6b1f960" type="Folders">4-5</container><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_69cc5a1861734c5fa5fa1b149205c165" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_fddd6850d09cea465fdcff7977a6c2df" parent="aspace_69cc5a1861734c5fa5fa1b149205c165" type="Folders">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7f2b92fbc863abe5327cf3dc6b342d41" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Book - third edition - second pass pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192417</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">2004</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_042cb03be436319c2f13d6b76f7c8f36" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_aa9ad74f389309106bf571cda90148ec" parent="aspace_042cb03be436319c2f13d6b76f7c8f36" type="Folders">3-6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5b374d243b12878c3f90bbac1b5175f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio interviews and transcripts</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192418</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1967-2020</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size half document box (12.5d 10.5h 2.5w)" id="aspace_1bebd4f6a53cea71b16736ac83a54540" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_60c33c91d97c89099826f4113d960a5d" parent="aspace_1bebd4f6a53cea71b16736ac83a54540" type="Folders">1-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_56a96f2205cc87bf8e6d07894176be3f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder 1 contains two MBB 4 at Museum of the Moving Image DVDs which feature Dan Ochiva, Shari E. Redstone, Jason E. Squire, Jamie Wilkinson, and Harold L. Vogel (7/26/2017). </p><p>The hard drive within folder 1 includes the following audiovisual recordings:</p><p>Stanley Kramer (11/12/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Sydney Pollack (11/13/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Sydney Pollack (6/15/1978) (for The Movie Business Book, 1st edition)
Robert Evans (11/3/1979) (for The Movie Business Book, 1st edition)
Henry Fonda (2/26/1971)
"A Conversation with Henry Fonda" (2/6/1969)
"A Conversation with Rod Steiger and Claire Bloom" (4/5/1968)
Rod Steiger (4/6/1969)
Otto Preminger (1967)
Joseph E. Levine (4/20/1969)
Governor George Wallace (4/26/1967)
"A Film on Linear Thought" student project (8/20/1969)
Beijing Film Academy lectures (5/28-29/2011)
The Movie Business Book (3rd edition), Japanese Edition Launch, Lecture and Discussion (5/14/2009)
Shanghai International Film Festival (6/18/2007)
The Movie Business Book (3rd edition), Launch and Panel, Barnes &amp; Noble at the Grove (7/12/2004)
Promo, DeTao Master of Entertainment Studies, Shanghai (1/5/2015)
The Movie Business Book (4th edition), Launch and Panel, Barnes &amp; Noble at the Grove (9/12/2016)
The Movie Business Book (4th edition), Tribute and Panel, Museum of the Moving Image (7/26/2017)
The Movie Business Book (4th edition), Panel at William Morris Endeavor Theatre (6/18/2018)</p><p>The hard drive also includes the following documents:</p><p>Transcript: Stanley Kramer (11/12/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Transcript: Sydney Pollack (11/13/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Transcript: Norman Lear and Bud Yorkin (9/28/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Transcript: Russ Meyer (9/12/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Transcript: Gordon G. Stulberg (9/23/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Transcript: Richard Lederer (8/25/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Transcript: Fouad Said (9/5/1970) (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
"Movies: Anatomy of the Business" - outline (April 1980)
Transcript: Henry Fonda (2/26/1971)</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_be23cf3d6a41dc1c65a2d3b6d06a0a37"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>FOLDER 1 CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO, AUDIOVISUAL/DIGITAL] MATERIALS: Audio, audiovisual and digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_5889eb90404728d031c646202bd2a884" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio recordings of interviews</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192419</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970-2002</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_92577d4fe0d43917ec5b28d83cc43467" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8c9c2c82b868428cc36a12984ae2198"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box contains the following interviews conducted by Jason E. Squire:</p><p>Stanley Kramer - 11/12/1970; Sydney Pollack - 11/13/1970 (for The Movie Business: American Film Industry Practice)
Henry Fonda  - 2/26/1971 (not related to the Movie Business Book)
William Goldman - 4/24/1978 (for The Movie Business Book)
Sydney Pollack - 6/15/1978 (for The Movie Business Book)
Mel Brooks - 1/30/1979  (for The Movie Business Book)
Robert Evans - 11/3/1979 (for The Movie Business Book)
James Bridges - 12/11/1979 (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
William Goldman - 4/5/1990 (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
David Puttnam &amp; JES - 3/20/1991 (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
Robert G. Friedman, Part 1/2 - 4/19/1991 (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
Robert G. Friedman, Part 2/2 -  4/19/1991; D. Barry Reardon (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
Sydney Pollack - 5/28/1991 (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
Mike Medavoy - 6/8/1991 (for The Movie Business Book, 2nd ed.)
Rob Aft, Sr VP International Distribution MDB Worldwide - Re: Global Distribution - 6/17/1996
Michael Grillo -  7/26/2000
William Goldman - 7/31/2000 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Louis A. Feola - 8/3/2000 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Lee G. Rosenberg 11/6/2000, Joel Gotler 11/12/2001 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Robert G. Friedman -  May-June 2001 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Robert Laemmle - 1/3/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Dan Fellman -  2/27/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Benjamin S. Feingold -  3/25/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Christina Fong - 4/30/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Al Ovadia -  6/20/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Louis A. Feola - 7/25/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Jessica Tuchinsky - 8/13/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Shari Redstone - 10/02/2002 (3/3) (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Shari Redstone -  10/02/2002 (1&amp;2/3) (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Bob Berney -  11/20/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Lindy De Koven - 12/4/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Barbara Boyle -  12/5/2002 (for The Movie Business Book, 3rd ed.)
Frank Biondi Jr. - 7/16/1998 (not related to The Movie Business Book)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d9ef00f46e6f09dd6b60fb18b566cd8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Movie Business Books</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1192515</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1972-2016</unitdate><container altrender="letter-size document box (12.75d 10.5h 5.25w)" id="aspace_4e43cf7bc123fe3f9038c15f70dea174" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_abbb78cec7c0e1caf02da47f55e76141"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Titles in this collection have been individually cataloged and can be discovered in the Library catalog. Records for these items may be found by keyword searching this string in the catalog: "Squire, Jason E., former owner."</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
