<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CLU-SC">uars0107.xml</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Anderson Graduate School of Management. Management in the Arts Research Program. Publications. 
<date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1970-1978.</date>
</titleproper>
<titleproper type="filing">Management (Anderson Graduate School of). Management in the Arts Research Program. Publications.</titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by University Archives staff, 1987 November; finding aid revised by Katharine A. Lawrie, 2014 February; machine-readable finding aid created by Katharine A. Lawrie, 2014 February.</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>UCLA Library Special Collections</publisher>
<address>
<addressline>Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library</addressline>
<addressline>Box 951575</addressline>
<addressline>Los Angeles, CA, 90095-1575</addressline>
<addressline>(310) 825-4988</addressline>
<addressline>spec-coll@library.ucla.edu</addressline>
</address>
<date>©1987 November</date>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
<date>2014-02-19T14:57-0800</date>
</creation>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<unittitle>Anderson Graduate School of Management. Management in the Arts Research Program. Publications.</unittitle>
<unitid>University Archives Record Series 107</unitid>
<repository>
<corpname>UCLA Library Special Collections</corpname>
</repository>
<langmaterial>
<language langcode="eng"/>
</langmaterial>
<physdesc>
<extent>0.4 linear ft.</extent>
<extent>(1 box)</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate>1970-1978</unitdate>
<abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">Record Series 107 contains publications generated by the Management in the Arts Program at the University of California, Los Angeles, Graduate School of Management.</abstract>
<origination label="Creator">
<corpname source="local">University of California, Los Angeles. Anderson Graduate School of Management. Management in the Arts Research Program .</corpname>
</origination>
</did>
<accessrestrict id="ref3">
<head>Access</head>
<p>COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict id="ref4">
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>Copyright of portions of this collection is held by The Regents of the University of California. The UCLA University Archives can grant permission to publish for materials to which it holds the copyright. All requests for permission to publish or quote must be submitted in writing to the UCLA University Archivist.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite id="ref5">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], Anderson Graduate School of Management. Management in the Arts Research Program. Publications (University Archives Record Series 107). UCLA Library Special Collections, University Archives.</p>
</prefercite>
<bioghist id="ref7">
<head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In 1939, the College of Business Administration at UCLA was authorized to institute a M.B.A. program and the first twenty-seven graduate students in business that entered the university. A doctoral program was initiated in 1953; and in the 1955, the graduate programs were to form a graduate school of business separate from the undergraduate school. Special agencies were then added to the graduate school, among them the Western Data Processing Center in 1956 and Western Management Science Institute in 1960. In 1961, a master of science degree was added to the graduate school's curriculum and school library was established. Before the end of the 1960s, the undergraduate and its B.S. degree in Business Administration were phased out, leaving the Graduate School of Business Administration as the only source of business education on the UCLA campus. The present name of the John E. Anderson Graduate School of Management was bestowed on the school 1987.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent id="ref8">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Record Series 107 contains publications generated by the Management in the Arts Program at the University of California, Los Angeles, Graduate School of Management. Files include announcements of events and newsletters.</p>
<p>This is an inactive Record Series; no additional University records are expected to be added.</p>
</scopecontent>
<odd>
<head>UCLA Catalog Record ID</head>
<p>UCLA Catalog Record ID: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:href="http://catalog.library.ucla.edu/vwebv/holdingsInfo?bibId=3521163">3521163</extref></p>
</odd>
<dsc>
<c id="ref9" level="file">
<did>
<unittitle>Announcements of Events.</unittitle>
<container id="cid6500052" type="Box" label="Box ">1</container>
<container parent="cid6500052" type="Folder">1</container>
<unitdate>1978; n.d.</unitdate>
</did>
</c>
<c id="ref11" level="file">
<did>
<unittitle>Newsletters.</unittitle>
<container id="cid6500051" type="Box" label="Box ">1</container>
<container parent="cid6500051" type="Folder">2</container>
<unitdate>1970-1975; n.d.</unitdate>
</did>
</c>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
